<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff.  Ruby / Rails / Elixir.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>When is Design Done?</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/06/when-is-design-done.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/06/when-is-design-done.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Dave Winer Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The power of outreach.  I’ve never been so surprised in all my life as when the phone rang, on a sunday morning, as I sat in my kitchen in Nahant, CT and I heard “Hi, this is Dave Winer”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-dave-winer-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-dave-winer-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>learnings</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Dave Sifry Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Grace and Kindness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a small industry you grow as a function of the market expanding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got fired from Feedster, a company I founded and where I hired every single executive, I was in a state of shock.  I had flown out to San Francisco and I knew that I was being terminated but I had expected to retain my board seat so I could at least influence things.  Little did I know that when a founder is removed from his firm, it happens with extreme prejudice.  So, when I discovered that even that had been stripped from me, well, I was a mess.  Over ten years later I remember wandering the streets of San Francisco in a daze.  And, when I needed office space for a few hours, to process the paperwork associated with all this mess, you know where I ended up?  Yep.  That’s right – I went to see Dave.  He let me use wifi, power and fax so I could get the paperwork handled.  At what was a moment of professional lowness, Dave was the very epitome of grace and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-dave-sifry-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-dave-sifry-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>learnings</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings - What Dave McClure Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Feedster was not the first company I raised money for but it was the first time I raised money from true silicon valley investors.  I vividly remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/02/what-scott-rafer-taught-me.html&quot;&gt;Scott Rafer&lt;/a&gt; taking me around all the different angel groups, individual investors and Sand Hill Road.  One of those investors was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davemcclure&quot;&gt;Dave McClure&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://500.co&quot;&gt;500 Startups&lt;/a&gt; fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave was one of our angel investors the the one that I felt personally responsible for.  So, after the awful day that I was let go from Feedster, I remember sitting in my apartment in Indianapolis and having to call Dave around 6 pm on a cold fall night and telling him that I was gone and I couldn’t look out for his investment any longer.  He took the news far better than I expected and wasn’t even angry or disappointed with me much to my surprise.  His actual concern was how I was taking everything.  Looking back at this, I can now see it a little differently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were just one of many investments that he had&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount wasn’t all that large&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preserving the relationship with the entrepreneur is more important; they’ll do something else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s what Dave McClure taught me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not everything works out.  And that’s ok.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationships matter.  Keep relationships strong no matter what.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I don’t think I’ve talked to Dave in years at this point but the truth of it is that I’m still impressed by how well he handled this and I still remember it vividly.  And If anyone ever asked me if they should take Dave on as an investor, I’d answer “Yes; a thousand times yes.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-dave-mcclure-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-dave-mcclure-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>learnings</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>feedster</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Brad Fitz Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;iterative Design
Memcache
Favorite Internet Architect&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-brad-fitz-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/06/what-brad-fitz-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>learnings</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The MVP From Hell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of just how bad communications got on this project:
Product Manager [5:20 PM]&lt;br /&gt;
@back_end_engineer_#1 @jon @chrisaddapp hello, i have tested the changes for dashboard and provided feedback to Chris. I also provided feedback to Jon on screenflow. Once those changes are fixed, I approve deploying the changes to production. Thank you for all your help and have a wonderful weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Front End Engineer [5:20 PM]&lt;br /&gt;
ive pushed my changes up to master&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back End Engineer #1 [5:27 PM]&lt;br /&gt;
@chhavi:  Um… @chrisaddapp is offline and hasn’t told me anything.  So I’m assuming that since you’re giving change orders after 5 pm on a friday to people working in eastern time zone that you’re ok with these changes not going live until monday or later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I’m not comfortable at this point with deploying anything to production until you have a chance to review it on staging.  There’s been too many miscommunications on this project.  once it goes onto production its difficult to roll back so it needs to be right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Product Manager [5:46 PM]&lt;br /&gt;
@back_end_engineer_#1 great point Scott and completely aligned with you on not deploying any changes unless confirmed by the engineers working on it. If @chris hasn’t confirmed the fixes to you, we should hold off on deploying those changes. I did test the changes in the staging server though and hence had feedback provided for Chris and Jon. @chrisaddapp please confirm once the fixes have been made. Thank you and have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/the-mvp-from-hell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/the-mvp-from-hell.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-08-total-spaces.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-08-total-spaces.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-07-fantastical.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-07-fantastical.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-06-enpass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-06-enpass.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 06:23:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-05-scrivener-on-the-ipad.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/software-worth-purchasing-05-scrivener-on-the-ipad.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
