<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff.  Ruby / Rails / Elixir.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:48:28 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:48:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gem Review Fuzzyurl Or How Do You Know if a Gem is Ready for Production Use?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Recently at ElixirConf I met Pete Gamache, the CTO of an Internet company and he showed me his Fuzzyurl Gem which is implemented in Ruby, JavaScript and Elixir.  Given my propensity for implementing crawlers / scrapers / content processors, I was immediately intrigued and it is a &lt;strong&gt;quality&lt;/strong&gt; bit of software.  Unfortunately in assessing it for our production use, I found a bug.  I have reported it as an issue and I’m sure it will get addressed, and there is an easy work around, but finding this bug raises the question of “How do you know if a gem is ready for production use?”  So I wanted to write this NOT to slam Pete’s work – which, again, is excellent – but to teach the point that you don’t blindly assume that code on the Internet always works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Before I even could finish this post, Pete responded to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gamache/fuzzyurl.rb/issues/2&quot;&gt;Github Issue&lt;/a&gt; I raised and it looks like he’s going to fix it.  Thanks man!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Having added a new engineer recently this post is written for him so he understands that before you grab a new gem and rely on it willy, nilly, you put some consideration into it.  I actually think he knows this already but the engineer we hire after him?  Well that’s unknown so …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I recently found the ruby Gem &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gamache/fuzzyurl.rb/&quot;&gt;Fuzzyurl&lt;/a&gt; by Pete Gamache and I am intrigued.  As part of my current work I am the mildly unhappy maintainer of massive class - roughly 5K lines dealing with nothing but url parsing and handling.  What you find, the moment you say “I’ll write a crawler”, is that most of the Internet is non RFC compliant and you’re dealing with a witches brew of nastiness.  Standard tools like URI.parse, &lt;em&gt;snort&lt;/em&gt;, well I might have some choice words for the author.  So when I found Pete’s work, the fact that it was implemented in Ruby, JavaScript and Elixir was intriguing to say the least.  Perhaps I might not have to port my url code to Elixir – that would be a huge win.  And since I’m pretty sure that Pete actually &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; this as opposed to the organic “here a problem; there a routine” approach I used to write my library, I’m pretty close to certain that it has to be better than mine.  Mine might handle a ton of weird edge cases but it was never designed – just implemented in a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_hog,_or_die&quot;&gt;root, hog or die&lt;/a&gt;” fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s return to the title of this blog post – How Do You Know if a Gem is Ready for Production Use?  There are a bunch of ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read the code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read the tests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;try and use it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;try and use it exhaustively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand here is that this is a case where you absolutely need to &lt;em&gt;time bound&lt;/em&gt; things.  Time bounding is the practice where you decide, before you start, how much time you should allocate to something.  We all know that tasks involving computers tend to expand to fill the time available.  In my case I decided that this task, assessing if we could use Fuzzyurl in production, was worth an hour.  And I do know that’s light but it was what felt right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an hour I can’t possibly read and understand parsing code.  I’ve written too much of it and I know how detailed it can get.  Reading the tests is another option and a better one.  Generally speaking if a gem is well tested, that bodes well for it being quality.  But I know how bad my input set of urls is.  I can guarantee that the random ass crap I have to encounter isn’t covered by tests.  So I’m left with either try and use it or try and use it exhaustively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;try-and-use-it&quot;&gt;Try and Use It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick addition to the end of Gemfile and then the bundle install dance lets me restart console and try it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fu = Fuzzyurl.from_string(&quot;http://www.foo.com/&quot;)
{
    :protocol =&amp;gt; &quot;http&quot;,
    :username =&amp;gt; nil,
    :password =&amp;gt; nil,
    :hostname =&amp;gt; &quot;www.foo.com&quot;,
        :port =&amp;gt; nil,
        :path =&amp;gt; &quot;/&quot;,
       :query =&amp;gt; nil,
    :fragment =&amp;gt; nil
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s perfect.  Here’s a 1:1 comparison with URI.parse:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2.3.1 :009 &amp;gt; fu = URI.parse(&quot;http://www.foo.com/&quot;)
#&amp;lt;URI::HTTP http://www.foo.com/&amp;gt;
2.3.1 :010 &amp;gt; fu.protocol
NoMethodError: undefined method `protocol' for #&amp;lt;URI::HTTP http://www.foo.com/&amp;gt;
	from (irb):10
	from /Users/sjohnson/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1@banks/gems/railties-4.2.7/lib/rails/commands/console.rb:110:in `start'
	from /Users/sjohnson/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1@banks/gems/railties-4.2.7/lib/rails/commands/console.rb:9:in `start'
	from /Users/sjohnson/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1@banks/gems/railties-4.2.7/lib/rails/commands/commands_tasks.rb:68:in `console'
	from /Users/sjohnson/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1@banks/gems/railties-4.2.7/lib/rails/commands/commands_tasks.rb:39:in `run_command!'
	from /Users/sjohnson/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1@banks/gems/railties-4.2.7/lib/rails/commands.rb:17:in `&amp;lt;top (required)&amp;gt;'
	from bin/rails:4:in `require'
	from bin/rails:4:in `&amp;lt;main&amp;gt;'
2.3.1 :011 &amp;gt; fu.host
&quot;www.foo.com&quot;
2.3.1 :012 &amp;gt; fu.port
80
2.3.1 :013 &amp;gt; fu.scheme
&quot;http&quot;
2.3.1 :014 &amp;gt; fu.path
&quot;/&quot;
2.3.1 :017 &amp;gt; fu.query
nil
2.3.1 :018 &amp;gt; fu.fragment
nil
2.3.1 :019 &amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only change that I would make here is that I would add an alias method on &lt;em&gt;protocol&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;scheme&lt;/em&gt; which is what URI.parse calls protocol (personally I think Pete is actually right here – protocol is a better word – but if you added scheme as an alias – then you’re closer to being a drop in replacement for URI.parse).  Maybe I’ll submit a pull request perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I know that Fuzzyurl works but anyone can type out a url - what about a real test case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;try-and-use-it-exhaustively&quot;&gt;Try and Use it Exhaustively&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best and worst things about my job is that I’m never lacking for data.  We’re currently crawling about 1/4 terabyte of data monthly so at any given point I have access to N million urls.  So why not just try to feed say 250,000 urls thru Fuzzyurl and see what happens.  This gives this simple rake task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;task :verify_fuzzy_url =&amp;gt; :environment do
  pages = Page.order(&quot;id asc&quot;).select(&quot;id, url, long_url_id&quot;).limit(250000)
  pages.each_with_index do |page, ctr|
    puts &quot;#{ctr} :: #{page.id} :: #{page.url}&quot;
    fu = Fuzzyurl.from_string(page.url.strip)
    puts &quot;    #{fu.hostname}&quot;
    raise &quot;error: #{fu}&quot; if fu.hostname.nil?
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all of these urls are supposed to be absolute urls we should always have a hostname and we’ll stop if we don’t.  Now we’ll need to examine the stop and make sure that the input wasn’t bad.  When we run this thru we hit a failure like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fu = Fuzzyurl.from_string(p.url)
ArgumentError: Couldn't parse url string: http://www.theintelligencer.net
from /var/www/apps/banks/shared/bundle/ruby/2.3.0/gems/fuzzyurl-0.9.0/lib/fuzzyurl/strings.rb:32:in from_string' from /var/www/apps/banks/shared/bundle/ruby/2.3.0/gems/fuzzyurl-0.9.0/lib/fuzzyurl.rb:169:infrom_string'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p in this case was a page which a url which looked like “http://www.theintelligencer.net “.  That trailing space there is the reason for the failure.  I submitted a github issue and the author has agreed to address it when he has the time.  That’s a great response - even tho this isn’t technically a bug - since space characters are allowed as part of urls but since it does cause a failure, I appreciated him being willing to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve used this a fair bit, a few of the errors I’ve seen with url processing comes back to my memory.  Here are a few common things you see in the wild that break URI.parse cold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;trailing spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;embedded spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;missing ? before the &amp;amp; fragment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a &amp;amp; instead of a ?  (#s 3 and 4 may actually be one and then same)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s try a few of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;embedded-space&quot;&gt;Embedded Space&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;url = &quot;http://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/scott was here&quot;
&quot;http://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/scott was here&quot;
2.3.1 :021 &amp;gt; fu = Fuzzyurl.from_string(url)
{
    :protocol =&amp;gt; &quot;http&quot;,
    :username =&amp;gt; nil,
    :password =&amp;gt; nil,
    :hostname =&amp;gt; &quot;fuzzygroup.github.io&quot;,
        :port =&amp;gt; nil,
        :path =&amp;gt; &quot;/blog/scott was here&quot;,
       :query =&amp;gt; nil,
    :fragment =&amp;gt; nil
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;instead-of--before-the-fragment&quot;&gt;&amp;amp; Instead of ? Before the Fragment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;url = &quot;http://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/scott was here&amp;amp;foo=bar&quot;
&quot;http://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/scott was here&amp;amp;foo=bar&quot;
2.3.1 :023 &amp;gt; fu = Fuzzyurl.from_string(url)
{
    :protocol =&amp;gt; &quot;http&quot;,
    :username =&amp;gt; nil,
    :password =&amp;gt; nil,
    :hostname =&amp;gt; &quot;fuzzygroup.github.io&quot;,
        :port =&amp;gt; nil,
        :path =&amp;gt; &quot;/blog/scott was here&amp;amp;foo=bar&quot;,
       :query =&amp;gt; nil,
    :fragment =&amp;gt; nil
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Fuzzyurl is just plain a fantastic bit of code.  It handles most of the common cases that break URI.parse.  Here are a few suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add an alias method called parse for from_string  That lets Fuzzyurl be used as a drop in replacement for URI.parse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add support for a call back function so you could register your own pre-processor to clean up a url before it gets parsed.  When implementing this type of library I understand the desire to follow the standards and only modify them slightly for common edge cases.  But there are so many ways to craft a crappy url in this Internet of ours that if you simply allow for a pre-processor routine then you can always say “there’s an api for extending this, use it.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/20/how-do-you-know-if-a-gem-is-ready-for-production-use.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/20/how-do-you-know-if-a-gem-is-ready-for-production-use.html</guid>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>gem</category>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>gem_review</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Father's Guide to Surviving Disney World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this from Orlando, Florida where we’re on our fourth trip to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disneyworld.com/&quot;&gt;DisneyWorld&lt;/a&gt;.  Now I realize that to the true &lt;em&gt;Disney faithful&lt;/em&gt;, four trips ins’t a lot, it feels like enough for me to write this with some degree of authority.  My wife is one of the true Disney faithful and all of this really comes from her one way or another.So here you go – &lt;strong&gt;how to survive DisneyWorld&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: All my Disney experiences have been at DisneyWorld in Orlando Florida.  Almost all of this would be applicable to any Disney theme park but I only know DisneyWorld so its written from that perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;abandon-all-cost-concerns-ye-who-enter-disney&quot;&gt;Abandon All Cost Concerns Ye Who Enter Disney&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally titled this section, &lt;em&gt;It’s going to cost more than you imagined&lt;/em&gt; and both titles are accurate.  DisneyWorld which was originally envisioned by Walt Disney as a cost effective family vacation has become a &lt;strong&gt;premier vacation destination&lt;/strong&gt; and the pricing reflects that.  The bottom line here is that you are going to spend more than you want and the overall experience will be worth it. I’ve been there and I’ve never regretted a dime that we spent at DisneyWorld but, man alive, it &lt;em&gt;costs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-an-early-morning-start&quot;&gt;Get an Early Morning Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are two things you need to understand about Orlando:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Its hot; the closer it gets to noon, the hotter it gets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The lines are the shortest first thing in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife is a huge fan of &lt;em&gt;rope drop&lt;/em&gt; or getting into the park literally the moment the rope drops.  That way you can race to the rides you care about and generally get on them without lines, fast passes or any waiting at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall an early morning start just makes your Disney experience better.  If you only take one thing away from this article, take that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;no-small-children&quot;&gt;No Small Children&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest mistakes I see other parents make is bringing small children to Disney World.  Now when I say small, I mean under about 7 years old.  I know the parents think “Disney.  Kids.  Great Pictures.  Cuteness Galore!!!”  And that is true.  But what’s also true are diapers, strollers and putting small children into a 90 plus degree temperature environment for hours on end.  And what you see are frustrated parents and kids screaming or crying or both.  We held off going for years until our youngest was over 7 years old and that was a fantastic decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;trip-planning-is-key&quot;&gt;Trip Planning is Key&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever thought “I know we’ll goto DisneyWorld and it will be easy!” then I have to disagree with you.  I’ve watched my wife plan multiple trips and it is anything but easy.  There are hundreds if not thousands of options and even things like “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=disneyworld+should+I+get+the+dining+plan&amp;amp;oq=disneyworld+should+I+get+the+dining+plan&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j0l2.10451j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Do we get the meal plan are widely debated&lt;/a&gt; (6.6 million hits on that Google search)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount of information about planning a Disney vacation is staggering.  There are literally dozens of hard core disney fanatic web sites which are an awesome resource.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The time of year is key.  Crowds at DisneyWorld are huge and picking the right time of year can make a big difference.  Happily there are resources like &lt;a href=&quot;http://wdwprepschool.com/disney-world-crowd-calendar-for-the-2016-2017-school-year/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.  And there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.undercovertourist.com/orlando/crowd-calendar/&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; of course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you can find a Disney fan, someone who really, really cares about Disney, then they can help you have an amazing trip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DisneyWorld is now an ecosystem of sorts - massive amounts of information, apps that analyze things, etc.  And there’s a whole language of things that make no sense outside of Disney - FastPass anyone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;app-up&quot;&gt;App Up!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that has really surprised me is the quantity and quality of apps that can really make your trip better.  Here are the apps that my wife and I use every single time.  All apps below are listed for iOS but most have equivalents for Google Play&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/my-disney-experience-walt/id547436543?mt=8&quot;&gt;My Disney Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/disney-world-lines-from-touringplans.com/id411091283?mt=8&quot;&gt;WDW Lines&lt;/a&gt; (pricey; read below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wait-times-for-disney-world/id321601474?mt=8&quot;&gt;Wait Times&lt;/a&gt; (not always accurate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/magic-guide-for-disney-world/id365817457?mt=8&quot;&gt;Magic Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WDW Lines app offers in app purchase for its line info on all rides (some are included in the free app) and the price seems a bit steep - $12.99 for a year’s worth of data.  And, yes, I balked at this the first few times and then I thought about it – &lt;em&gt;I’m spending $thousands$ on this vacation - another $12.99 isn’t going to hurt me&lt;/em&gt;.  And I paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gear-up&quot;&gt;Gear Up!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that has made my trips more successful is putting together a small &lt;strong&gt;nerd bag of doom&lt;/strong&gt; or all the gear that techno dad needs to be successful.  Here’s what’s in mine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-17 17.16.32.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-17 17.16.32.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explanation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this fits into a teeny, tiny bag and goes a long way towards travelling well.  Here’s the inventory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A - Tiny travel sack.  More elegant than a zip lock but that would work just fine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;B - Nail clippers.  Useful for cutting the zip ties in k.  There is always a use for zip ties. This trip they closed a bag with a broken zipper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C - Batteries.  Yes you can buy them there but you might find yourself scouring the resort late at night to find them.  Easier to bring a small handful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;D - Penlight.  Yes your phone has a flashlight but its crappy compared to something purpose built.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E - Multi function screw driver.  I got this one at Menards for like $2 and it does flat, phillips and two flavors of torx.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F - USB Charging cable.  Useful for kindles, Beats pill, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;G - This is a Belkin multiple outlet with dual usb port mini power strip.  It is awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;H - Extra headphones so that a small child’s cartoons don’t drive you absolutely insane.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I - Business cards because you never know who you will meet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;J - Lighting cable for iPhone charging (technically what is shown is a micro usb but it should be at least one lightning cable here; all of them were, at the time of the picture, charging various i devices).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;K - Zip ties because, well, zip ties.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L - Mini stand for propping up a tablet for watching videos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M - Pocket multi tool with attached flashlight.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/edc&quot;&gt;Reddit’s /r/edc&lt;/a&gt; is the goto source if you like miniture tools; edc = every day carry - things small enough you can carry them every day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;N - Three to two prong adapter. This will let you plug in something like the powerstrip into a recessed airport outlet like one in the floor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;O - Pocket knife for, well, anything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P - HooToo Tripmate.  This is an absolutely, outstanding, tremendously wonderful product that I have fallen in love with. What you see here is a teeny, tiny wifi hub that shares usb sticks with movies on them for viewing on an iPad.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-own-personal-wifi-storage/&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt; said it better but &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/wifi/2016/09/17/tripmate-titan-instructions.html&quot;&gt;I said it shorter&lt;/a&gt;.  Follow these links and then just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00RVIGY1I/?tag=codihorr-20&quot;&gt;buy one from Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;always-look-up&quot;&gt;Always Look Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my wife’s favorite phrases at DisneyWorld is “always look up”.  Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-13 11.00.06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-13 11.00.06.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-13 11.03.09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-13 11.03.09.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-16 11.23.50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-16 11.23.50.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-16 11.26.10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-16 11.26.10.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-17 09.57.21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-17 09.57.21.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-17 10.44.55.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-17 10.44.55.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;managing-i-want-i-want-i-want&quot;&gt;Managing I Want, I Want, I Want&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking kids to DisneyWorld is a bit like taking an addict into a drug den.  All you’re going to hear is “I want”, “I want”, “I want” and, as a parent, its frustrating as heck.  Here’s how my wife and I handle it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Say no to everything for the first two days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give each kid a gift card with an amount on it on the third day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell them “once its out then you’re done and I’m not buying you anything”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for not giving it to them on the first few days is that you want them to understand that you don’t buy the first thing you see.  Please note that this lesson is received best if Mom and Dad follow this rule also.  The amount you set will depend on you and your kids.  Personally I wouldn’t do less than $30 / kid but it also depends on how many kids you have. If you have 6 kids then, well, ouch!  If you’re going to take this approach then you need to be hands off and let your kids make bad purchases.  Then you have a great teachable moment when they regret spending money on something foolish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;line-management-or-motion-is-happiness&quot;&gt;Line Management or Motion is Happiness&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s DisneyWorld, 2016, it isn’t uncommon to see a 65 plus minute wait for a top tier ride like Seven Dwarves Mine Train. And here’s what I’ve found about dealing with lines in DisneyWorld:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Motion is Happiness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one, not the most devoted Disney fan, is actually happy when waiting on line. No matter how magical Disney is, a 65 minute wait is just simply just a sucky experience.  What you’ll find is that wait times vary dramatically and go up and down.  So if you have an app which tracks wait times, you can notice “oh wow People Mover is now only 10 minutes” and just rush over to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find that your kids will often fixate on particular rides and want to ride things at a given time.  &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt;.  I repeat &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;.  Motion really is happiness at DisneyWorld so take rides when they are available.  Don’t pass up a ride when the line is small.  We did this yesterday when we actually did want to ride People Mover and 15 minutes later it was a 25 minute wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-right-shoes&quot;&gt;The Right Shoes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking around DisneyWorld basically amounts to traversing a concrete jungle – honestly there is a just a ton of walking.  My wife’s fitbit normally hits 20,000 steps by late afternoon.  And, having brought more comfortable shoes to my wife, yesterday, when I met her at the park, I’m more convinced than ever about the need for excellent shoes.  And since that is highly variable from person to person all I can really say here is picture whatever shoe your feet can be in for hours upon hours and then wear that shoe.  I’d recommend something with arch support personally but that’s just me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;do-evening-events-with-care-if-at-all&quot;&gt;Do Evening Events with Care if At All&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of amazing things to do at DisneyWorld during the evenings.  The problem is that if you have kids, by the time the night time events roll around all the kids want to do is lie around and watch TV or play video games and you, the parent, is like &lt;em&gt;But we paid for this cool thing; get off your butt and come along!!!&lt;/em&gt;  We’ve now tried to do evening events on almost every trip and they always end up with one parent at the event and the other parent at the hotel with whatever kid is exhausted and that’s no fun for Mom and Dad.  So here are two thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ease into evening events with only 1 per trip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are going to try to do evening events, you should do them at the beginning of your trip when you’re not just plain exhausted as you will be by the end of the trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I wrote the section above prior to Saturday night when we attended the Club Villain event which was just outstanding and while what I wrote is true, Club Villain was amazingly good and it has made me rethink my previous position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;carrying-less-is-happiness&quot;&gt;Carrying Less is Happiness&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always see people carrying big bags, backpacks, etc and I wonder just what they have in them.  Personally I never carry anything more than an almost empty backpack and even that is sometimes too much.  Right now to get into DisneyWorld you have to go thru:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ticket check&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bag check&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;metal check; this is a &lt;em&gt;random&lt;/em&gt; pick that I somehow got selected for every time I entered one of the parks except for one time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can eliminate one of those by not having a bag at all then its one less step to worry about.  And, as covered below, Orlando is hot.  The less you carry the happier you will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-your-kids-to-carry-the-stuff&quot;&gt;Getting Your Kids to Carry The Stuff&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a firm believer that requiring more of your kids is ultimately good for them.  So I think that if you have a bag or a misting fan or whatever, you should divide responsibility among your kids.  Usually this will cause no end of whining or kid1 shoving it over to kid2 and so on.  Here’s what I did this trip to get my kids to deal better with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set iPhone timer to 15 minutes with a distinctive ring tone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give it to Kid1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When timer goes off give it to Kid 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a turn after Kid2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat until back in hotel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mileage may vary but it worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dining-if-you-have-a-favorite-meal-or-kids&quot;&gt;Dining If You Have a Favorite Meal or Kids&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Disney dining experience is generally excellent.  One unfortunate thing that we have noticed, however, is that the menus change regularly.  My wife suffers from celiac disease which generally means that there is only 1 or 2 things on most menus that she can eat.  And if those options change it can actually be pretty disappointing.  If you want to avoid this, the menus for every single restaurant, food kiosk and more are online in the My Disney Experience.  And given that kids can often be pretty picky eaters, its not a bad idea to preview the menu before you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;take-taxis-or-uber-when-youre-beat&quot;&gt;Take Taxis or Uber When You’re Beat&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are generally three main modes of transportation at DisneyWorld:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monorail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dominant mode of transport is the &lt;strong&gt;bus&lt;/strong&gt; and while they can be excellent, they also can be late and they can be slow.  Given that all the buses are free, a frugal father might want to use them exclusively.  This, alas, is a false economy.  Given the amount of money that you will have invested in your Disney vacation, waiting an hour to deal with a slow bus ride can actually be a large chunk of time.  The taxis are actually quite good and Uber is another option.  I never had a ride from park to hotel run more than $20.  When the entire family is exhausted and you just discovered the Monorail is mysteriously closed then spending $15 on a taxi is a great use of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eat-lightly-or-mastering-the-disney-5&quot;&gt;Eat Lightly or Mastering the Disney 5&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I jokingly refer to the &lt;em&gt;Disney 5&lt;/em&gt; or the five pounds that it seems you put on after a week at Disney.  We generally, for convenience, use the dining plan and there is a ton of food provided.  However, lately we’ve taken to treating the dining plan much like tapas - a few bites or this, a few bites of that; we just don’t finish our plates anymore.  It isn’t an economic way to do things but you don’t end up so full and feeling so fat afterwards.  If you’re looking for good information about the economics of the dining plan then the ever superb EasyWDW always has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.easywdw.com/easy/blog/figuring-out-if-one-of-the-disney-dining-plans-make-sense-for-your-group/&quot;&gt;something good to read&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dealing-with-the-heat&quot;&gt;Dealing with the Heat&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Orlando heat and humidity can be relentless.  Normally we go in the fall when you would think that it wouldn’t be so bad but that’s just not true.  And while my wife thrives in the heat, I, like many basement dwelling, light phobic technology nerds, can find it a bit much.  Listed below are some of the tips that I have figured out to manage the heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Some friends of our family recently went to DisneyWorld this past summer and they came back to tell us that it hit 114 degrees one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-walk-in-the-shade&quot;&gt;Always Walk in the Shade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single best thing you can do is simple – walk in the shade.  Depending on the time of day you will find that there is always shade.  Now you might have to walk contrary to the flow of traffic but people do do it and its ok.  Shade is really, really important at DisneyWorld.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/surviving-disney-world/2016-09-11 11.05.50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2016-09-11 11.05.50.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wear-white-not-black&quot;&gt;Wear White not Black&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know my audience for this is another dad and I suspect a technically minded individual.  And I know that you understand that black is the absolute worst color to wear in the heat.  But even if you do understand this, your children may not.  Both my kids, this last trip, managed to pack almost all black wardrobes.  Oy.  Wear white people!  It reflects the sun not absorbs it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hat-and-sunglasses&quot;&gt;Hat and Sunglasses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is obvious but your kids may not think to pack a ball cap or sunglasses.  Make sure you have them prior to the trip otherwise your talking a $30 pair of glasses plus a $30 ball cap – for a 9 year old.  And for best luck fighting the head the ball cap should be white not black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bandana-around-the-head&quot;&gt;Bandana Around the Head&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My classic technique for beating the heat when I labor outdoors is the Bandana around the temple soaked in cold water.  I know, I know – I look like a refugee from a 1980s rock video but it does work.  I haven’t had to do it yet at DisneyWorld but I can sense it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-the-mid-afternoon-break&quot;&gt;Take the Mid Afternoon Break&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your approach to theme parks may vary but, at least for my family, we find a mid afternoon break to be essential.  When the clock hits one or two, its time to go back to the hotel for air conditioning, the pool or just plain down time.  We go back out around three or four and everyone is refreshed, happy and far less cranky.  Please note that this reduced crankiness includes the author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leverage-small-world-for-a-break&quot;&gt;Leverage Small World for a Break&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re at the Magic Kingdom then one of the best rides, when you’re hot and tired, is Small World.  While Small World isn’t an exciting ride by any means, it is a wonderfully pleasant experience and it has some wonderful attributes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great air conditioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About 11 minutes in length&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moderately comfortable seating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gives a great way to talk to kids about racism and why Walt Disney made the ride in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every trip we’ve made to DisneyWorld, except for this one, has featured multiple rides on Small World.  Why not this one?  Alas its closed for renovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please bear in mind that every Disney park has some ride that’s the equivalent of Small World in this regard.  Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magic Kingdom - Small World, Hall of Presidents, Carousel of Progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epcot - Spaceship Earth, Three Caballeros&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hollywood Studios - Muppet*Vision 3D&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animal Kingdom - Primeval Whirl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hydrate-hydrate-hydrate&quot;&gt;Hydrate, Hydrate, Hydrate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again we return to the theme of Orlando is &lt;strong&gt;hot&lt;/strong&gt;.  So drink up!  Depending on the hotel you may get free bottles of water in the morning and you can always bring them to the park to save some money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-misting-fan-is-your-ally&quot;&gt;A Misting Fan is Your Ally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find these blue plastic fan / water bottles sold through out the parks for about $19.  And you’d think “too much money” but they really do work well.  Cheap bastard that I am, I kept it from my very first trip and we’re still using it.  If you really want to level up your usage of this then put in the fridge overnight or load it with ice cubes (or both).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sometimes-a-line-is-ok&quot;&gt;Sometimes a Line is Ok&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite what I’ve written about avoiding lines, when a line lets you avoid the heat, it is a viable tactic.  The lines are almost always in shade and they are invariably air conditioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bring-a-jacket&quot;&gt;Bring a Jacket&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how much I’ve written about the pervasive heat and humidity in Orlando you might be surprised to find me closing this essay with “Bring a Jacket” but it is unfortunately true.  The air conditioning indoors in Orlando is as pervasive as the heat is outdoors and I find my normal indoor state is either chilly, cold or too cold.  You might be different but I’ve never traveled here without a fleece and I’ve never regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;postscript-1-the-disney-doctor&quot;&gt;Postscript 1: The Disney Doctor&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heaven forbid you get sick at DisneyWorld but it has happened twice to my youngest – strep throat once and food poisoing a the second time.  Luckily one of the maids turned us onto Resort Physicians – an old fashioned, honest to goodness, house call.  A fantastic doctor came to our room, took care of us and managed to save what was left of the vacation.  And, ever since, I’ve kept his business card close since I knew we’d be going back again. Here are the details if you need a great doctor at DisneyWorld in Orlando:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Resort Physicians
Thomas Blehl
407-465-0000 (office)
407-399-9190 (mobile)
tblehl@resortphysicians.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;postscript-2-packing-list&quot;&gt;Postscript 2: Packing List&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my packing list for a disney trip.  This section likely needs a bit more work so keep that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things You Bring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;jacket / fleece&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bathing suits; the pools generally are excellent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a 4 pack of Ramen noodles; our youngest has gotten seriously sick at the parks twice and ramen is his “I’m sick” food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things You Bring to the Park:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;misting fan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;good shoes with arch suports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;advil / tylenol / both&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bandaids and neosporin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hat / sunglasses per person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/19/a-father-s-guide-to-surviving-disney-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/09/19/a-father-s-guide-to-surviving-disney-world.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick Tip - How to Get the Best Hotel Wifi at Disney</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems to be an axiomatic rule of the universe that no one is is ever happy with connectivity when traveling.  One tip that works fantastically well for improving your connectivity when traveling, however, is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Up Early&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this from DisneyWorld and I’ve had ok luck with connectivity so far during the day but the mornings have been just plain outstanding.  I’m normally up by between 3 and 4 and what I have found is that connectivity is always best prior to 7 am.  That’s when people seem to get up and everything grinds to a halt.  I’ve been up working now for about an hour and the wifi is just plain screaming along.  I’ve watched 60 plus photos sync to DropBox while I started this post – its why I realized it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/wifi/2016/09/18/quick-tip-how-to-get-the-best-hotel-wifi-at-disney.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/wifi/2016/09/18/quick-tip-how-to-get-the-best-hotel-wifi-at-disney.html</guid>
        
        <category>wifi</category>
        
        <category>disney</category>
        
        
        <category>wifi</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tripmate Titan Instructions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-own-personal-wifi-storage/&quot;&gt;Jeff, over at CodingHorror&lt;/a&gt;, recently turned me onto the TripMate Titan which is a tiny wifi hub which lets you plugin a USB stick that can be shared to your iPad.  This, coupled with the File Explorer app, lets your kid watch all of their programs without:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;having to sync them onto an iPad or Kindle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;having to have an iPad with lots of pricey storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;having to have them all in the precise mp4 format that Apple has blessed - MKV?  AVI?  MOV?  No problem!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a $40 product you can get from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00RVIGY1I/?tag=codihorr-20&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and it is &lt;strong&gt;brilliant&lt;/strong&gt;.  Best little hardware gadget I’ve bought in 2016 by far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve bought one, compiled a USB stick of the kid’s favorite shows and taken it away from home on vacation.  The only real issue that I’ve had is that using it takes a few discrete steps that last night, when I was exhausted, I bungled thus delaying watching by my boys.  Now Jeff’s post, linked above, covers all of this in exhaustive detail.  What’s listed below is the cliff notes version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn TripMate on by pressing center button and holding for 3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In wifi settings &lt;strong&gt;connect&lt;/strong&gt; to the device; it will be labeled TripMateSith-xxx.  The password is &lt;strong&gt;11111111&lt;/strong&gt; (8 ones).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In File Explorer add a &lt;strong&gt;windows share&lt;/strong&gt; if you don’t have one already.  This needs to be an ip address of &lt;strong&gt;10.10.10.254&lt;/strong&gt; with a username of &lt;strong&gt;admin&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;NO PASSWORD&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the right folder and enjoy some form of media goodness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn it off by pressing and holding down for 3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: You can use the built in admin tool to customize these settings and Jeff recommends it.  Me?  Eh.  I figured just write them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see all kinds of uses for this including putting movies from a family trip onto a USB stick to view via an iPad.  Recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/wifi/2016/09/17/tripmate-titan-instructions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/wifi/2016/09/17/tripmate-titan-instructions.html</guid>
        
        <category>wifi</category>
        
        <category>tripmate</category>
        
        
        <category>wifi</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interesting Kubernetes Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I found some interesting Kubernetes stuff yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danielmartins.ninja/posts/five-months-of-kubernetes.html&quot;&gt;Five Months of Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; (excellent)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreos/coreos-kubernetes/tree/master/multi-node/aws&quot;&gt;kube-aws&lt;/a&gt; looks like the way to go if you use AWS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://railsadventures.wordpress.com/2015/12/06/why-we-chose-kubernetes-over-ecs/&quot;&gt;Why Kubernetes over ECS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;k8s is apparently the abbreviation for Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/kubernetes/2016/09/16/interesting-kubernetes-stuff.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/kubernetes/2016/09/16/interesting-kubernetes-stuff.html</guid>
        
        <category>kubernetes</category>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        
        <category>kubernetes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elixir Tutorial 03 - Deploying to Ubuntu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As discussed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/15/elixir-tutorial-02-adding-redis-support-to-our-page-fetcher.html&quot;&gt;my last Elixir Tutorial post&lt;/a&gt; we are trying to build a redis driven page fetcher that will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;connect to redis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pop a tuple of information that identifies what to fetch including a url&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;will fetch the page from the internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;will save the html to a database table for processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Elixir is new to me (and arguably most people), the question of how to get this running on a server is actually a big deal.  Getting stuff running on a server is what is called deployment and deploying code can be tricky.  It literally took years before I was comfortable with the state of Ruby deployment and it is only relatively recently that I would posit that Capistrano is actually good.  So given the relatively embryonic state of Elixir, what are our deployment options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;git clone to a server and adjust settings manually as needed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;build to a container and push&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use a CI tool like &lt;a href=&quot;http://elviovicosa.com/blog/2016/07/13/deploying-elixir-releases.html&quot;&gt;this approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/boldpoker/edeliver&quot;&gt;e-deliver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitwalker/distillery&quot;&gt;distillery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial, I’m going to do a straight git clone to make sure I understand how an Elixir app is structured and then I’ll likely move to either distillery or e-deliver in a later tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-elixir-installed-server-side&quot;&gt;Getting Elixir Installed Server Side&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working on an Ubuntu 14.04 trusty box for this.  Here are the steps from  &lt;a href=&quot;http://elixir-lang.org/install.html&quot;&gt;elixir-lang&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wget https://packages.erlang-solutions.com/erlang-solutions_1.0_all.deb &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo dpkg -i erlang-solutions_1.0_all.deb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sudo apt-get install esl-erlang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sudo apt-get install elixir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have at all an unreliable network connection then run Tmux first so connection loss doesn’t bork your install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that while your results may vary, this is not a fast install by any means.  I witnessed the erlang install take more than 40 minutes or enough time to browse the internet quite a bit, discover &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timezone.io&quot;&gt;timezone.io&lt;/a&gt; and setup a whole remote organization with it.  Very cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cloning-your-project&quot;&gt;Cloning Your Project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as your server has access to Github then it should be a simple matter of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mkdir ~/elixir (to give a project root)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cd ~/elixir&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;git clone git@github.com:fuzzygroup/elixir_page_fetcher.git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then to test your project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cd ~/elixir/elixir_page_fetcher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mix deps.get&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;answer Y to install the hex package manager or do mix local.hex –force as your first step&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mix test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all goes well the code should compile and the test should run.  Here’s what the whole process looked like for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[foo@adl-ad-work2 /home/foo/srv/current]$ cd ~/elixir/elixir_page_fetcher/
[foo@adl-ad-work2 /home/foo/elixir/elixir_page_fetcher]$ mix deps.get
Could not find Hex, which is needed to build dependency :exredis
Shall I install Hex? (if running non-interactively, use: &quot;mix local.hex --force&quot;) [Yn] Y
* creating /home/foo/.mix/archives/hex-0.13.0
Running dependency resolution
* Getting exredis (Hex package)
  Checking package (https://repo.hex.pm/tarballs/exredis-0.2.5.tar)
  Fetched package
* Getting eredis (Hex package)
  Checking package (https://repo.hex.pm/tarballs/eredis-1.0.8.tar)
  Fetched package
[foo@adl-ad-work2 /home/foo/elixir/elixir_page_fetcher]$ mix test
Could not find &quot;rebar&quot;, which is needed to build dependency :eredis
I can install a local copy which is just used by Mix
Shall I install rebar? (if running non-interactively, use: &quot;mix local.rebar --force&quot;) [Yn] Y
* creating /home/foo/.mix/rebar
* creating /home/foo/.mix/rebar3
==&amp;gt; eredis (compile)
Compiled src/basho_bench_driver_erldis.erl
Compiled src/eredis.erl
Compiled src/eredis_sub.erl
Compiled src/basho_bench_driver_eredis.erl
Compiled src/eredis_sub_client.erl
Compiled src/eredis_client.erl
Compiled src/eredis_parser.erl
==&amp;gt; exredis
Compiling 5 files (.ex)
Generated exredis app
==&amp;gt; page_fetcher
Compiling 1 file (.ex)
Generated page_fetcher app
.

Finished in 0.1 seconds
1 test, 0 failures

Randomized with seed 243121
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understanding-some-elixir-ecosystem-basics&quot;&gt;Understanding Some Elixir Ecosystem Basics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a number of things in the output above that may need some clarification:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.erlang.org/&quot;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt; - this is the root language which Elixir is written in.  Erlang provides a language, a virtual machine and the OTP framework which is designed for building concurrent, distributed applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hex.pm&quot;&gt;Hex&lt;/a&gt; - this is the underlying package manager for Elixir.  Think of it as Ruby Gems but improved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/erlang/rebar3&quot;&gt;Rebar&lt;/a&gt; - this is a build tool which makes it easier to build Erlang applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-time&quot;&gt;Next Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next tutorial I will, hopefully, actually get to write some working Elixir code - what I’ve been trying to work towards for weeks if not months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/16/elixir-tutorial-03-deploying-to-ubuntu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/16/elixir-tutorial-03-deploying-to-ubuntu.html</guid>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dad Why Is Your Face Bloody? An Essay on Shaving Economics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another excellent question from my youngest son.  I’ve heard it said that when the question begins with “Why …”, the answer generally is &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt; and that is the reason here.  My youngest is too young to shave so much of this won’t make sense to him yet but I’ll write it none the less since some day it might save him even more money than it saved me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three common types of razors that men shave with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cartridge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;disposable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only ever used cartridge and blade so I can’t talk to the underlying economics of disposable razors but I’d guess that they are between cartridge and blade on the pricing spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leading contender is cartridge and this is commonly sold by Gillette.  Blades for a top of the line Gillette like the Mach 5 Fusion tend to run about $6 to $8 per cartridge at least based on pricing at the supermarket.  And, in my experience, a given cartridge is good for no more than 3 weeks.  Yes I am a cheap bastard in pushing a single cartridge that long.  So 52 weeks per years / 3 weeks per blade means that you will use &lt;strong&gt;17 1/3&lt;/strong&gt; blades per year.  At say $7 / blade that means a year of shaving costs you &lt;strong&gt;$121&lt;/strong&gt;.  I turn 49 this year and I have been shaving daily since I was 18 which puts me at 31 years of daily shaving or as I often think of it &lt;em&gt;face scraping&lt;/em&gt;.  And at the $121 per year that means I have invested $3,761 in shaving to date over my life span.  And if I was to shave for another 40 years that would make the total $4,840 for the next 40 years or a lifetime total of $3,761 + $4,840 or $8,601 – for nothing more than the privilege of being clean shaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these numbers aren’t even 100% accurate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It doesn’t include shaving cream which would raise the total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It doesn’t allow for price increases which Gillette does with increasing frequency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cartridge razors didn’t used to be anywhere near as expensive so my $3,721 is likely too high.  On the other hand I didn’t used to be so cheap so I would would change the blade much more frequently so perhaps $3,721 is just fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most people I suspect, I’ve bought cars that were cheaper than $3,761.  My first car, in fact, cost under $3,000 (some work required admittedly) and I have to admit that I’d far rather have had one of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://porsonly.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/77933a3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;http://porsonly.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/77933a3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;than shaving my face for 31 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if cartridge razors are &lt;strong&gt;too expensive&lt;/strong&gt; then what is the solution and why is my face bloody?  The answer is to go back to what preceded cartridge razors – blade razors.  Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000NL0T1G/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;great example&lt;/a&gt; that I gave to my father this past father’s day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On November 24, 2014, I ordered from Amazon a blade razor for $29.47 and 100 blades for $47.94.  I’m still using the same damn box of blades.  That price gives me a per blade cost of $0.48 and a single blade lasts me at least 3 weeks.  So that blade is only about 6% of the overall cost of a cartridge blade.  And that changes my lifetime shaving economics to 6% of $8,601 or $516.  And that feels reasonable.  I’d always known that cartridge razors were ridiculously expensive but I never thought this expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and the reason for the bloody face?  When I change the blade every three weeks, the first two or three shaves the blade is so sharp that I might nick myself a bit.  But a touch of a styptic pencil and its fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you care about shaving then I highly recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/wicked_edge&quot;&gt;Wicked Edge subreddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/dad_why_do_you/2016/09/16/dad-why-is-your-face-bloody.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/dad_why_do_you/2016/09/16/dad-why-is-your-face-bloody.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad_why_do_you</category>
        
        <category>m</category>
        
        <category>shaving</category>
        
        <category>razor</category>
        
        <category>economics</category>
        
        
        <category>dad_why_do_you</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software Worth Purchasing 02 - Enpass</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Password Managers are one of those categories of tools that provoke fierce debate among us nerd folk.  Personally now that I’ve figured out how to remember a different password for every web site I log into, I’ve needed one less than I used to but the recent move to a monthly billing plan for 1 Password just plain made me furious.  Not only is that ridiculous but 1 Password, at least in my experience, doesn’t work worth a damn.  I spent the time and money to buy it for my wife and myself about a year 
ago and we had nothing but problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The task that flipped my need for a password manager was actually traveling to the recent Elixir Conf and realizing at the airport that I don’t know my TSA Pre number:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And even if I knew it where in the rabbit’s maze of tiny text files that surround my daily life would it go?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then would I really pull out a whole laptop at the airport just to get it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then even if it was in a text file how would I get it onto my phone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly a way to store information securely was needed.  A discussion on Hacker News of the 1 Password billing changes led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enpass.io/&quot;&gt;Enpass&lt;/a&gt; and I tried it.  And it worked.  Not only did it give me a way to store away my passwords but it nicely solved the TSA Pre number storage needs.  Their business model is that desktop is free they only charge for mobile when you need to sync beyond either 10 or 20 passwords.  They charge on a lifetime model which is likely a mistake and will definitely cause them business model issues over time but it is a great little product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and I recently tested out their support and got an answer all the way from India where it is written in about a half hour which is fantastic considering the time zone.  And the answer was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an endorsement if anyone over at Enpass wants a quote for their website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Enpass is a fantastic product.  It is the first password manager that not only works but works consistently well.  I’m now using it across my laptop, iPhone and iPad and am just delighted with it.  And they have great support.  &lt;strong&gt;Recommended&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_worth_purchasing/2016/09/15/software-worth-purchasing-02-enpass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_worth_purchasing/2016/09/15/software-worth-purchasing-02-enpass.html</guid>
        
        <category>software</category>
        
        <category>tools</category>
        
        <category>password_managers</category>
        
        
        <category>software_worth_purchasing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails2Elixir - Generating a New Elixir Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things where there isn’t a direct equivalent in the Rails world.  To generate a new Rails project you, of course, use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rails new
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that brings in, well, Rails.  And all of the plethora of stuff that entails.  What if you just wanted to generate a standalone application say a page fetcher that talked to Redis and got back a url to fetch so you could store it away.  In that case you wouldn’t want all of the whole Rails stack.  You might want say just redis or just rake but not everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As discussed previously, mix is the integrated version of rails, rake and bundler and that’s what we’re going to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix new page_fetcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that will work but if you really want something reliable – and if you don’t, why would you bother with Elixir at all – then you really want to add a supervision tree which makes this an OTP application.  OTP is the core Erlang libraries that related to building distributed, reliable code.  Here’s how to do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix new page_fetcher --sup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the official reference to &lt;a href=&quot;http://elixir-lang.org/docs/stable/mix/Mix.Tasks.New.html&quot;&gt;mix new&lt;/a&gt; in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails2elixir/2016/09/15/generating-a-new-elixir-project.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails2elixir/2016/09/15/generating-a-new-elixir-project.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails2elixir</category>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        
        <category>rails2elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elixir Tutorial 02 - Adding Redis Support to our Page Fetcher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails2elixir/2016/09/15/generating-a-new-elixir-project.html&quot;&gt;last elixir post&lt;/a&gt; I documented how to generate a standalone Elixir project for a page fetcher.  Technically that would have been Elixir Tutorial 01 but I’m too tired right now to go back and rename it since this is my middle of the night, can’t sleep coding time while on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a description of what we’re planning to build.  What is a page fetcher?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A page fetcher is a bit of software that pulls content (pages) from the Internet and stores them some where for processing by something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do we actually need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bit of software that runs reliably&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And doesn’t require writing low level libraries as we’re just not there yet with our Elixir skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And pulls content from Redis that describes what to fetch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And fetches a page off from a url&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And stores it away for processing.  Likely in a database or some such place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t sound so hard, does it?  Here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/artemeff/exredis&quot;&gt;redis library&lt;/a&gt; we’re going to use.  Let’s start by adding redis support to what we generated last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change into your working directory.  For me that is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/me/fuzzygroup/elixir/page_fetcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run mix test to make sure everything is still working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix test    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the file mix.exs in your editor and add the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;:exredis,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;gt;= 0.2.4&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This needs to go between the [] in the defp deps routine.  Think of it this way – you are updating Gemfile.  That’s all this is.  Only its a more reliable Gemfile without the cruft and crap of bundler.  I love you Ruby but good lord the packaging infrastructure lately blows monkey chunks.  Not a day goes by that I don’t hit some Gemfile / bundler crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run mix test again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’re going to see a failure like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sjohnson@ScottJohnsonMacbookAir:~/me/fuzzygroup/elixir/page_fetcher$ mix test
Unchecked dependencies for environment test:
* exredis (Hex package)
  the dependency is not available, run &quot;mix deps.get&quot;
** (Mix) Can't continue due to errors on dependencies
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’re going to do what I think of as the &lt;em&gt;deps dance&lt;/em&gt; and type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix deps.get
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’ll see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A new Hex version is available (0.13.0), please update with `mix local.hex`
Running dependency resolution
Dependency resolution completed
  eredis: 1.0.8
  exredis: 0.2.5
* Getting exredis (Hex package)
  Checking package (https://repo.hex.pm/tarballs/exredis-0.2.5.tar)
  Fetched package
* Getting eredis (Hex package)
  Checking package (https://repo.hex.pm/tarballs/eredis-1.0.8.tar)
  Fetched package    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mileage may vary with respect to the “please update …” stuff.  Please bear in mind that Hex isn’t perfect at present.  I’ve see issues but they are few and far between at least in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step up is to modify your project to talk to your Redis server.  Do that by modifying config/config.exs with your server params.  Here are mine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;config :exredis,
  host: &quot;127.0.0.1&quot;,
  port: 6379,
  password: &quot;&quot;,
  db: 0,
  reconnect: :no_reconnect,
  max_queue: :infinity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re connecting on 127.0.0.1 you need to run this on the same machine where your redis server lives or adjust the ip address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always when you change anything run your test suite which will compile your code and show you any errors.  Here’s what mine looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix test
==&amp;gt; eredis (compile)
Compiled src/eredis_sub.erl
Compiled src/eredis_parser.erl
Compiled src/eredis_sub_client.erl
Compiled src/basho_bench_driver_erldis.erl
Compiled src/eredis.erl
Compiled src/basho_bench_driver_eredis.erl
Compiled src/eredis_client.erl
==&amp;gt; exredis
Compiling 5 files (.ex)
Generated exredis app
==&amp;gt; page_fetcher
Compiling 1 file (.ex)
Generated page_fetcher app
.

Finished in 0.05 seconds
1 test, 0 failures

Randomized with seed 697093    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at this point we have an elixir application with a supervision tree for reliability and a redis client.  Given that I’m a strong believer in “deploy early; deploy often”, I’ll handle getting all this deployed onto an Ubuntu server.  After that I’ll tackle getting this to run continuously popping things from the redis queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All code can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/elixir_page_fetcher&quot;&gt;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/elixir_page_fetcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/15/elixir-tutorial-02-adding-redis-support-to-our-page-fetcher.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/15/elixir-tutorial-02-adding-redis-support-to-our-page-fetcher.html</guid>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
