<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc / Hyde.
</description>
    <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 10:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 10:13:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dropbox for the Software Developer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An old friend asked me a great question recently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I saw you mentioning your use of Dropbox the other day. I’ve been using GitHub as my “cloud device”: when would I find Dropbox a better option?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the single best decisions that I made in 2016 was to adopt &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; as the key part of my personal computing environment.  I last talked about this back on &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/postmac/2016/11/05/life-in-a-postmac-world.html&quot;&gt;November&lt;/a&gt;, see the section “Conclusion - A Synchronized Computing Environment For Me” but it really does bear further description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My use for Dropbox is exactly what it is designed for – synchronization.  I’ve always had multiple machines but one has always been my “primary”” machine.  Since all my code was on Github, I could generally get to my code from any machine but what about my spreadsheets?  Or my documents?  Or just about any other file that I needed.  Here’s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signup for a 1 Terabyte Dropbox account (roughly $50 / year so dirt cheap).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Dropbox on all my machines including my ChromeBook, my Linux box, my iPhone and iPad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Symlink ~/Dropbox to ~/me so I have an easier path to type.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move all the files that matter to me into ~/me under a logical file structure related to my usage context - ~/me/blogging for all my blogs, ~/me/Documents for Documents, ~/me/consulting for consulting work, ~/me/fuzzygroup for anything I do online and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move important things like SSH keys under ~/me and then use symlinks to insert them back into their correct location.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a ~/me/transfer directory to copy transitory data from one machine to anther.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move all the git repos that matter underneath ~/me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My working set of data for Dropbox is about 40 gigabytes and I suspect that could be made smaller but I haven’t seen the need.  This approach has meant that literally no matter what computing device I am on, I always have access to the data that actually matters to me.  True I don’t have, for example, my iTunes music synchronized or my Photos but in terms of the data that I, as a software developer, actually rely on, this is about as perfect an environment as I could dream up.  The only objection I have is that on one of my machines, oddly the most powerful, Dropbox refuses to fully sync, always stalling out on two files that never complete.  Since there are no user facing logs on Dropbox for OSX, well, I have no idea what they are.  And, worse, it spikes my CPU past 100% always running up the fan and down the battery life.  But, other than that, I’m ridiculously happy with this as an approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that this was supposed to be what Apple was going to give us with iCloud but iCloud:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doesn’t seem to work particularly well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removes local file storage of documents into the cloud solely thus absolutely screwing you over if you don’t have internet access&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has no cross platform support – I really wanted all my data on my ChromeBook and my Linux box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is astonishing to me that the cross machine synchronization environment that I’ve been searching for most of my professional life is nothing more than a simple Dropbox subscription but that’s all it took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still do full OS level backups periodically but I don’t generally worry about it terribly since the data that matters is always safe being mirrored across all my computing devices and into the Dropbox cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/dropbox/2017/03/13/dropbox-for-the-software-developer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/dropbox/2017/03/13/dropbox-for-the-software-developer.html</guid>
        
        <category>dropbox</category>
        
        
        <category>dropbox</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leveling Up as a Developer Part 2 - Interstitial Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/software_engineering/2017/02/24/leveling-up-as-a-developer.html&quot;&gt;Leveling Up as a Developer&lt;/a&gt;.  Leveraging Interstitial Time is another approach to improve your skills.  As a developer there are at least two very different types of learning that you have to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep, Focused Learning&lt;/strong&gt;.  The classic example here is the syntax of a language.  Some of us can do that by simply reading a book but most of us need the focused, “muscle memory” effort of actually doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness Learning&lt;/strong&gt;.  A huge part of the IT or Information Technology space is simply being aware that something exists.  Whether it is a tool, a particular library, an algorithm or merely a way to approach a problem, awareness is often all you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know how to do deep focused learning – you sit, generally alone, in a quiet space with a computer and lots of time and you work at it.  Some of us have a set of problems that we like to solve to teach ourselves.  Others focus on working through tutorials.  And there are certainly other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you tackle &lt;em&gt;awareness learning&lt;/em&gt;?  Given how vast the world of IT is in 2017, how can you possibly be aware of everything you need to know to be an effective software engineer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of this post talks about awareness learning and my approach to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understanding-interstitial-time&quot;&gt;Understanding Interstitial Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as an interstitial ad is the ad that shows up between page transitions, I view interstitial time as the &lt;em&gt;time between times&lt;/em&gt;.  A good example of this came up last night – I had to peel two pounds of shrimp for dinner.  This was easily 30 minutes of time when my hands were occupied and I really couldn’t do much.  Given that my hands were nasty dirty, I couldn’t even turn the pages of a book while I did it.  To me that’s interstitial time – normally it would be entirely wasted.  What I do, however, is turn interstitial time into awareness learning because while I can’t do much, I can &lt;strong&gt;listen&lt;/strong&gt; – and that’s at the heart of awareness learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;required-items&quot;&gt;Required Items&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the things you need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/smart_phone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smart_phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some type of smart phone; doesn’t have to be iOS, android is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/bluetooth_headset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bluetooth_headset.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bluetooth headset.  Personally I favor the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Plantronics-Universal-Cancelling-Wireless-Bluetooth/dp/B010XDJTWS&quot;&gt;Plantronics M180&lt;/a&gt; but any one will work.  This one has good volume, easy pairing and a 7 hour battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/icatcher-podcast-player/id414419105?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/icatcher.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;icatcher.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need some kind of podcasting listening tool.  Personally I Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/icatcher-podcast-player/id414419105?mt=8&quot;&gt;iCatcher&lt;/a&gt; on iOS but &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/overcast-podcast-player/id888422857?mt=8&quot;&gt;OverCast&lt;/a&gt; by Marco Arment is also excellent and I recently bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/apple-store/id1080840241?mt=8&amp;amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4&quot;&gt;Castro&lt;/a&gt; but haven’t used it as well.  There are great ones on Android as well but none that I have personally used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/podcast_feed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;podcast_feed.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is some podcast feed that’s going to download new things to learn right into your phone on an ongoing basis.  Thankfully, in 2017, that essentially means any podcast on the planet – since they pretty much all have an RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From top to bottom this is a smart phone, a bluetooth headset and a podcast feed or podcast feeds of things that for your type of software engineering you should be aware.  I’m a generalist with a focus on web and back end so I find &lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/&quot;&gt;Software Engineering Daily&lt;/a&gt; to be outstanding.  But here are some more great learning sources by category:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DevOps - &lt;a href=&quot;http://packetpushers.net/datanauts-podcast/&quot;&gt;Datanaughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big Data - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drilltodetail.com/&quot;&gt;Drill to Detail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online Marketing - &lt;a href=&quot;http://okdork.com/podcast/&quot;&gt;Noah Kagan Presents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine Learning - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetalkingmachines.com/&quot;&gt;Talking Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Science - &lt;a href=&quot;https://dataskeptic.com/podcast&quot;&gt;Data Skeptic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript - &lt;a href=&quot;https://devchat.tv/js-jabber&quot;&gt;JavaScript Jabber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby - &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/rubyonrails&quot;&gt;5by5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elixir - &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/elixirfountain&quot;&gt;Elixir Fountain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you can see that there is a podcast for almost any time of IT learning.  For example I just googled for Embedded System podcast and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://embedded.fm/&quot;&gt;Embedded.fm&lt;/a&gt; which is 189 episodes long on Embedded Systems and is currently covering Soft Robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just google for what you need to learn about and then “podcast” and you’re very likely to find something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pulling-off-awareness-learning-on-an-ongoing-basis&quot;&gt;Pulling Off Awareness Learning On an Ongoing Basis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to this is that you need to develop a &lt;strong&gt;habit&lt;/strong&gt; around applying interstitial time to learning.  Here’s all you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the things above&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your headset and phone regularly charged&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whenever you’ve got at least 5 minutes doing something crappy – commuting, dishes, peeling shrimp, raking leaves, building your kids tree house, widening your driveway with a pickaxe, sitting with your kids while the fall asleep – it can be anything, you &lt;strong&gt;listen&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;learn&lt;/strong&gt;.  And, yes, I did build a tree house while listening to Ruby podcasts and I widened a driveway doing the same thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep at it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last one, Keeping at it, is the hard part.  If you work in IT then your days tend to be long and there are times that your brain just hurts and you don’t want to listen to, well, YMITC (yet more IT crap).  It doesn’t matter, this only works if you stick with it.  So you suck it up and build it into a habit where you just keep at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s pretty much it but let me finish up with a concrete example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-example&quot;&gt;An Example&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently listening to Software Engineering Daily, their podcast on &lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/02/28/heroku-autoscaling-with-andrew-gwozdziewycz/&quot;&gt;Heroku AutoScaling&lt;/a&gt; and Andrew Gwozdziewycz gave their algorithm for determining when to auto scale.  He described it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Time point: 35:40 Autoscaling like I said is a little bit more complicated.  The only data we use for auto scaling is your response time, the p95 response time, the number of requests that you’re serving be it errors or successful requests and the number of dynos that you currently have.  And what we do is utilize Little’s Law, this thing from queueing theory that basically  says (gives example of bank tellers and queues) - think of the arrival rate as through put and think of the latency as the time a teller takes to make a deposit or withdrawal.  These things are interrelated into this relationship – Little’s Law.  We look at the actual number of bank tellers versus the theoretical number if the latency is zero.  If you’re app starts responding greater than that latency then we’ll scale it up to get that latency down.  We put that into an exponential weighted moving average and we plot a regression line and the slope of that regression line gives us whether or not its ok to scale up or scale down.  (Time point: 38:50)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I may have munged the description a bit but if you start listening at minute 35 and go thru it once or twice, you’ll pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just having heard that much, I can think of about a dozen different ways to apply that algorithm to my daily work as I’m sure you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s why I listen to podcasts so avidly – trying to come up with something like this on your own is truly hard but just knowning that this exists often gives you the critical first step to solving this type of problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2017/03/12/leveling-up-as-a-developer-part-2-interstitial-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2017/03/12/leveling-up-as-a-developer-part-2-interstitial-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using ngrok for Web Development</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 17:22:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/11/using-ngrok-for-web-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/11/using-ngrok-for-web-development.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>There's Always A Reason</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So the side project I’ve been referring to&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 03:07:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2017/03/09/there-s-always-a-reason.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2017/03/09/there-s-always-a-reason.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>developer_psychology</category>
        
        <category>cartazzi</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Sidekiq Makes You Nuts Check Your Types</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of what I do at the job I’m in the process of leaving is large scale data processing and it is all done through queues and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sidekiq.org&quot;&gt;Sidekiq&lt;/a&gt;.  I generally do it with a method call that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CompileWorker.perform_async(id)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today though I had to do it and pass in a date to my method call so I had this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CompileWorker.perform_async(id, date)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I got crazy, crazy, crazy results – my object would get about 10 lines into the call and then … nothing.  I’d test my method line by line in rails console on production and it would work perfectly.  I even went so far as to isolate it down to one Sidekiq thread and one redis server (on local host no less to make sure that no other sidekiq worker was messing with things).  And nothing made any difference.  Finally I realized that the crucial difference was actually that I was passing in a date.  Here’s the docs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t pass symbols, named parameters or complex Ruby objects (like Date or Time!) as those will not survive the dump/load round trip correctly. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mperham/sidekiq/wiki/Best-Practices&quot;&gt;More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, sure enough, when I removed the date by treating it as an internal constant, it worked perfectly.  Here’s the workaround I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;compile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;is_a?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I call it as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;CompileWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;perform_async&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows my internal use of the compile method where a date is passed in normally to function without issue but to work correctly when called in an asynchronous manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually don’t have a problem with Sidekiq working in this fashion but it does bother me that while the Sidekiq documentation warns about this, there’s no error thrown or alert raised.  Now it might be impossible to pull off an error message but this is a damn easy mistake to make.  I knew about the ActiveRecord object limitation in Sidekiq but didn’t have a clue that it extended to a simple date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/03/08/when-sidekiq-makes-you-nuts-check-your-types.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/03/08/when-sidekiq-makes-you-nuts-check-your-types.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>sidekiq</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Side Project Validation - Finally</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: I wrote this blog post a number of weeks ago when this happened (about 1 minute after) but there was no point to publishing it until the product launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing a side project is a damn lonely thing.  You sit in front of a blank code editor with no code to start and then you literally &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; it into existence.  Often you don’t even discuss it with the people in your life – perhaps the idea is too ludicrous or perhaps past side projects haven’t panned out and you don’t want the scrutiny.  Or perhaps you have kids in which case how the kids did in school the previous day is far, far more relevant than minor code triumphs.  But there is always that spark when you realize “Oh man – this might really work”.  That just happened for me.  It was 3:07 am on Tuesday March 7th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cartazzi, as you know by now, is a personal analytics dashboard that helps you succeed online with one click analytics.  Like any data centric product I’ve ever built, Cartazzi is built from real world data.  I was looking at the home page for my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidrovics.com&quot;&gt;David Rovics&lt;/a&gt; and noticed that he was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.songkick.com/artists/152746-david-rovics&quot;&gt;SongKick user&lt;/a&gt;.  I had no idea what SongKick was but Cartazzi is built to support the analytics sources people actually use and someone linking to something on their home page is a strong signal to us to support it.  So I follow the link and discover that David has 847 fans.  Ok then – that’s a metric and that’s something I should be able to support.  So I go through my “build a new parser dance” for Cartazzi and scaffold together a new parser.  At this point I’ve implemented 42 of these things comprising almost 4K lines of code so I’m pretty good at it.  About 5 minutes later I have a new PageSongKickArtist parser object and it works out of the gate.  These things working the first time wasn’t a surprise by this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do my normal testing dance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;start with the data I began with and confirm that it works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;find another instance of this type of data - I found the band &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.songkick.com/artists/5183683-houndmouth&quot;&gt;HoundMouth&lt;/a&gt; by just randomly clicking around SongKick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I notice that HoundMouth has 39,058 fans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I build a parser object in Rails console and verify the data – and it increased to 39,059!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a glitch.  It is absolute confirmation that what I built for Cartazzi is on point and will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I bandsintown&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 04:15:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/cartazzi/2017/03/07/side-project-validation-finally.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/cartazzi/2017/03/07/side-project-validation-finally.html</guid>
        
        <category>cartazzi</category>
        
        
        <category>cartazzi</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cartazzi Parser Dance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;wget the url&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bundle exec rails g page_parser page_song_kick_artist&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 03:49:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/07/the-cartazzi-parser-dance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/07/the-cartazzi-parser-dance.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Ansible as a Development Tool with Rails and AWS for Large Scale Data Processing Automation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Man it was a hell of a busy week last week.  Here’s an illustration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/me/appdatallc/ansible-clean [master|✚ 1…1]
01:34 $ find . -name '*.yml' | xargs wc -l
...
283 total

~/me/appdatallc/ansible_monthly [master|✔]
find . -name '*.yml' | xargs wc -l
...
 1066 total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep.  Starting last week, from Monday morning to Friday afternoon, working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://winstonkotzan.com/&quot;&gt;Winston&lt;/a&gt; to teach him &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, I authored almost 1,300 lines of Ansible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really interesting part of this was using Ansible as a &lt;strong&gt;development tool&lt;/strong&gt; with Rails.  The use case in question was automating production of large scale data processing jobs.  Example what these jobs did is highly proprietary but they basically had a shared architecture like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Execute on a developer’s workstation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verify state of the application by calling an API server side&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change the thread count as needed for the right amount of concurrency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear the rails log&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the right redis server to isolate sidekiq from other concurrently executing jobs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear the Sidekiq log&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make an AMI of the EC2 instance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch N instances of the AMI to do the needed data processing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill the Sidekiq queue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Display the count of items in the Sidekiq queue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a series of 8 different data processing jobs, 6 of which matched the above list and two of which were slightly different.  Each of the stages above was represented by a small Ansible playbook and the coordination between each of the playbooks was handled by a bash script which called each of the stages in succession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classically Ansible is a devops tool for provisioning boxes but last week really illustrated to me the power of &lt;strong&gt;Ansible as a development tool&lt;/strong&gt;.  Ansible’s idempotent, state based approach of modeling the world as a succession of yaml files can definitely be funky but the model works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;adding-status-tracking&quot;&gt;Adding Status Tracking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early Friday I realized that once these jobs were running, the developer running them would need to understand the status of the job on a highly discrete level.  Historically I’ve done this by directly querying the database and just &lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; the objects involved and the tables that represent them.  But that comes from a huge amount of internal domain knowlege that Winston didn’t have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This status would need to include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amount of data left in the sidekiq queue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amount of records produced for each job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure in an idealized world this would be a pretty, graphical dashboard available on the web to all people in the company.  Practically speaking, the following is sufficient:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TASK [run_rake_task_and_show_output : debug] &lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;*****
ok: [monthly-categorization] =&amp;gt; {
    “msg”: [
        “in LoadError rescue statement”,
        “Queue Size = 0”,
        “Total categorization records = 271408”,
        “Total distinct entities in categorization = 6783”
    ]
}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to run this at any point in the process is hugely useful and here’s an example of how simple that code can be.  There are three key pieces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ansible Playbook - a playbook which defined a Rake namespace and task to be executed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ansible Role - essentially a function which executes the Rake namespace and task, capturing its output and displaying it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rake Task - the business logic of what to analyze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ansible-playbook&quot;&gt;Ansible Playbook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ansible&quot;&gt;    - hosts: monthly-categorization
      become: yes
      remote_user: ubuntu
      vars:
        - rake_task: &quot;monthly:echo_stats&quot;
      roles:
        - { role: run_rake_task_and_show_output }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ansible-role&quot;&gt;Ansible Role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ansible&quot;&gt;    - name: run a rake task on the target box
      shell: 
        chdir: /var/www/apps/rails_app/current
        cmd:  RAILS_ENV=production bundle exec rake 
      register: result

    - debug:
        msg: &quot;&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass on all this had the output being listed as a jumbled mess (typical to captured output by Ansible).  Winston correctly pointed out something to the effect of “Looks a bit like arse”.  Well a quick google led to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/34188167/ansible-print-message-debug-msg-line1-n-var2-n-line3-with-var3&quot;&gt;StackOverflow post&lt;/a&gt; where this technique:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;msg: “”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;could be applied.  In our case we had it as result so it was just a matter of replacing msg with result.stdout.  And, almost magically, that jumbled mess came into razor sharp focus.  My thanks to Winston for recognizing that this was an issue.  I was so close to the problem that I didn’t even perceive it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rake-task-being-called-by-playbook&quot;&gt;Rake task being called by Playbook:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:echo_stats&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:environment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data_shard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;ShardedData&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;shard_for_date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;service&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;distinct_entities&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data_shard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;entity_id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;distinct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;
    
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Queue Size = &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Sidekiq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Queue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Total categorization records from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; = &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data_shard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;    
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Total distinct entity_ids in categorization from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; = &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;distinct_entities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;    
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more complex example of this based on Ruby meta-programming is shown below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:echo_other_stats&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:environment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tables&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tables&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;rating_estimates&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tables&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;type_estimates&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tables&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;category_estimates&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stats&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt;
    
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;table&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;table&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;table&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;classify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;constantize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:job_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Table: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; = &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; for Processing Run &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;ProcessingRun&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach was based on some internal analysis logic where we had an array of table names that we used for generating some SQL code dynamically.  It took about 5 minutes to convert that list of tables into this.  The table.classify.constantize call takes the name of the table and first converts it to a model name (classify) and the converts that model name to a constant that represents the class itself.  Once you have a class that inherits from ActiveRecord you can then call a .where statement to get a count.  Finally you inject the original table name and the count back into a hash to store the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been managing this job production process for almost two years now and most of my approaches to making it better have evolved around different rake tasks and some fairly bad internal documentation.  By pulling Ansible into this, for the first time, we actually have a solution which:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goes end to end&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automates tasks like AMI creation and instance launching historically done with the AWS developer console&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows use of N instances to process the data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fully uses our existing code base without change – I can’t emphasize this point enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Displays status on the running jobs at any point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is broken down into small, modular chunks – each of our playbooks are maybe 10 lines in total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible isn’t how I expected to solve this problem but its approach really, really worked – keep it in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/aws/2017/03/06/using-ansible-as-a-development-tool-with-rails.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/aws/2017/03/06/using-ansible-as-a-development-tool-with-rails.html</guid>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>shell</category>
        
        <category>bash</category>
        
        <category>sidekiq</category>
        
        <category>devops</category>
        
        <category>meta_programming</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CloudBleed Revisited</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this then you’re almost certainly a developer (or a friend; Hi Dave West) and if so I would urge you to listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/03/04/cloudbleed-and-sha-1-collision-with-max-burkhardt/&quot;&gt;Software Engineering Daily podcast on CloudBleed&lt;/a&gt;.  Just follow the link and you can listen right from your browser.  You should really do this now whether or not you ever listen to podcasts.  As most developers I fall into the category of “security conscious but not really security knowledgeable” and this podcast does a fantastic job of making clear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exactly what happened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether or not it was a big deal (personally I think its a bigger deal than they acknowledged)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What passwords you should change (I changed my Medium and Uber passwords)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explaining the issues with SHA1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to absolutely commend Jeff from SE Daily for not doing this interview himself.  While I really, really enjoy Jeff’s style, security is hard&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 04:44:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/cloud_bleed/2017/03/05/cloudbleed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/cloud_bleed/2017/03/05/cloudbleed.html</guid>
        
        <category>cloud_bleed</category>
        
        <category>cloud_flare</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
        <category>cloud_bleed</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create Custom Generators Using Pattern Generator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am strongly of the opinion that Rails generators are one of the unsung heros of the Rails world.  Certainly the fact that a Rails generator always creates the matching test stub has to have influenced the success of testing in the Rails world.  And while Rails generators are great, there aren’t a lot of easy options when you want a customized generator.  In the remainder of this post, I’ll discuss the gem Pattern Generator which lets you put together&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;caveats&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re working with a fork of Pattern Generator you should be aware that your fork is inherently going to be publicly available on Github.  Keep that in mind if you view the model that you’ve generated is proprietary.  In that case you may need to break the fork and make it non-public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 11:34:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/04/create-custom-generators-using-pattern-generator.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/04/create-custom-generators-using-pattern-generator.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
