<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc / Hyde.
</description>
    <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 02:06:12 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 02:06:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So that &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/aws/2017/01/26/s3-ruby-api-programming-tip.html&quot;&gt;data center migration&lt;/a&gt; that I mentioned recently has turned into not, well a disaster, but a bit of challenge.  The problem at hand was how to get data off three large MySQL databases, about 4 terabytes in size and then capture whatever else was desired and do it all in about 10 days to avoid getting hit with another $5 K data center monthly fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: If you want a hilarious tale of how this data actually got to the data center in the first place then I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/humor/2014/08/21/anatomy-of-a-business-trip-gone-horribly-wrong.html&quot;&gt;Anatomy of a Business Trip Gone Horribly Wrong&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this data was in Ubuntu virtual machines apparently hosted under Windows Server Hyper-V.  Why any hosting company worth their salt would ever opt to run a *nix based operating system under the Windows Hyper-V, well, I don’t understand.  Sigh.  I’ll come back to this if I have the mental energy to engage in a rant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial approach was to roll a custom backup solution which took a prioritized list of databases and tables and them dumped the data using mysqldump, split the data with the unix split tool and then gzipped each split file.  Finally it uploaded it to S3, deleting its in process work files as it goes.  Yes this sounds awfully convoluted but rolling your own means that you actually understand what it is in and isn’t doing – something critical when you are know the original hardware is going away forever.  And since I didn’t have much in the way of free disc space, this could not be done all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this approach we transferred over 400 gigs of data to S3.  Given that this was gzip compressed data without the MySQL index overhead, which takes up a huge amount of the raw disc space, we got a sizable percentage of the data.  And, yes, that’s why I blogged about &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/linux/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-use-bmon-for-bandwidth-monitoring.html&quot;&gt;bmon&lt;/a&gt; recently – I was monitoring these transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, by the power of Murphy’s Law, I wasn’t able to get it all.  So this called for mechanism #2 – hard drives.  I delivered to the data center several three terabyte drives with instructions to the effect of “Get these mounted and I’ll do the rest”.  My plan was to just use ansible to recursively copy the directory structures onto the hard drives, get the drives back and then go on my merry way.  Remember – all I wanted was the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly the hosting company was never able to get these hard drives to show up in the Ubuntu virtual machine that is running under the Windows Hyper-V.  I don’t understand why but since I wasn’t physically in the data center, I couldn’t do much about it.  With time running out the hosting company suggested “Why don’t we just copy the virtual machines onto the hard drives and then you can have your exact environment and do what you want”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds great, doesn’t it?  I mean who wouldn’t want their old servers back, right?  Well, &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; actually.  Once again, what I wanted was &lt;strong&gt;my data&lt;/strong&gt;.  I didn’t want the virtual machines but since I have them, here’s how I went about using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks go out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickjanetakis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; who walked me thru large parts of this and edited this documentation.  I’m a *nix guy who last used Windows XP in 2004.  The experience was, well, illuminating to say the least.  I’m sure that I will return to this in a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here were the initial steps that I had to follow to get ready to use these virtual machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy a Windows laptop&lt;/strong&gt;.  This was the first step.  I took a trip to the local &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frys.com/&quot;&gt;Frys&lt;/a&gt; and managed to find a refurbished HP laptop for only $500.  The key thing here is that you need Windows 10 Pro.  If you don’t have Windows 10 Pro you don’t have the Hyper-V tools.  And since Windows 10 Pro is about $200, well, it really is cheaper to buy it installed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the BIOS Options to Enable Virtualization&lt;/strong&gt;.  Every BIOS is different so I can’t tell you where / how to do this.  I had to press F10 during the boot process and navigate thru all the options until I found the virtualization options and turned them on.  If you don’t do this then the HyperVisor itself won’t start and you won’t be able to run virtual machines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the HyperV Manager in Windows&lt;/strong&gt;.   We enabled hyper-v by searching for “windows features” and then turned it on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect the USB Drive / Drives&lt;/strong&gt;.  This was just a plug and play operation so piece of cake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Label the Physical Drives&lt;/strong&gt;.  This is optional but since I have 26 virtual machines spread across three physical hard drives so I used my label maker to indicate which virtual machines are on which hard drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the hard drives attached, the next step was to actually deal with the virtual machines.  Even though I had actual .vhdx virtual machine files, for some bizarre reason, I was unable to use them directly.  Instead I had to recreate the virtual machine from scratch, yes, 26 times, and then attach the .vhdx file as a drive.  This process was something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I say “something like this” because I’m writing this from memory after a long, long day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the HyperVisor Manager, start by creating a virtual network interface.  This needs to be your very &lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt; step because without it you can’t attach the .vhdx files – you wil die on errors like “Hyper-V encountered an error while configuring the network on New Virtual Machine”.  This should be called NIC#1 or at least this is what I needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a new virtual machine and walk thru the steps and in the last step browse to the .vhdx file and select it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But if your vhdx file is actually in two parts then you don’t want to browse to the .vhdx file at all.  Instead create the virtual machine and then edit its settings after the fact and attach the multiple .vhdx files at that stage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once your .vhdx files are attached as per #2 or #3 then you can actually make use of them.  Remember that these really are virtual machines and, well, you still have some hoops to jump through.  The first step is to turn on the virtual machine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After the virtual machine is running you then need to connect to it.  And this, dear reader, is where you will be confronted by a login prompt – and you will realize that you’ve been using SSH keys to login for over two years now and you have &lt;strong&gt;no idea&lt;/strong&gt; what the password is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A quick email back to the data center staff will elicit information like “well it might be this username and this password or it might be this other username and this other password”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here’s where I’m going to argue against rational security practices and say use your label maker again and attach the different username / password combos physically to each backup hard drive.  Trust me – when I need this data for real sometime in the next six months I’m going to be wondering where the heck that text message with the details disappeared to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’ve resolved the username and password info you can actually get into a database server virtual machine and verify that, well, it appears to be actual data.  I mean the directories appear to be there and the data appears to be real.  Huzzah!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;sudo su&lt;/strong&gt; to root and the do a &lt;strong&gt;passwd actual_username&lt;/strong&gt; and reset that password to something insecure but easy (again these are virtual machines on hard drives on a development laptop; its ok).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then the grim spectre of reality strikes – you go and start MySQL and you get this wonderful kick to the nuts: “The partition with /var/lib/mysql is too full”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s where I stopped.  As best I can tell I actually have the data and the virtual machines but I don’t know if the data is actually valid.  My guess is that verifying this is likely about a full week of repetitive, manual, unscriptable work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some screenshots I captured along with way.  And yes, because I don’t have the equivalent of command+shift+4 on OSX, I used my phone.  Alas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows-hardware-on-my-desk&quot;&gt;Windows Hardware On My Desk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/hyperv_hardware.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hyperv_hardware.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-error-when-you-dont-have-a-virtual-network-adapter&quot;&gt;The Error when You Don’t have a Virtual Network Adapter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/hyperv_error.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hyperv_error.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hyperv-manager&quot;&gt;The HyperV Manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/hyperv_manager.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hyperv_manager.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-ubuntu-virtual-machine-running-under-hyperv&quot;&gt;An Ubuntu Virtual Machine Running Under HyperV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/hyperv_mounted_filesystem.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hyperv_mounted_filesystem.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 02:06:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/31/2017-01-31-working-with-windows-10-pro-hypervisor-when-you-are-a-mac-guy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/31/2017-01-31-working-with-windows-10-pro-hypervisor-when-you-are-a-mac-guy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip of the Day inotifywait</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My podcast listening, which has always been on the nerdy side, has recently taken a trip down the far, far nerdier rabbit hole.  Whereas I used to listen to things with at least some connection to pop culture such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://majorspoilers.com/category/podcast/&quot;&gt;Major Spoilers&lt;/a&gt;, I now find myself listening to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntupodcast.org/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, a British podcast covering the Ubuntu community.  It was there that I learned about inotifywait and I had a feeling it was brilliant.  I tried it out and it is brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install on Linux, use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install inotify-tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since inotify is a Linux api this doesn’t exist for OSX but you can use an open source tool called notifywait available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggreer/fsevents-tools&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Alternatively there is fswatch which can be easily installed with &lt;strong&gt;brew fswatch&lt;/strong&gt;.  Please note that I didn’t try either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inotifywait utility takes a few command line parameters and then tells you all file accesses that go on in that directory.  This sounds a bit obscure but here’s how I tested it last night:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;inotifywait ~ -mr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tells inotifywait to run on the ~ or home directory and monitor it forever (the m flag) and r tells it to monitor recursively on all directories below the current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of its output once I set it monitoring in one shell window on a server after I logged into the same box in a different shell window and then touched the file foo.txt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/inotifywait.png&quot; alt=&quot;inotifywait.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really interesting here is that while I sort of know that the bash prompt initialization pattern is .profile and then  .bashrc but I’ve never &lt;strong&gt;seen&lt;/strong&gt; it before.  I have a feeling that I’ll understand this better from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is this useful for sysadmin / devops work but I can see it being highly useful for application developers. Sometimes the files you are touching or your io access patterns are not always apparent.  Using inotifywait makes them obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different events can even be monitored with the –e flag.  Here’s what you can monitor for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Events:
	access		file or directory contents were read
	modify		file or directory contents were written
	attrib		file or directory attributes changed
	close_write	file or directory closed, after being opened in
	           	writable mode
	close_nowrite	file or directory closed, after being opened in
	           	read-only mode
	close		file or directory closed, regardless of read/write mode
	open		file or directory opened
	moved_to	file or directory moved to watched directory
	moved_from	file or directory moved from watched directory
	move		file or directory moved to or from watched directory
	create		file or directory created within watched directory
	delete		file or directory deleted within watched directory
	delete_self	file or directory was deleted
	unmount		file system containing file or directory unmounted
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2017/01/31/linux-tip-of-the-day-inotifywait.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2017/01/31/linux-tip-of-the-day-inotifywait.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux_tip_of_the_day</category>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>sys_admin</category>
        
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails New with .</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;rails new . –api –d=mysql –skip-spring –skip-listen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 10:22:28 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/30/rails-new-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/30/rails-new-with.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip of the Day Git Standup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/kamranahmedse/git-standup&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 09:00:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/30/linux-tip-of-the-day-git-standup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/30/linux-tip-of-the-day-git-standup.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip of the Day - git recall</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every so often your boss asks you what you’ve been working on and if you have been all over a code base it can actually be hard to break it down.  The new git recall command actually makes this pretty easy.  This is a new Linux tool I just learned about - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Fakerr/git-recall&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13517486&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install it on Linux as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;npm install –global git-recall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install it on OSX as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;brew install less&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-or- you might need to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;brew install homebrew/dupes/less&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I know you already have less installed on your system.  You need lesskey which git recall relies on but Apple, unhelpfully, &lt;a href=&quot;http://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/27269/is-less1-missing-lesskey-functionality&quot;&gt;did not include&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have lesskey then you need to install git recall itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;npm install –global git-recall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you change into a directory where you’re working on something git, do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;git recall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial view shows you your commits in a recent time frame:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/git_recall1.png&quot; alt=&quot;git_recall_.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can go up and down the list and select a commit that you’re interested in with the arrow keys and enter or j/k and enter.  I had issues with the arrow keys so keep j/k in mind.  Then you’ll see the commit details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/git_recall2.png&quot; alt=&quot;git_recall_.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2017/01/30/linux-tip-of-the-day-git-recall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2017/01/30/linux-tip-of-the-day-git-recall.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux_tip_of_the_day</category>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>20 Days of Zero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This really is about weight loss and I’ll even show much much I lost but I’m looking at this from a startup context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I generally find people’s second act in the startup world far, far more interesting than people’s first act.  By second act, of course, I am referring to when an entrepreneur tries to replicate the lightning in a bottle experience that they initially had when they built a startup.  Second acts seem to almost always be less successful than people’s first act.  Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Hawkins&quot;&gt;Jeff Hawkins&lt;/a&gt; who built Palm and then Handspring into a multi billion success is now working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numenta&quot;&gt;Numenta&lt;/a&gt; software that mimic human memory – and he’s been at it for more than a decade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charles Ferguson who built Vermeer, the original creators of FrontPage, left high tech entirely and is now a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Ferguson_(filmmaker)&quot;&gt;film maker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Andreessen&quot;&gt;Marc Andreessen&lt;/a&gt; who created Netscape then created Opsware and is now a Venture capitalist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_Rose&quot;&gt;Kevin Rose&lt;/a&gt; founded Digg which although it is much forgotten these days was once upon a time beating Reddit in the social space.  He then did Pownce and is now doing an app called Zero for weight loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, dear reader, brings us to Kevin Rose and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kevinrose/introducing-zero-a-new-app-to-help-you-fast-209935e8245d&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/a&gt;.  Zero is a new app for what is termed Intermittent Fasting (IF) which is a technique where you fast for a long stretch of the day on an ongoing basis.  Here’s what the app looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/873/1*C9hnNf_51CYUoTl_MFBeYA.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zero App&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve now been using Zero since 1/7 so I have 20 days on it which I think is enough to make some comments.  On 1/7 I weighed in at 194 which isn’t an all time high for me but does reflect, well, post Christmas and Holiday weight gain.  I certainly wasn’t fat by any means but I felt larger than I wanted to be.  After showing my wife Zero we made the joint decision to go on Zero.  My wife suffers from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coeliac_disease&quot;&gt;Celiac disease&lt;/a&gt; in a fairly bad way and by the after Christmas period she was in pretty much constant stomach pain.  Zero, at the time, seemed like a fairly rational decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my weight metrics, unsophisticated as they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/weight_metrics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;weight_metrics.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This was originally written late last week which is why the day count is slightly different.  I’ve lost about another pound since this was written but it wasn’t worth updating the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started Zero I have lost almost 10 pounds which for a 49 year old man is, I think, fairly good.  The only real goal I had at the start of this was a Gandalf like approach to buying new jeans.  When I found out, post Christmas, that my jeans didn’t fit all that well, I took the position:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Thou Shalt Not Buy Bigger Pants! (Gandalf to a group of fat hobbits)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that no new jeans have been purchased and their fit is much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;adding-whole-30-to-zero&quot;&gt;Adding Whole 30 to Zero&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot say that all of this is tied to Zero.  On 1/15 one of my wife’s good friends, H, convinced her to go on &lt;a href=&quot;http://whole30.com/&quot;&gt;Whole 30&lt;/a&gt; and I came along for the chaos.  Whole30 is one of those diets where you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drink no alcohol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no preservatives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no dairy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no corn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no carbs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eat only things you cook yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eat only meats and vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I cook everything from scratch already this basically amounted to slight modifications to what I already cook.  I’ve never drank so the alcohol restrictions amounted to “don’t put wine in the beef stew made yesterday” and didn’t affect me at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I can’t say that all of this is due to Zero, I think the bulk of the weight loss is attributable to the Zero’s Intermittent Fasting approach.  By reducing the window of time during which you can eat down to say 7 to 8 hours, my wife and I have gone from two large meals (lunch and dinner) generally down to 1 (lunch) and a snack (dinner).  So from a weight loss perspective, I suspect the reduction in overall food volume is a bigger contributor than the foods I’ve taken out of my diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I’ve been fairly pleased with Whole 30 as a approach to food.  My wife’s constant stomach pains are gone so that’s a huge win from my perspective.  That was why I agreed to go on it and it has been a complete success in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the Whole 30  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0544854411?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=whole3009c-20&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0544854411&quot;&gt;cookbook&lt;/a&gt; isn’t all that good.  The recipes fall into that difficult, pretentious category of recipe where my comment would generally be “trying too hard”.  Additionally some of the recipes are flat out either bad or wrong (don’t try to make mayonaise their way; go get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Food-Lab-Cooking-Through-Science/dp/0393081087/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1485516745&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=kenji+lopez+alt&quot;&gt;Kenji’s book&lt;/a&gt;) or follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://thepioneerwoman.com/food-and-friends/how-to-make-mayonnaise/&quot;&gt;the Pioneer Woman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;comments-on-the-zero-app&quot;&gt;Comments on the Zero App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zero app is very much no nonsense – you get a calendar and a few different options for scheduling your fasts and that’s it.  And that’s my biggest problem with it – there’s no way to add your own data to the fast.  I would have very much liked it if say you could attach a picture of each meal you ate to each day.  Or if you could put in a weight metric.  Or if you could put in how you felt.  I’d love to know how many days of Zero it took for my wife to feel better but I have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still Zero led to me losing 10 pounds and that’s nothing to disregard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do get some summary metrics – I can see my average fast time was 16h 49m and that on average I ate for only 6 minutes during the night (I was using the Circadian approach to fasting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-zero&quot;&gt;Getting Zero&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero can be gotten from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zero-fasting-tracker/id1168348542?mt=8&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-whole30&quot;&gt;Getting Whole30&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation would be to just get the baseline &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Whole30-30-Day-Guide-Health-Freedom/dp/0544609719&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; and then ignore their whole philosophy and just focus on the food aspect of it.  Diets, these days, generally seem to be as much guru advice as they are diet and, honestly, I doubt you need a guru.  I know I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero is ridiculously simple to use does make it easy to stick with a fast.  Pairing Zero with Whole30 did seem to produce, at least for me, overall weight loss and, I think, some health gains.  Recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/weight_loss/2017/01/30/20-days-of-zero.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/weight_loss/2017/01/30/20-days-of-zero.html</guid>
        
        <category>diet</category>
        
        <category>weight_loss</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>kevin_rose</category>
        
        
        <category>weight_loss</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip of the Day - Use ncdu for Disc Space Usage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I was to look back over the time I’ve spent doing sys admin work, I would guess that I’ve spent more time singing the song:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Where oh here has my disc space gone, Where oh where could it be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;than anything else.  Managing storage just plain &lt;strong&gt;sucks&lt;/strong&gt;.  And ever since we moved from hard discs to first SSDs and now cloud boxes with 8 gig partitions, well, its a bigger issue than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Linux and OSX tool ncdu actually makes this pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install on Linux it as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install ncdu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install on OSX it as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;brew install ncdu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start it as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ncdu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you will get a character mode interface you can move with the arrow keys to get a better feel for the disc space.  Here are some screen shots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/ncdu1.png&quot; alt=&quot;ncdu1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/ncdu2.png&quot; alt=&quot;ncdu2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/ncdu3.png&quot; alt=&quot;ncdu3.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/ncdu4.png&quot; alt=&quot;ncdu4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 16:01:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-use-ncdu-for-disc-space-usage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-use-ncdu-for-disc-space-usage.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux_tip_of_the_day</category>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>sysadmin</category>
        
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resume Values versus Obituary Values</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 06:16:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/29/resume-values-versus-obituary-values.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/29/resume-values-versus-obituary-values.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip of the Day - ncdu</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 06:09:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-ncdu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-ncdu.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip of the Day - bmon</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 06:09:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-bmon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/01/29/linux-tip-of-the-day-bmon.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
