<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 07:47:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 07:47:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>App Review - Zero by Kevin Rose</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I turn 50 and for the first time in my life my high metabolism is mildly failing me – I’m not fat by any means but like a truck bearing down upon me, I can see a change coming.  And I do not like that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 05:48:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/personal/2017/01/11/a-review-of-zero-by-kevin-rose.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/personal/2017/01/11/a-review-of-zero-by-kevin-rose.html</guid>
        
        <category>celiac</category>
        
        <category>fasting</category>
        
        <category>zero</category>
        
        <category>app_review</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electron Development is Like Mos Eisley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So for my side project there is, for the first time in years, a client side component.  I already have 3 target users in mind and one of them uses Windows exclusively so that rules out any type of Mac development tool.  And because I really do believe that we are now in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/category.html#postmac&quot;&gt;postmac&lt;/a&gt; world, I also need to support Linux.  All of that rolls up into the nigh inescapable conclusion that I’m going to have to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://electron.atom.io/&quot;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt; for development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that the Atom editor and Slack are both based on Electron and run across OSX, Windows and Linux you really can’t argue against Electron at this point.  Atom and Slack are both best of breed applications and my only objection to them is resource usage.  And arguing against resource usage is a sucker’s bet – you always, always, always build for tomorrow’s platform because machines get faster (or at least stay the same) and memory gets larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crying shame of electron development is the abysmal state of documentation and examples.  Honestly it is like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mos_Eisley&quot;&gt;Mos Eisley&lt;/a&gt; – a wretched hive of scum and villainy or really a &lt;strong&gt;wretched hive of things that don’t actually work &lt;em&gt;anymore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  I’ve been working for the past two hours on nothing more than trying to follow top ranked tutorials and the only thing I’ve been able to make is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/HelloWorldElectron01&quot;&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt; app of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core problem here is that the JavaScript / Node world which vomited all this technology onto us is changing more rapidly than anything I’ve seen before.  And when that happens people don’t tend to go back and fix their samples.  And I get it, I really do.  But the taste that it leaves in your developer mind is, well, Mother Johnson told me never to use words like those.  ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my only reliable advice if you’re trying to learn electron is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re trying to learn from a code sample on the net, git clone it to your machine IMMEDIATELY and try and run it with the normal electron . process from the checkout directory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If it dies as seems to be the norm then abort and move on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the dates on sample apps carefully; older then a year and I wouldn’t even try anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personally I learn better from examples and I tend to avoid API documentation.  I think in this case I need to make a beeline for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://electron.atom.io/docs/&quot;&gt;official electron docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The docs are actually very good.  Because I’m trying to make a standard desktop app, I looked at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://electron.atom.io/docs/api/menu/&quot;&gt;Electron Menu&lt;/a&gt; docs and it was very helpful.  Integrating this into an overall app skeleton – not helpful; sigh.  Getting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/34840026&quot;&gt;menu to show up at all&lt;/a&gt; in development – entirely unhelpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/electron/2017/01/11/electron-development-is-like-mos-eisley.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/electron/2017/01/11/electron-development-is-like-mos-eisley.html</guid>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>electron</category>
        
        <category>hyde</category>
        
        
        <category>electron</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating New Rails Projects with RailsApps</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 15:40:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/creating-new-rails-projects-with-railsapps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/creating-new-rails-projects-with-railsapps.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review Git Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;http://www.syntevo.com/smartgit/download?file=smartgit/smartgit-macosx-8_0_3.dmg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git-tower.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git-fork.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gitkraken.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gitup.co&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;github.com/jonas/tig&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 15:11:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/review-git-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/review-git-clients.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Spring is Sprung or when rails g model makes nothing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;sjohnson@FuzzygroupMacbookPro2016:~/me/fuzzygroup/voice_click/voice_click_site$ bundle exec rails g model MailingList
Running via Spring preloader in process 80231
Expected string default value for ‘–jbuilder’; got true (boolean)
      invoke  active_record
      create    db/migrate/20170110073523_create_mailing_lists.rb
      create    app/models/mailing_list.rb
      invoke    rspec
      create      spec/models/mailing_list_spec.rb
      invoke      factory_girl
      create        spec/factories/mailing_lists.rb
sjohnson@FuzzygroupMacbookPro2016:~/me/fuzzygroup/voice_click/voice_click_site$ mate db/migrate/20170110073523_create_mailing_lists.rb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to kill multiple spring processes&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 02:40:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/when-spring-is-sprung-or-when-rails-g-model-makes-nothing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/when-spring-is-sprung-or-when-rails-g-model-makes-nothing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>End of an Era rails db:migrate or a Salute to Jim Weirich</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 06:01:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/09/end-of-an-era-rails-db-migrate-or-a-salute-to-jim-weirich.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/09/end-of-an-era-rails-db-migrate-or-a-salute-to-jim-weirich.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So You Have to Help Your Kid with Algebra</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a great overview of the different &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/710537/31440d3205ea5d83/&quot;&gt;Symbolic Math tools on Linux&lt;/a&gt; and here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13332781&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;integrate(%e^(-x^2), x);

solve(3x+2=10, x);

solve(x^2+2x=5, x);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;brew install homebrew/science/maxima&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://coeurdecode.com/2015/02/27/installing-maxima-on-mac-os-x-2/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wolfram Alpha Pro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of quick maxima tips and examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To quit out just type if it says &lt;strong&gt;ENTER&lt;/strong&gt; then just press the enter key:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;quit(); &lt;strong&gt;ENTER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;brew install homebrew/science/maxima&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;solve(x+3=10, x);&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Maxima can be a tool to check your home work&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 13:05:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/math/2017/01/08/so-you-have-to-help-your-kid-with-algebra.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/math/2017/01/08/so-you-have-to-help-your-kid-with-algebra.html</guid>
        
        <category>math</category>
        
        <category>algebra</category>
        
        
        <category>math</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hyde Feature Overview 01 - Check for Broken Links aka The Nick Feature</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently programming what in my head will always be known as &lt;em&gt;The Nick Feature&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://nickjanetkis.com&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; is a buddy of mine and a regular pair programming partner. Together he and I have wrestled to the ground a number of Ansible powered dragons, dynamically build tens upon hundreds of AWS instances and other various and sundry nerd tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the way that nerds often do, we chat about things as we go about the day and one day he asked me about programmatically checking his blog for broken links.  As questions like this always do, it made me think.  Several hours later I spun up a small test project and starting playing with that in the context of both his blog and mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: His question was specifically about preventing broken links from ever going live in the first place and that’s how this Hyde feature now actually functions.  His specific request drove the development of the jekyll-hyde plugin which enables all Hyde functionality as part of the Jekyll publishing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broken links share a particular fascination for me because in my first hypertext authoring tool, Black Magic, we didn’t allow them.  Our underlying engine made it very, very hard for dangling links to exist.  You could do it but you did it by moving a file outside the environment.  It wasn’t until the world wide web came along that I ran into the problem of broken links in the wild.  And like everyone else in the web tools 1.0 world I solved this problem with perl scripts and other first generation automation tools.  But I haven’t ever forgotten the elegant architecture for broken links that my first partner, Brian Giedt, created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I looked at Nick’s blog and then my own I realized that broken links actually are only really a problem in a certain context. Given that the Internet is constantly changing, broken links are just an inevitability – they will happen.  And, honestly, trying to fix them after a certain point in time is likely not possible.  Additionally things like server side mod_rewrite rules mean that links may break and proper 404s may never be returned to you. Finally just knowing the original destination of a link often is enough.  There is, after all, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archive.org&quot;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if there are contexts where you don’t worry about broken links, is there a context where you &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; worry about them.  The answer is absolutely YES – you worry about broken links when the content item is newly created.  And that’s why one of the very first features I’ve written into Hyde is just that – it takes a newly created post and makes sure that all of the links in it actually exist.  It is executed every time a post changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Nick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;technical-notes&quot;&gt;Technical Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Nick, a very experienced software engineer, was asking me how to tackle this I thought it might be worth discussing how to implement something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;result = HTTPClient.head(“http://www.scripting.com/fooddfdfdfdfd”)
 =&amp;gt; #&amp;lt;HTTP::Message:0x007feaf8454558 @http_header=#&amp;lt;HTTP::Message::Headers:0x007feaf8454508 @http_version=”1.1”, @body_size=0, @chunked=false, @request_method=”HEAD”, @request_uri=#&amp;lt;Addressable::URI:0x3ff57c22aa90 URI:http://www.scripting.com/fooddfdfdfdfd&amp;gt;, @request_query=nil, @request_absolute_uri=nil, @status_code=301, @reason_phrase=”Moved Permanently”, @body_type=nil, @body_charset=nil, @body_date=nil, @body_encoding=nil, @is_request=false, @header_item=[[“x-amz-id-2”, “GzHUJzCkS3rqbqEBuWdGD2V9cApmMZX7SKUV8Xc9WT/ECKz9glwtBpK6x65rnDdsyjqrP1ITrv4=”], [“x-amz-request-id”, “00986197CE6075E4”], [“Date”, “Fri, 06 Jan 2017 09:08:05 GMT”], [“Location”, “http://scripting.com/fooddfdfdfdfd”], [“Content-Length”, “0”], [“Server”, “AmazonS3”]], @dumped=false&amp;gt;, @peer_cert=nil, @http_body=#&amp;lt;HTTP::Message::Body:0x007feaf8454490 @body=””, @size=0, @positions=nil, @chunk_size=nil&amp;gt;, @previous=nil&amp;gt;
2.3.1 :007 &amp;gt; result = HTTPClient.head(“http://www.google.com/fooddfdfdfdfd”)
 =&amp;gt; #&amp;lt;HTTP::Message:0x007feaf842e5b0 @http_header=#&amp;lt;HTTP::Message::Headers:0x007feaf842e560 @http_version=”1.1”, @body_size=0, @chunked=false, @request_method=”HEAD”, @request_uri=#&amp;lt;Addressable::URI:0x3ff57c217bd4 URI:http://www.google.com/fooddfdfdfdfd&amp;gt;, @request_query=nil, @request_absolute_uri=nil, @status_code=404, @reason_phrase=”Not Found”, @body_type=nil, @body_charset=nil, @body_date=nil, @body_encoding=#&lt;Encoding:UTF-8&gt;, @is_request=false, @header_item=[[&quot;Content-Type&quot;, &quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot;], [&quot;Content-Length&quot;, &quot;1574&quot;], [&quot;Date&quot;, &quot;Fri, 06 Jan 2017 09:08:22 GMT&quot;]], @dumped=false&amp;gt;, @peer_cert=nil, @http_body=#&amp;lt;HTTP::Message::Body:0x007feaf842e420 @body=&quot;&quot;, @size=0, @positions=nil, @chunk_size=nil&amp;gt;, @previous=nil&amp;gt;&lt;/Encoding:UTF-8&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 11:53:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/08/hyde-feature-overview-01-check-for-broken-links-aka-the-nick-feature.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2017/01/08/hyde-feature-overview-01-check-for-broken-links-aka-the-nick-feature.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fixing Arrow Key Support in Maxima</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: All of this is tested only on OSX but I suspect the suggestions, slightly adapted, would work on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently started using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://maxima.sourceforge.net&quot;&gt;Maxima&lt;/a&gt; symbolic math tool as a way to help my son with his Algebra I class.  You wouldn’t think a practicing sotware engineer with a background in data science and analytics would have issues helping a teenager with math but when I actually brought his grade &lt;strong&gt;down&lt;/strong&gt; after helping him, I knew I needed some help from technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help on using Maxima then you might want to check my earlier post.  A great guide to installing Maxima on OSX can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://coeurdecode.com/2015/02/27/installing-maxima-on-mac-os-x-2/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first real issue that I found using Maxima was that the &lt;strong&gt;arrow keys didn’t work&lt;/strong&gt;.  Maxima is based on common lisp, specifically the SBCL variant.  Given that I’m from the VI / VIM side of the Internet, I had a feeling that somehow the issue was tied to the underlying lisp / emacs orientation of Maxima.  This is one of those odd things that is actually hard to google for.  I finally found the answer in a post on using Sublime Text with SBCL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One unfortunate aspect of SBCL on OS X is its poor cursor support: you may have noticed that already if you tried to press the left or right arrow keys while using SBCL’s REPL. This can be fixed by installing a readline module. &lt;a href=&quot;https://marktrapp.com/blog/2014/01/20/lisp-with-os-x-sublime-text/&quot;&gt;More…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what to do to make your arrow keys work correctly with Maxima on OSX:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;brew install rlwrap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rlwrap maxima&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step #1 installs the rlwrap utility which wraps the readline library.  Step #2 launches the command line version of maxima but “wrapped by readline” so it knows how to handle You then use it to launch maxima.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note 1&lt;/strong&gt;: This only works with the command line version of maxima.  If you are using the graphical version this won’t work.  But if you are using the graphical version of Maxima, you should really be using wxMaxima and actually have a user interface instead of just Maxima running in what is essentially a shell window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note 2&lt;/strong&gt;: There are some other instructions in the Mark Trapp blog about using linedit and and a .sbclrc file.  I was not able to make those work with Maxima to make any of this more automatic.  My best advice is that if you are using Maxima on OSX and want to avoid the wxMaxima package is to use rlwrap to launch Maxima; that’s what I am doing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 11:50:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/maxima/2017/01/08/fixing-arrow-key-support-in-maxima.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/maxima/2017/01/08/fixing-arrow-key-support-in-maxima.html</guid>
        
        <category>maxima</category>
        
        <category>readline</category>
        
        <category>readlinewrapper</category>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        
        <category>maxima</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings What Piloting Palm Taught Me or Examples of Equity Splits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of the iPhone, it is really, really hard to imagine just how significant Palm used to be.  Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Palm used to sell over a billion dollars worth of organizers annually&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There were multiple compatible versions of the Palm from different companies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both Palm and Handspring, a compatible, went public with multi billion dollar valuations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As late as 2010, HP acquired Palm for 1.2 billion &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palm_(PDA)&quot;&gt;WikiPedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read the book Piloting Palm: The Inside Story of Palm, Handspring and the Birth of the Billion-Dollar Handheld Industry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;![https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51yPty1M7oL._SX311_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg](https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51yPty1M7oL._SX311_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg)&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/Piloting-Palm-Handspring-Billion-Dollar-Handheld/dp/0471089656&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its heart this book is the story of Jeff Hawkins, the inventor of Palm and Donna Dubinsky, the first CEO of Palm.  As Palm grew more successful and Hawkins and Dubinsky’s ambitions grew, they ultimately left and founded the Palm compatible company, Handspring.  If you’ve ever read a startup case study then I doubt this book will surprise you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single best part of this book was that it gave metrics for the equity splits that are common for early stage management positions in startups.  This is something that is always hard to judge so having comparables is really useful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CEO of a spun out company from a larger entity would likely own no more than 1 percent of the company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CEO of an independent startup would generally have 5 percent or more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the former CEO of Palm, Donna Dubinsky, set up a new company, HandSpring, with Jeff Hawkins, the equity split should be 2:1.  The reason was that Dubinsky felt that Hawkins skills to the new company were more essential than her own i.e. Jeff Hawkins couldn’t be replaced but she could be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When Ed Colligan let Palm to join Handspring as VP of Marketing, he received the percentage of company ownership that a startup’s CEO would get rather than the far smaller amount that a VP normally owns.  Given that we know from #2 that a CEO would get 5% then we can guess that a VP of Marketing might get 1% (far smaller).  This is backed up by this result from &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hubspot.com/opinion/how-much-equity-cmo&quot;&gt;the Hubspot blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 07:58:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2017/01/08/startup-learnings-what-piloting-palm-taught-me-or-examples-of-equity-splits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2017/01/08/startup-learnings-what-piloting-palm-taught-me-or-examples-of-equity-splits.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>equity</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
