<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 07:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 07:38:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Silver Searcher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a project die about two months ago and I’ve been involved in a bit of resurrection work recently.  This was related to my comments on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/06/code-rot-is-very-very-real.html&quot;&gt;code rot&lt;/a&gt;.  Happily, with the assistance of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dasari.me&quot;&gt;Dv&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickjanetakis.com&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; for different aspects, we’re once again indexing and functioning correctly.  Today I’m going to talk about a basic search tool, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggreer/the_silver_searcher&quot;&gt;The Silver Searcher&lt;/a&gt;, also known as ag and that’s how I’ll refer to it mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post is written as a basic, example based tutorial since that type of information seems to be entirely missing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://geoff.greer.fm/ag/&quot;&gt;ag’s home page&lt;/a&gt; and github page.  ag is a fantastic tool but its usage isn’t always apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ag, the silver searcher’s command line invocation, is a search tool similar to grep or ack only:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;faster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;able to leap tall buildings in a single bound! (just kidding but it feels that way)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ag is a fantastic tool and its strong enough that I’ve just added it to my standard ansible playbook for all my servers so I will always have it available.  Recommended&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ag can be installed on a mac using homebrew:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install the_silver_searcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or on Ubuntu using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install silversearcher-ag
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ag operates by searching in the current directory and below using a very simple syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ag WHAT_YOU_WANT_TO_FIND
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;replace WHAT_YOU_WANT_TO_FIND with, well, what you’re looking for.  Here’s an example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ag NUM_THREADS=10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case I was struggling to find documentation that I knew I had written down but I had changed boxes, re-organized directories and so on.  By simply opening a Terminal window to my home directory i.e. ~ and then typing ag NUM_THREADS=10 I was able to find all documents containing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-how-ag-operates&quot;&gt;Understanding How ag Operates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search tools tend to be fiddly little beasts at the best of times and if you don’t understand how they work then this tends to rise up and bite you badly.  Here’s what I know about how ag operates and that I took the time to verify:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Searches by default are case insensitive; I got roughly the same results with ag num_threads=10 as I did with ag NUM_THREADS=10; no I don’t understand why I got 76 results with the lower case version and 77 with the upper case but the box I’m searching is a bit wonky so perhaps that’s it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Searches go across directories by default&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 04:39:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/search/2016/12/14/the-silver-searcher.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/search/2016/12/14/the-silver-searcher.html</guid>
        
        <category>search</category>
        
        <category>grep</category>
        
        <category>ack</category>
        
        <category>ag</category>
        
        <category>silver_searcher</category>
        
        
        <category>search</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Just Happened To Your Database In the Past 10 Minutes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I’m rapidly coming to the conclusion that Christmas is the enemy of getting things done.  While I have come up with a lot of potential topics to write about recently I don’t seem to be able to get anything actually finished due to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present Shopping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present Wrapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christmas Events (parties, choir concerts, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christmas Baking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas – at least, as my old boss, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rafer&quot;&gt;Scott Rafer&lt;/a&gt;, used to say – &lt;em&gt;these are high quality problems to have&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick post today – looking at the state of your database.  Let’s say you have a table called posts and it has a field called created_at (the Rails standard way of tracking table changes) and you want to see how many things came into that table in the past 10 minutes.  Here’s the sql you need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT COUNT(*) FROM posts WHERE created_at &amp;gt; DATE_ADD(NOW(),INTERVAL - 10 MINUTE);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I’ve generally looked at tables and then tried to relate what’s going on to the current time and adjust in my head for the server time zone offset.  This is &lt;strong&gt;much, much&lt;/strong&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A really nice side effect of this is that you can simply change the interval quickly and see if your performance is linear or non-linear.  Let’s say you change your interval to 5, 10 and 15 minutes and this was the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [foo_production]&amp;gt; SELECT COUNT(*) FROM posts WHERE created_at &amp;gt; DATE_ADD(NOW(),INTERVAL - 5 MINUTE);
+----------+
| COUNT(*) |
+----------+
|      468 |
+----------+
1 row in set (0.45 sec)

MariaDB [foo_production]&amp;gt; SELECT COUNT(*) FROM posts WHERE created_at &amp;gt; DATE_ADD(NOW(),INTERVAL - 10 MINUTE);
+----------+
| COUNT(*) |
+----------+
|      512 |
+----------+
1 row in set (0.44 sec)

MariaDB [foo_production]&amp;gt; SELECT COUNT(*) FROM posts WHERE created_at &amp;gt; DATE_ADD(NOW(),INTERVAL - 15 MINUTE);
+----------+
| COUNT(*) |
+----------+
|     1312 |
+----------+
1 row in set (0.45 sec)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this illustrates is that while performance was non linear in the 5 to 10 minute range, it became linear again (roughly) at the 15 minute mark.  This is a nice simple way to get a &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; if performance is overall on track.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/mysql/2016/12/14/what-just-happened-to-your-database-in-the-past-10-minutes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/mysql/2016/12/14/what-just-happened-to-your-database-in-the-past-10-minutes.html</guid>
        
        <category>mysql</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>sql</category>
        
        
        <category>mysql</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So You Want to Hire a Freelancer to Be Full Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For most of the past 8 years I’ve been a professional freelancer and it all started with &lt;em&gt;eduFire&lt;/em&gt; where I was VP of Engineering.  When eduFire dissolved in a wash of founder level “oh crap we can’t raise our A round; what do we do; I know – I’ll just quit and start something else”(Note1) I made the choice to become a professional freelancer and I have really enjoyed that decision.  I’ve never made as much money or learned as much as I have since I’ve been a freelancer.  My skills now are better than they ever have been and it is largely from freelancing – more on that in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time clients try, often hard, to hire you full time.  And if you want to hire a freelancer full time then I have one piece of advice for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay the freelancer’s bills promptly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone is a freelancer and they are resistant to taking a full time job, I’d argue that there has to be a reason for it since it is &lt;strong&gt;dramatically harder&lt;/strong&gt; to be a freelancer than a full time employee.  We may all talk a lot about the &lt;em&gt;gig economy&lt;/em&gt; but, in 2016 America, things are still structured against freelancers in every way – insurance, taxes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case I have &lt;strong&gt;trust&lt;/strong&gt; issues.  eduFire shut down 2 weeks before Christmas in 2009 with &lt;em&gt;no notice&lt;/em&gt; and all of us were left high and dry and scrambling for what was next.  And since no one hires in December or even January it meant that everyone was faced at least 2 months of no salary.  I think we all landed on our feet - I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as a client is moderately rational or at least not insane the best impression you can give a freelancer is, well, if you &lt;strong&gt;pay your bills promptly&lt;/strong&gt;.  As long as the freelancer is paid on time, well, we’re generally happy.  And if you want them to join you full time, well, pay your bills on time.  That goes a long, long way towards giving a freelancer the positive feelings you want them to have if you are going to name them a job offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note1: No eduFire wasn’t mine and yes that’s more than a little bit of much deserved bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/hiring/2016/12/14/so-you-want-to-hire-a-freelancer-to-be-full-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/hiring/2016/12/14/so-you-want-to-hire-a-freelancer-to-be-full-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>hr</category>
        
        <category>hiring</category>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>freelance</category>
        
        <category>gig</category>
        
        
        <category>hiring</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recent PostMac Notes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some recent things in the Post Mac category:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mondaynote.com/macbook-pro-launch-perplexing-b47003037b2e#.88txiffc1&quot;&gt;Jean Louis Gassee returned his New MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; and called the launch &lt;strong&gt;perplexing&lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13162310&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2016/12/13/why-apple-is-removing-time-remaining-battery-life-estimates-macbook-pro/&quot;&gt;Apple is removing battery life estimates from the MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/dec/12/apple-macbook-pro-review-the-best-computer-you-shouldnt-buy&quot;&gt;The Guardian calls the next MacBook Pro the Best Computer You Shouldn’t Buy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=macbook%20pro&amp;amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;dateRange=pastWeek&amp;amp;type=story&quot;&gt;Hacker News search on recent MacBook articles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note that I am basically happy with my MacBook Pro 13” but I bought the previous generation so it is much, much older than the current.  And my wife absolutely adores here brand new MacBook (but not the pro).  Her only real objection is having to use a dongle to print on our old Brother laser printer but she’s back in graduate school now and very, very happy with the weight and size of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/12/14/recent-postmac-notes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/12/14/recent-postmac-notes.html</guid>
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Considering Phabricator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I ran across &lt;a href=&quot;https://phacility.com/phabricator/&quot;&gt;phabricator&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://phacility.com&quot;&gt;phacility&lt;/a&gt; recently and I’m intrigued.  I also had a horrific out of the box experience trying it out that I thought nicely illustrated a number of what I consider straight up fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phabricator is a multi author code review and management tool that was originally built at Facebook and is now a hosted open source product.  They describe it as: &lt;em&gt;Discuss. Plan. Code. Review. Test. - Every application your project needs, all in one tool.&lt;/em&gt; and I think that’s a fairly solid overview.  They also have a hell of a great sense of humor and if you haven’t read this &lt;a href=&quot;https://phacility.com/phabricator/&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; then you should go there now and search for either intern or purple.  +10 for the sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went to phacility and chose to set up a hosted instance in order to evaluate it.  Here’s my sad, short, less than sweet experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://secure.phabricator.com/book/phabricator/article/diffusion_existing/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 15:50:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/phabricator/2016/12/13/considering-phabricator.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/phabricator/2016/12/13/considering-phabricator.html</guid>
        
        <category>phabricator</category>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        
        <category>phabricator</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multi Cooking Is A Thing And Here's How To Do It</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 05:22:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/11/multi-cooking-is-a-thing-and-here-s-how-to-do-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/11/multi-cooking-is-a-thing-and-here-s-how-to-do-it.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple MacBook Pro Alternatives</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I’m certainly not the only one who is curious about life beyond the Macbook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/broken-window/my-search-for-a-macbook-pro-alternative-e549ea2b2dee#.j80auzeup&quot;&gt;Medium Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13142754&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly he didn’t even mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://system76.com/&quot;&gt;System 76&lt;/a&gt; which makes native Ubuntu laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/12/10/apple-macbook-pro-alternatives.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/12/10/apple-macbook-pro-alternatives.html</guid>
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Tutorial - Using Squid, EC2 and ELB to Defeat Crawling Blockages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I write crawlers.  I have crawlers for years.  And I &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; beyond &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; when companies throw up roadblocks to defeat crawlers.  As a general rule of thumb the big Internet companies tend to be the worst at this – they, who shall be unnamed, love information to be “free” but they hate like hell to themselves be indexed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, in the age of the cloud, crawling blockages can be really, really easy to defeat.  In this tutorial I’m going to show you how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;proxying&quot;&gt;Proxying&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core technology to defeat blockages is simple – you use a proxy server.  Let’s say that you have a server on this ip address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;24.36.48.19
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone wants to block your crawler all they need to do is place a block on that ip address by any number of means - code, router level, firewall level, etc and your code can’t actually access the data.  A proxy server sits in between your code and the data you want to access.  Here’s a ruby example using Mechanize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;agent = Mechanize.new
url = &quot;http://www.google.com/&quot;
proxy_server_url = &quot;proxy.foo.com&quot;
proxy_server_port = 3199    
agent.set_proxy(proxy_server_url, proxy_server_port)
page = agent.get(url)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That will cause the request to be through the proxy server and NOT from your actual server.  Given that a proxy server can be blocked as easily as your actual server this may not seem all that significant – but think of this in terms of a cloud computing environment like AWS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In aws you can create instances trivially with tools like ansible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In aws you can automatically / automagically install a full featured proxy server like squid with one command&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In aws you can front end a cluster of proxy server instances behind an elastic load balancer allowing your software to simply access the load balancer and then the proxy servers can be dynamically replaced either when they are blocked or perhaps proactively every single day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;squid&quot;&gt;Squid&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squid is the proxy server we’re going to be using.  Squid is an old school Internet tool – I remember experimenting with it back in maybe 2002 although that seems impossible but it actually isn’t since it is cited in papers going back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Squid_(software)&quot;&gt;1995&lt;/a&gt;.  We’re going to need to use the 3.5 or later version of Squid since we need support for what is called ProxyPass which is what lets a proxy transaction travel through a load balancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re uncertain about the installed version of Squid then run this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/usr/sbin/squid -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mamchenkov.net/wordpress/2004/03/23/how-to-check-squid-proxy-server-version-on-a-linux-system/&quot;&gt;Mamchenkov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Troubleshooting an ELB in Front of an EC2 Running Squid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the proxy programmatically using proxy protocoal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Squid has to be 3.5 or later&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure that the ec2 has the proxy port open in its security group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ec2 has a sec group
lb has a security group&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;make sure the ports are sync’d&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;architecture&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to need the following architecture bits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an elastic load balancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 or more EC2 instances that run squid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ansibling-this-all-together&quot;&gt;Ansibling This All Together&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;be-careful---bandwidth-bills-are-real&quot;&gt;Be Careful - Bandwidth Bills Are Real&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 09:58:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/08/aws-tutorial-using-squid-ec2-and-elb-to-defeat-crawling-blockages.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/08/aws-tutorial-using-squid-ec2-and-elb-to-defeat-crawling-blockages.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails Commando - Parachuting into a Rails Code Base and Adding Value from Day 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2009, 2 weeks before Christmas, with no notice, I and the rest of the eduFire startup were laid off with no notice, no severance and no benefits save, I believe, some small level of legally required COBRA.  My role was VP of Engineering and I held stock options on 10% of the company.  It was a mind-blowing level of &lt;strong&gt;suck&lt;/strong&gt; and one that I doubt I’ll ever forgive the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonbischke&quot;&gt;founder&lt;/a&gt; for – classless in every single way.  I think it was also the last time I’ve trusted an organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m a firm believer that there are good times and there are bad and while 2009 was the heights of suck, it launched me down the path of “make lots and lots of money from consulting” and that’s been fantastic for me.  In particular I’ve become more than a bit of what I refer to as a &lt;em&gt;rails commando&lt;/em&gt; – I can drop into a Rails code base and add value from Day 1.  This blog post talks about how I go about that.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 05:55:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/07/rails-commando-parachuting-into-a-rails-code-base-and-adding-value-from-day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/07/rails-commando-parachuting-into-a-rails-code-base-and-adding-value-from-day-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>eduFire</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Incredible Smartness of Bezos or A New Revenue Stream for Amazon with Amazon Go</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I made a full commitment this past summer to AWS, I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Everything-Store-Jeff-Bezos-Amazon/dp/0316219282/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1481104973&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=The+Everything+Store&quot;&gt;The Everything Store&lt;/a&gt; which is a detailed analysis of how Amazon operates and Jeff Bezos personally.  As someone who has been an entrepreneur on many different occasions, I find this type of book particularly compelling and this particular book was no exception.  What I walked away from the book were these observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeff Bezos is at the essential core of Amazon’s success; yes there are many other talented executives but at its heart it is Jeff’s place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeff Bezos is a once in a century type businessman and if I don’t think of in the same light as Gates, Rockefeller and Carnegie then I’m making a massive mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is far, far smarter for me to commit to AWS than it is for me to fight AWS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, dear reader, is why I went full scale with AWS.  Yes there were &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws.html&quot;&gt;technical reasons&lt;/a&gt; as well but at its heart it was a bet on Bezos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-this-categorized-as-startup&quot;&gt;What is this Categorized as Startup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Amazon is literally a globe spanning entity with aggregate revenues north of 100 billion, you may find it odd that my primary category for this piece is startup.  Well Amazon, at least to me, just plain acts like a startup.  The level of innovation that the company consistently delivers is breath taking.  I mean what other big company launches new things at the pace that Amazon does?  Honestly Amazon is a startup at least in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;amazon-go&quot;&gt;Amazon Go&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I come to yesterday’s announcement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/b?node=16008589011#&quot;&gt;Amazon Go&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13105689&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;, a complete re-thinking of grocery stores.  Amazon has announced that they will be building 2,000 local grocery stores which are basically a complete rethinking of the grocery store concept implemented along the lines of a convenience store.  Particularly interesting to me since I grew up working retail were these ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no cashier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wave your phone when you enter to authenticate yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shop by putting items in your basket; take whatever you want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;amazon figures out what you bought and automatically charges your credit card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think about all the various services that Amazon offers through AWS this is a clear implementation of those services applied to the physical world.  In specific I’d place a good bet that this will be powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2016/09/introducing-amazon-ec2-p2-instances-the-largest-gpu-powered-virtual-machine-in-the-cloud/&quot;&gt;GPU instances&lt;/a&gt; using some kind of machine vision API that you’ll see announced next year at the next Amazon developer conference. And I’d be surprised if we don’t see the store proactively reaching out to people’s phones using the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lex/&quot;&gt;Amazon Lex&lt;/a&gt; ChatBot tool to say something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I see that you picked up and put down three different types of red meat.  In case it helps make your buying decision we have a 10% instant coupon on any type of red meat you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this would be dynamically coupled with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/&quot;&gt;Amazon Redshift&lt;/a&gt; warehouse analysis of inventory trends and if meat is going to spoil or not.  Amazon could entirely automate what a talented meat department manager does for a grocery store only better because the special is dynamically delivered to customers who are much more likely to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-new-revenue-stream-for-amazon&quot;&gt;A New Revenue Stream for Amazon&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new revenue stream that I see coming out of this is consumer marketing data.  My strong guess is that Amazon will be able to roll up data from actions like pick up and put down on an individual consumer level and then see that type of analytics back to consumer goods firms.  Now I’m sure that Amazon already licenses some consumer marketing data to companies but I suspect this is going to be fairly unprecedented.  Let’s say that you are a consumer goods company that just rolled out a new label.  Here’s what I can envision happening:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New label rolls out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon is able to give you time adjusted comparisons of shopping experiences before and after along with being able to watch the consumers interact with the product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think of this as a/b analytics for the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt there’s a single person reading this who, whether or not they believe in a/b testing, doesn’t understand the power it offers.  Personally I’m not a fan but as a marketer I can see this being truly compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-wifes-reaction&quot;&gt;My Wife’s Reaction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife isn’t part of the high tech world anymore but she had an interesting reaction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All restaurants are going to be Taco Bell!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Props to her for an outstanding nerd culture reference, the 1993 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106697/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;Demolition Man&lt;/a&gt; movie starring Stallone, Bullock and Snipes of a dystopian future where literally all restaurants are Taco Bell.  Perhaps all commerce will be Amazon…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/12/07/the-incredible-smartness-of-bezos-or-a-new-revenue-stream-for-amazon-with-amazon-go.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/12/07/the-incredible-smartness-of-bezos-or-a-new-revenue-stream-for-amazon-with-amazon-go.html</guid>
        
        <category>amazon</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>bezos</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
