<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc / Hyde.
</description>
    <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 05:46:51 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 05:46:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Game Nanny Story Or When Life Gives You Lemons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have built a lot of products in my career:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;search engines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blogging tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;podcasting tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;online learning systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hypertext authoring tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;email marketing aka spamming tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even a web UI to calculate radiation doses for prostate cancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the one thing that I’ve stayed resolutely way from is &lt;em&gt;gaming&lt;/em&gt;.  And, despite that, three days ago, I launched a product named &lt;strong&gt;Game Nanny&lt;/strong&gt; so what happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short answer is &lt;strong&gt;life happened&lt;/strong&gt; or as I refer to it with my wife, &lt;em&gt;When Life Gives You Lemons&lt;/em&gt;.  Here’s a snippet from the home page that tells the tale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 50px; margin-right: 50px; background-color: #f6f8fa; padding: 16px;overflow: auto;font-size: 85%;line-height: 1.45;background-color: #f6f8fa;border-radius: 3px;&quot;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Scott and I'm a parent, I bet a lot like you. I recently discovered that one of my children has been using my credit card to purchase things in the XBox store -- a lot of things. That $347.82 bill I mentioned above, well, that's true -- and it was just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm also a software developer and I'll admit that while I realized immediately that I had a parenting problem, this was also an opportunity -- and the very next morning I started building Game Nanny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As parents, even if we don't like video games, we should admit that our kids love them -- but they can be addictive and lead to crazy bad behavior. I'm not the first parent to be surprised by his kid's gaming spending and I won't be the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Game Nanny to take control of your kid's XBox bad habits. Don't be surprised again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the honest to god truth as how Game Nanny came into being.  To summarize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I saw my kid had made a mistake (and, yes, a big one)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I realized that this wasn’t just a parenting problem, that it was an opportunity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That realization took about all of a minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After that first minute, I had a pretty good idea of what the product was&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two weeks later I had a functional product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line for anyone that either perceives themself to be an entrepreneur or wants to be is that when life gives you a problem, you can look at as just that.  Or you can look at your problem as “Is there an opportunity here?” and then, if you think the answer is “Yes” then build a business around it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/startup/2017/10/06/the-game-nanny-story-or-when-life-gives-you-lemons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/startup/2017/10/06/the-game-nanny-story-or-when-life-gives-you-lemons.html</guid>
        
        <category>game_nanny</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self Hosting a Jekyll Site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a blogger since 2002 and over the years there have been a lot of different blogging tools: Radio, WordPress, Serendipity, Movable Type, TypePad, b2, etc.  After a long, on and off hiatus, I made the decision in 2016 to get serious about blogging again and at that point I committed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.  The reason was really the simplicity of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having all my blog posts in a filesystem, not a database, was a transformative and wonderful experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being able to use my coding editor to jot down a simple blog post was a big, big deal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having all my blog posts run thru github, a tool I use not just daily but generally hourly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ease of use of Github Pages which magically hosts a blog for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, for the past almost 2 years, this has been a great decision.  My blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/blog/&quot;&gt;FuzzyBlog&lt;/a&gt;, has been an essential tool for writing and just personal documentation.  Basically whenever I have to learn something, I try and write it down and that’s a model which works great for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently needed, however, to make a product specific blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.gamenanny.io&quot;&gt;blog.gamenanny.io&lt;/a&gt;, for my new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamenanny.io/&quot;&gt;Game Nanny&lt;/a&gt; product and I discovered that I just couldn’t use Github Pages for this at all.  Github Pages creates a single blog tied to your github username and, well, I only have one github username.  This meant that I had to get into self hosting my Jekyll blog or changing from Jekyll to something else.  I chose the self hosting route and there in lies a how to tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Like most things on the Internet, there must be a way around this limitation but I haven’t found it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/stevegrossi&quot;&gt;Steve Grossi&lt;/a&gt; told me that you can get around this apparent &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/user-organization-and-project-pages/&quot;&gt;Github limitation&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not entirely certain that I understand it but I’m glad to have it as an option. Thx Steve!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understanding-jekylls-output&quot;&gt;Understanding Jekyll’s Output&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key thing to understand about Jekyll is that, at its heart, it is a static site generator.  What this means is that when you type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;jekyll build&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it creates a set of static files that represent your site based on the markdown documents in _posts and your _config.yml configuration file.  Self hosting a Jekyll site basically amounts to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating a jekyll site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating content in that Jekyll site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running jekyll build or jekyll serve to create the static site files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting the files in _site to a public server (rsync).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a web server on a public box that can serve the files generated by Jekyll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of this blog post walks you through all these steps.  I’m a big, big believer in AWS so that’s what I used but any public web host will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-a-jekyll-site&quot;&gt;Creating a Jekyll Site&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be done with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;jekyll new site_name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;jekyll new game_nanny_blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to cover Jekyll details like theme configuration much although I have a set of references at the end.  Jekyll theme configuration is to me, well, a &lt;strong&gt;black art&lt;/strong&gt; that best resembles a &lt;em&gt;pagan ritual&lt;/em&gt; (do it at in the dark of night, naked, chanting and so on).  I just use the default minima theme and generally hope I can get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic configuration can be done by modifying _config.yml in your Jekyll root directory.  Advanced configuration, well, it can be tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;configuring-your-server&quot;&gt;Configuring Your Server&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to self host a jekyll blog is a dead simple web server like Nginx.  Although I’ve mostly been doing Docker for executable software for sometime now, it just felt simpler to go old school on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install nginx with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install nginx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may need to edit the main configuration file with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo vi /etc/nginx/nginx.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the defaults are pretty basic but your details may vary.  And you’d also need to create a config file specifically for your main blog with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo vi /etc/nginx/conf.d/blog.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I have in my blog.conf file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;server {
  listen 3301;
  server_name blog.gamenanny.io;
  root /home/ubuntu/gamenannyblog/_site;

  expires 30s;
  add_header Cache-Control public;
  add_header ETag &quot;&quot;;

  error_page 404 /404.html;
  error_page 500 /500.html;

  location  ~ ^/assets/ {
    expires max;
  }

  location ~ /\. {
    return 404;
    access_log off;
    log_not_found off;
  }

  location = /favicon.ico {
    try_files /favicon.ico =204;
    access_log off;
    log_not_found off;
  }

  location / {
    try_files $uri $uri.html $uri/ =404;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main changes that I made in blog.conf are these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;listen 3301;
server_name blog.gamenanny.io;
root /home/ubuntu/gamenannyblog/_site;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these is explained as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listen 3301;&lt;/strong&gt; The reason for that is that I have multiple sites on this one AWS instance and my AWS Elastic Load Balancer will be responsible for translation data on port 3301 to an port 80 request on blog.gamenanny.io.  I use a standard set of port mappings on everything I build (*00 is always the main site, *01 is always the blog, *05 is always the ecommerce)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;server_name server_name blog.gamenanny.io;&lt;/strong&gt; This configures the site’s domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;root /home/ubuntu/gamenannyblog/_site;&lt;/strong&gt; This sets the root directory to serve the site’s data from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aws-specifics&quot;&gt;AWS Specifics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m deploying to a basic AWS EC2 instance and here is a quick overview of what I needed to do.  Please note that these are the very broad strokes as I was quite rushed when I did it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add blog.gamenanny.io to my Route 53 domain settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a target group to the ELB for the blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a listener rule to the ELB for the blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect the listener rule to the target group.  Until you do this there will be a 503 error and that’s what always reminds me to couple the two.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a directory on your file system where the content can reside.  I did this with:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;mkdir /home/ubuntu/gamenannyblog/_site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The _site corresponds to Jekyll’s _site directory where it generates all data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;deployment&quot;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to handle deployment, I wrote a small shell script. deploy3.sh, which invokes jekyll build and then rsync’s the content to the server.  I’ve now spent almost two years using Jekyll with Github pages and my one comment about the git push to get my content live is that &lt;strong&gt;it is slow&lt;/strong&gt;.  I was absolutely shocked just how fast invoking jekyll build and then rsync was.  Here’s my deploy3.sh script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;JEKYLL_ENV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;production bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exec &lt;/span&gt;jekyll build
rsync -avr --rsh&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'ssh'&lt;/span&gt; --delete-after --delete-excluded _site/ ubuntu@52.14.179.50:/home/ubuntu/gamenannyblog/_site
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This level of speed is just plain awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually the first time I’ve ever successfully used Nginx; previously I was a straight up, old school Apache guy.  My buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickjanetakis.com&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; did my Nginx configuration in about 2 shakes of time (read that as “really, really, really quick”).  Thanks Nick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;see-also&quot;&gt;See Also&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nginx.com/resources/wiki/&quot;&gt;Nginx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/minima&quot;&gt;Customizing Minima&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/themes/&quot;&gt;Customizing Jekyll Themes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/deployment-methods/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vitalyrepin/vrepinblog/blob/master/transfer.sh&quot;&gt;Jekyll RSync Example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sgeos.github.io/jekyll/disqus/2016/02/14/adding-disqus-to-a-jekyll-blog.html&quot;&gt;Adding Disqus to Your Jekyll Blog&lt;/a&gt; Disclaimer - this was a total fail for me and I found the documentation horrid but Disqus has always failed for me so perhaps it is just me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jekyll/2017/10/06/self-hosting-a-jekyll-site.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jekyll/2017/10/06/self-hosting-a-jekyll-site.html</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Chrome Driver with Docker, Rails and Selenium on AWS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a lot of crawling in my professional career and I mean a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt;.  The recent trend towards JavaScript based sites, however, has wreaked havoc on my traditional approach of low level html parsing.  For a new product I’m launching, I recently had to make the switch to using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SeleniumHQ/&quot;&gt;Selenium&lt;/a&gt; for crawling.  Selenium, commonly known as a testing tool, can be used in an embedded fashion where you use code like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;browser = Selenium::WebDriver.for :chrome
browser.get &quot;https://www.google.com&quot;
html = browser.page_source
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a rough equivalent in Mechanize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;agent = Mechanize.new
page = agent.get(&quot;https://www.google.com&quot;)
html = page.body
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the lines of code look similar to something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sparklemotion/mechanize&quot;&gt;Mechanize&lt;/a&gt; this is actually an entirely different approach because underneath it all is a full browser including JavaScript which lets something like a page which sends its data down in a JavaScript array and then uses JavaScript to display it actually render and return back to you parseable html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;doing-this-server-side&quot;&gt;Doing this Server Side&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to use Selenium for a server side crawling process then what you actually needs is called ChromeDriver which is the embedded chrome executable that represents a browser.  One approach is to locally install ChromeDriver on each of your compute nodes but the better approach is to Dockerize everything and run ChromeDriver as a container.  Here are the steps to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;add-chromedriver-to-your-docker-compose-file&quot;&gt;Add ChromeDriver to Your Docker Compose File&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll likely need to implement both Step 1 and Step 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1&quot;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you’ll need for docker-compose.yml or docker-compose.production.yml:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chromedriver:
  image: 'robcherry/docker-chromedriver'
  ports: 
    - 4444:4444
  restart: on-failure
  shm_size: 1G    
  environment:
    - CHROMEDRIVER_WHITELISTED_IPS=&quot;&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2&quot;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A docker container is dramatically lighter than a full computer and you’ll find that Chrome will start.  The specific error you are likely to hit is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Selenium::WebDriver::Error::UnknownError: unknown error: Chrome failed to start: crashed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you discover this you need to change your daemon.json file (normally located in /etc/docker/daemon.json) to have a larger shm_size like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat daemon.json
{
  &quot;default-shm-size&quot;:&quot;2g&quot;,
  &quot;storage-driver&quot;: &quot;overlay2&quot;,
  &quot;log-driver&quot;: &quot;json-file&quot;,
  &quot;log-opts&quot;: {
    &quot;max-size&quot;: &quot;10m&quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I’m aware that I use 1G in the first example and 2g in the second.  This is how I currently have it working and I’m leaving it alone until I play with it more.  I suspect you could sync these but I don’t know that definitively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3&quot;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next error you are likely to hit is one of these two, possibly both:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Net::ReadTimeout during browser launch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UnknownError: session deleted because of page crash from tab crashed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to each of these is how you invoke the core browser object.  Here’s what I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;browser = Selenium::WebDriver.for :chrome, url: &quot;http://chromedriver:4444&quot;, :prefs =&amp;gt; {:password_manager_enable =&amp;gt; false, :credentials_enable_service =&amp;gt; false}, :switches =&amp;gt; [&quot;disable-infobars&quot;, &quot;no-sandbox&quot;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;security-issues&quot;&gt;Security Issues&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an interesting security note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: ChromeDriver restricts access to local connections by default. To allow external connections, you can pass in a custom CHROMEDRIVER_WHITELISTED_IPS environment variable. By default, this is set to 127.0.0.1, but this can by any comma separated list of IP addresses. Setting the value as empty will allow all remote connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS security groups really save you on this one.  By setting CHROMEDRIVER_WHITELISTED_IPS=””, I am able to use ChromeDriver from any other container but nothing else can execute them.  An embedded browser like Selenium is akin to an open proxy so you do not want that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/r/robcherry/docker-chromedriver/&quot;&gt;Docker Chrome Driver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SeleniumHQ/selenium/wiki/Ruby-Bindings&quot;&gt;Ruby and Selenium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/ziadoz/3e8ab7e944d02fe872c3454d17af31a5&quot;&gt;Installing Chrome Driver Locally on Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SeleniumHQ/docker-selenium/issues/198&quot;&gt;Net::ReadTimeout during browser launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://intoli.com/blog/running-selenium-with-headless-chrome/&quot;&gt;Running Selenium on Headless Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/run/#ipc-settings-ipc&quot;&gt;Setting Docker Shm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elgalu/docker-selenium&quot;&gt;Docker and Selenium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zalando/zalenium#run-it&quot;&gt;Zalenium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elgalu/docker-selenium/issues/20#issuecomment-133011186&quot;&gt;Docker and Selenium and Shm / Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos and thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickjanetakis.com/&quot;&gt;Nick my Docker buddy&lt;/a&gt;.  He teaches Docker professionally and really knows his stuff.  I probably could have slogged through this but his help turned what would have been a man day into a quick one hour pairing session.  Appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/docker/2017/09/30/using-chrome-driver-with-docker-rails-and-selenium-on-aws.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/docker/2017/09/30/using-chrome-driver-with-docker-rails-and-selenium-on-aws.html</guid>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>selenium</category>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating an HTTPS Site on AWS with a .IO Domain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently registered my first .io domain using an all AWS stack (Route 53, EC2, Elastic Load Balancer or ELB, Amazon Certificate Manager or ACM) and I found the process mildly odd – to the degree that I know that it will either bite me again or it will bite someone else.  Either way I thought that it would be best to fully document the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site I’m building has login and as such https is important for this site.  Although I could have used &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/lets-encrypt-vs-cloudflare-for-https&quot;&gt;Let’s Encrypt or CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt; for the https, if you’re using https on AWS then there’s a good chance that you are using an ELB and ACM as they make SSL brilliantly simple.  In all my years of deploying SSL, it has never been as simple as using this AWS stack and I sincerely recommend it.  The oddness occurred when I had to bind the .io domain into the certificate itself.  This process requires an email authentication to the owner of the domain to ensure that no one compromised your AWS credentials.  When you are using a normal .com or .net domain and you do this, Amazon sends the email to the email address on the domain registration itself, easy peasy.  When you are using a .io account, the email is NOT sent to the email address on the domain registration but it is instead sent to all of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;administrator@your_domain.io&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hostmaster@your_domain.io&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;postmaster@your_domain.io&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;webmaster@your_domain.io&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;admin@your_domain.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Amazon’s credit, they do kind of disclose this in the ACM documentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/acm/latest/userguide/troubleshoot-iodomains.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s the relevant passage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ACM does, however, send validation email to the following five common system addresses where your_domain is the domain name you entered when you initially requested a certificate and .io is the top level domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(see above)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To receive validation mail for an .IO domain, make sure that you have one of the preceding five email accounts enabled. If you do not, you will not receive validation email and you will not be issued an ACM certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that like a lot of us, probably most of us, I don’t have a mail server running on my .io domain so there’s nothing to receive the email (so I can respond to it).  Now I could have set up a mail server but a much, much easier approach is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://improvmx.com/&quot;&gt;ImprovMX&lt;/a&gt; which promises “Free painless email forwarding for your domains” and it really, really delivers.  Within only a few minutes, I had my ACM mailing and I was off to the races.  With any luck, I will even launch my new site later this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ImprovMX is strongly, strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I resolved this with my favorite pairing buddy, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickjanetakis.com&quot;&gt;Nick Janetakis&lt;/a&gt;.  He does Docker stuff and is very, very talented.  He is also a Let’s Encrypt expert.  Recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/aws/2017/09/30/creating-an-https-site-on-aws-with-a-io-domain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/aws/2017/09/30/creating-an-https-site-on-aws-with-a-io-domain.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>io</category>
        
        <category>https</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails, AuthLogic, CSRF, 422 and session_store.rb</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you’re a professional developer, you come to recognize a category of problems that I refer to as “Pair Programming Required”.  These are those mysterious failures where you know damn well that something should work but &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; and I repeat &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; works.  In this situation, you really want to bring another set of eyes to bear on the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the process of bringing a new Rails powered application online and I discovered around 3:53 am this morning that login, which works perfectly in development, completely fails in production with the wonderfully helpful error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rails 5 ActionController::InvalidAuthenticityToken error&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I dug into it, I saw that was a CSRF error and, oddly, I was getting a 422 error message returned to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mystery of all this was that this wasn’t new login code – it was code that I’ve been using in another application for months and it has been flawless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are just a few of the things that I tried to address this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Switch from Rails 5.1.x back to 5.0.x&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigate the prepend: true approach to protect_from_forgery (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stackoverflow.com/questions/38331496&quot;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewrite most of application_controller.rb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massively hack around in the guts of AuthLogic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run production locally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;change, deploy, test, change again, Lather, Rinse Repeat N times where N is &amp;gt; 10 and less than 50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I exhausted all these possibilities, I reached out to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickjanetakis.com/&quot;&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; and he and I paired on it.  And that’s where the power of pair programming really illustrated itself.  We fairly quickly discovered that the issue was that session_store.rb didn’t match the production domain.  I find it unbelievable that the error message wasn’t actually useful but since I’ve been guilty of that sin more than a few times, well, karma I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documented here for the next time that I hit this (in the spirit of being a good Internet citizen, I did add it to the Stack Overflow as well).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/09/25/rails-authlogic-csrf-422-and-session-store-rb.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/09/25/rails-authlogic-csrf-422-and-session-store-rb.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>authlogic</category>
        
        <category>csrf</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Docker Won't Install Libxml</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most vexing situations in any type of development is when something that you swear you’ve done literally hundreds of times fails to work – at all.  It always turns out to be that what you’re doing is 99.995% the same as something previous – and .005% different.  Last night I went to do a docker-compose build on a new application using my standard stack of Ruby, Rails, Mechanize and the like and I got this, well, crap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[24/1918]
Gem::Ext::BuildError: ERROR: Failed to build gem native extension.

   current directory: /usr/local/bundle/gems/libxml-ruby-3.0.0/ext/libxml
/usr/local/bin/ruby -r ./siteconf20170920-5-mpa6ar.rb extconf.rb
checking for libxml/xmlversion.h in
/opt/include/libxml2,/opt/local/include/libxml2,/usr/local/include/libxml2,/usr/include/libxml2...
no
*** extconf.rb failed ***
Could not create Makefile due to some reason, probably lack of necessary
libraries and/or headers.  Check the mkmf.log file for more details.  You may
need configuration options.

Provided configuration options:
       --with-opt-dir
       --without-opt-dir
       --with-opt-include
       --without-opt-include=${opt-dir}/include
       --with-opt-lib
       --without-opt-lib=${opt-dir}/lib
       --with-make-prog
       --without-make-prog
       --srcdir=.
       --curdir
       --ruby=/usr/local/bin/$(RUBY_BASE_NAME)
       --with-xml2-config
       --without-xml2-config
       --with-xml2-dir
       --without-xml2-dir
       --with-xml2-include
       --without-xml2-include=${xml2-dir}/include
       --with-xml2-lib
       --without-xml2-lib=${xml2-dir}/lib
extconf failure: need libxml2.

   Install the library or try one of the following options to extconf.rb:

     --with-xml2-config=/path/to/xml2-config
     --with-xml2-dir=/path/to/libxml2
     --with-xml2-lib=/path/to/libxml2/lib
     --with-xml2-include=/path/to/libxml2/include


To see why this extension failed to compile, please check the mkmf.log which can
be found here:

/usr/local/bundle/extensions/x86_64-linux/2.3.0-static/libxml-ruby-3.0.0/mkmf.log
I can't get to the mkmf.log file since that's I think done with a container since its clearly linux not osx.
No clue why this is happening since I use this same damn gem everwhere
There was also this info

Gem files will remain installed in /usr/local/bundle/gems/libxml-ruby-3.0.0 for
inspection.
Results logged to
/usr/local/bundle/extensions/x86_64-linux/2.3.0-static/libxml-ruby-3.0.0/gem_make.out

An error occurred while installing libxml-ruby (3.0.0), and Bundler cannot
continue.
Make sure that `gem install libxml-ruby -v '3.0.0'` succeeds before bundling.
ERROR: Service 'web' failed to build: The command '/bin/sh -c bundle install --binstubs' returned a non-zero code: 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major reasons I got into Docker in the first place was to get away from this kind of crap!  Gem builds, particularly where libxml is involved, well, suck.  I spent close to two hours last night tweaking things, updating libraries and such and it was a complete and utter failure.  I even installed Docker on a brand new dev machine and got the exact same result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I revisited it using the Google query &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=docker+won%27t+install+libxml&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&quot;&gt;docker won’t install libxml&lt;/a&gt; and found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/docker-library/php/issues/315&quot;&gt;Github Issue&lt;/a&gt; where they suggest adding libxml2-dev to your Dockerfile.  Thus this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;RUN apk update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apk add build-base nodejs mariadb-dev tzdata git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;becomes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;RUN apk update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apk add build-base nodejs mariadb-dev tzdata git libxml2-dev&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was hugely surprising to me because according to github, I haven’t touched my Dockerfile in &lt;strong&gt;4 months&lt;/strong&gt; ever since my &lt;a href=&quot;https://diveintodocker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker buddy and guru, Nick&lt;/a&gt;, helped me set it up.  My docker-compose file, however, was just modified 22 days ago. As docker-compose has become ever more important in the Docker world, the basic Dockerfile is something you touch less and less – apparently until something bites you in the proverbial arse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;and-heres-why-this-happened&quot;&gt;And Here’s Why this Happened&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My normal use of libxml, for the past decade or so, is always tied straight to Ruby’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sparklemotion/mechanize&quot;&gt;Mechanize gem&lt;/a&gt; which I’ve had running correctly under Docker for the past six months.  And that’s why this was so, so surprising to me.  The mistake that I made was that earlier today I had added &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twilio/twilio-ruby&quot;&gt;twilio-ruby&lt;/a&gt; to my Gemfile and apparently twilio-ruby has different nokogiri dependencies than Mechanize which caused the Dockerfile to need libxml2-dev.  Digging into the twilio-ruby issues, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twilio/twilio-ruby/issues/315&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; which seems to address it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;see-also&quot;&gt;See Also&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My buddy Nick, mentioned above, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/docker-tip-9-installing-popular-packages-on-alpine&quot;&gt;talks about this on his blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/docker/2017/09/21/docker-won-t-install-libxml.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/docker/2017/09/21/docker-won-t-install-libxml.html</guid>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing iPhone X, iPhone 8 and iPhone 8 Plus</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not an Apple blogger – I leave that to people like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daringfireball.net&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; but I am an avid Apple user.  Between my wife and two sons, all of us have at least one Mac, iPad or iPhone.  I wrote this piece to analyze the differences between the new iPhones and help analyze how to spend what ultimately will be quite a bit of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This is all sourced from the web; my thanks to all the wonderful coverage cited below.  Particular kudos to Quincy Larson for his salient &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/why-you-should-never-unlock-your-phone-with-your-face-79c07772a28&quot;&gt;FaceID analysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understanding-your-personal-phone-usage&quot;&gt;Understanding Your Personal Phone Usage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the key to deciding whether or not to upgrade is to understand your personal phone usage and then if the new phones offer &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; a benefit.  You &lt;em&gt;don’t have&lt;/em&gt; to upgrade.  Let me repeat that – you &lt;strong&gt;don’t have&lt;/strong&gt; to upgrade.  Personally I am still running a 128 gig iPhone 6.  I never made the leap to the 7 because I use the smaller phone form factor and the camera was mostly unchanged from the 6 to the 7.  Given the importance of the camera to people’s daily lives, I was delighted to see all the camera updates in the iPhone X - it is now the same camera as the 6 plus / 7 plus but in the smaller phone’s form factor (ok the X is a little bit larger but I would deem it insignificant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My iPhone usage pattern is simple: it goes &lt;strong&gt;everywhere&lt;/strong&gt; I go.  I carry it constantly and the only place I don’t take it is swimming. I’ve carried it with me when I was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working on a roof&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cutting down trees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fishing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In aggregate, I use my phone more than any other computing device.  I compute less with it than I do a laptop but I use it more (if that makes sense).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I am using an iPhone 6 still, this means that I am now two cycles removed from current.  Consequently my battery life is such that I have to recharge during the day even when I’m not using the GPS, I’m constantly running out of space, the screen is scratched (no clue how that happened).  I am thus in the market for a new phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;new-phones-summarized&quot;&gt;New Phones Summarized&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three new phones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-8/specs/&quot;&gt;iPhone 8&lt;/a&gt; (similar to the current 7).  $699.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-x/specs/&quot;&gt;iPhone 8 Plus&lt;/a&gt; (similar to the current 7 plus).  $799.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-x/specs/&quot;&gt;iPhone X&lt;/a&gt; (the new phone).  $999.  Slightly bigger physically than the current iPhone 6 / 7 base model but NOT at all as large as the plus model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPhone X is the new hotness with an all new form factor, better camera, &lt;strong&gt;no home button&lt;/strong&gt; and an OLED screen.  Both the iPhone X and iPhone 8 offer wireless charging although Apple’s own wireless charging mat will not ship until “2018”.  Given the AirPod shipping delays this is concerning.  Technically any Qi compatible charging mat can be used but my suspicion is that Apple’s will somehow be better / faster (otherwise why the delay).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;key-stats&quot;&gt;Key Stats&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone X is available for pre-order on October 27 w/ launch on November 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone X is available in 256 and 64 gig capacities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone X has the &lt;strong&gt;same camera&lt;/strong&gt; as on the 7 Plus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone X has no home button and no TouchID.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone X claims 2 hours longer battery life than the iPhone 7.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animoji is exclusive to the iPhone X&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 8 is available for pre-order on September 15th with launch on September 22&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 8 and iPhone 8 Plus offer 12 MP cameras but the 8 Plus also has a telephoto lens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone/compare/&quot;&gt;Compare page&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;qualms-and-a-decision&quot;&gt;Qualms and a Decision&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest issue with the iPhone X is the lack of the home button and TouchID.  This is a fundamental change to the iPhone interface and one that greatly concerns me.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/why-you-should-never-unlock-your-phone-with-your-face-79c07772a28&quot;&gt;Quincy Larson&lt;/a&gt; raises some excellent points on why you shouldn’t unlock with your face.  Personally I find the need to unlock your phone while driving (GPS, play a podcast, etc) and the new FaceID feature disturbing to say the least.  As the parent of a driving age teenager, I will not be eager to see him get anything with FaceID.  Thankfully the device cost alone will prevent that but in a few years …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the analysis that I’ve done so far, I’m likely to upgrade to the iPhone X and do it through Apple’s monthly plan.  From what I’ve read, this amounts to about a $12 and change difference over the baseline 7 model and while I don’t like the $999 price, I don’t think that’s too much for something that I use constantly and travels with me literally everywhere I go that isn’t a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tipping point that pushed me over the edge to the new iPhone X was the new camera features being available in the iPhone X’s smaller form factor.  Had iPhone X had the same camera as the iPhone 7 then I likely wouldn’t have upgraded at all.  And had the iPhone 7 had the new camera as the iPhone X or 7 Plus, I likely would have decided to stay with the traditional home button design and not risked learning the new gestures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;see-also&quot;&gt;See Also&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some excellent breakdowns:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone/compare/&quot;&gt;Apple iPhone Compare Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-x/&quot;&gt;Apple iPhone X Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-8/&quot;&gt;Apple iPhone 8 Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-3/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-x/specs/&quot;&gt;iPhone X Tech Specs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-8/specs/&quot;&gt;iPhone 8 Tech Specs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/hands-on-with-the-iphone-x-oled-and-hdr-outshine-everything-else/&quot;&gt;Ars Technica Hands On on the iPhone X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/apples-radically-different-smartphone-is-called-the-iphone-x/&quot;&gt;Ars Technica on the iPhone X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/12/16287932/apple-iphone-8-plus-photos-video-hands-on&quot;&gt;iPhone 8 and 8 Plus from The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/12/16291244/new-iphone-x-photos-video-hands-on&quot;&gt;iPhone X from the Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/roundup/iphone-x/&quot;&gt;MacRumors on iPhone X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/roundup/iphone-8/&quot;&gt;MacRumors on iPhone 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15229317&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Discussion on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/iphone/2017/09/13/analyzing-iphone-x-iphone-7-and-iphone-7-plus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/iphone/2017/09/13/analyzing-iphone-x-iphone-7-and-iphone-7-plus.html</guid>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remembering Jerry Pournelle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There were three main dimensions to how I grew up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Computing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jerry_Pournelle&quot;&gt;Jerry Pournelle&lt;/a&gt; dramatically affected each of these for me.  Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you strip everything else away from me, at my core, I am a reader, specifically of the science fiction variety – and this goes all the way back to my childhood.  I’ve been reading as long as I can remember and it pretty much always has been science fiction.  I got started early with the Heinlein juveniles and it wasn’t a far leap from Heinlein to Jerry Pournelle.  I still remember when the librarians let me move from the kids section of the library to the adult section and that’s where I found him - King David’s Spaceship, West of Honor, Lucifer’s Hammer, Oath of Fealty and more.  And I can remember devouring Jerry’s work in Analog both under his name and under “Wade Curtis” when I started buying back issues and I remember having &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abebooks.com/book-search/author/curtis-wade-pournelle-jerry/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; in my collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good author, whether fact or fiction, imparts something to his readers far beyond the story and what Jerry Pournelle gave to me was a deep appreciation for engineering and just plain &lt;em&gt;rationality&lt;/em&gt;.  Thanks Jerry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;computing&quot;&gt;Computing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right along side reading for me was computing which I discovered in the 7th grade in Wilton, Connecticut at the school’s computer lab (a selection of TRS-80 Model 1s).  A trip to the local Walden Books made me aware of Byte Magazine way back in April 82 with this issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fiu-assets-2-syitaetz61hl2sa.stackpathdns.com/static/use-media-items/25/24048/full-971x1298/56703a87/198204.jpeg?resolution=0&quot; alt=&quot;byte magazine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That issue is still in my office and as I write this it is on my desk; I’ve owned it since I was 14 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I’m being honest, well, I understood about 1 word in 20, mostly the adjectives but what I did find actually not only readable but just plain joyful was &lt;em&gt;Chaos Manor&lt;/em&gt;, Jerry Pournelle’s column.  From that point forward, I read Byte for Jerry’s column and he was the person who gave me a deep love for computing in general and software in specific.  I can remember hours upon hours in my college library devouring back issues of Byte Magazine once I found their periodicals section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I became aware of hypertext from things written in Byte Magazine – and my first startup was a hypertext company.  If not for Jerry addicting me to Byte Magazine, I might never have known about it and my whole life would have been different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you didn’t read Jerry back in the day then you don’t understand what a colossus Jerry was in small computing.  Computing was deeply different in those days, a much smaller community and if you were influential, well, you were important.  This was a man who knew everyone – Bill Gates, Marvin Minsky, Steve Wozniak and more.  According to Jerry, Byte Magazine paid him $10,000 per month to write that column and that’s a fair bit of $$$ even today – back in the early 80s, that was a king’s ransom just to write a monthly computer column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;entrepreneurship&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my first company, a software firm building hypertext tools, when I was 19 and the very first copy of software I ever sent to a reviewer was sent to Jerry Pournelle.  He didn’t cover it then and it took repeated copies that we kept sending him until November 26, 1990 when he did give us some coverage in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=u1AEAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA64&amp;amp;lpg=PA64&amp;amp;dq=%22jerry+pournelle%22+%22ntergaid%22&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=pDFl9rznro&amp;amp;sig=wHE-VXmUd2h64RPIIYSYmvcs2Rs&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjGjdCY55zWAhUJ5oMKHeZPCHoQ6AEIJjAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22jerry%20pournelle%22%20%22ntergaid%22&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Infoworld column&lt;/a&gt;. A huge amount of what I know about the software business, specifically about writing good documentation, providing good technical support and just plain listening to customers, I learned from Jerry and his long tales of Zeke, the S100 bus and more.  Jerry wrote about computing from the user’s perspective and he gave a large number of us a deep appreciation for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rediscovering-jerry-pournelle-through-twit&quot;&gt;Rediscovering Jerry Pournelle Through Twit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the deep impact that Jerry Pournelle has had on my life, I haven’t thought much about Jerry for a long time now – Byte is long gone and the pace of his fiction output has decreased and his Chaos Manor column on the web didn’t resonate for me in the same way as his print column.  But thanks to Leo Laporte’s excellent TWIT show on YouTube, I have been able to discover him all over again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S7j3IG4h42Y&quot;&gt;Twit 90&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_5UVunOiXCk&quot;&gt;Twit 95&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some amazing stories here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Twit 90, he talks about making nitroglycerin at age 12&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Twit 95, he talks about the act of god that led him into freelance writing and then discussing the probability of it with Marvin Minsky (Minsky created Lisp and founded the MIT AI lab)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Twit 95, we talks about Robert Heinlein and the problem with being a best selling author, no one has the guts to edit you: “Time Enough or Love – there are three good novels there, shouldn’t they be three good novels?” (loose paraphrase but it is pretty close)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Twit 90, Jerry describes his Byte writing as “I wrote the Field and Stream column” and that analogy instantly brought all of his computing writing into focus for me since I actually grew up hunting &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reading Field and Stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very, very much Leo for doing these interviews, listening to you talk with Jerry for a few hours means a huge amount to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodbye Jerry, you’ll be missed but your influence is still alive and well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/personal/2017/09/11/remembering-jerry-pournelle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/personal/2017/09/11/remembering-jerry-pournelle.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SAAS Business Best Practices from Jonathan Siegel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Siegel wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B071NGMJPN&quot;&gt;The San Francisco Fallacy&lt;/a&gt; which is my favorite startup book of the year.  I liked it well enough that I’m in the middle of a second read and its one of the books I packed for an upcoming trip to Disney World.  Jonathan was &lt;a href=&quot;http://okdork.com/buying-a-business-jonathan-siegel/&quot;&gt;recently interviewed by Noah Kagan for Ok Dork&lt;/a&gt; and while all of it was excellent, there was one brief shining moment where it felt like the sun had opened up and ideas were literally shining down.  Here’s a recap of the best practices that he identified for a SAAS business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing their adwords.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doing landing page testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending out newsletters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogging regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forming partnerships.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going to events.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 minute callbacks whenever they get a new lead on the website&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try six times to reach every new inbound lead&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numbers 7 and 8 are new to me and ones that I definitely want to try.  Much of this interview was covering how he buys a business and the money statement of this was “If they team is already doing all these then I would never buy this company” because these techniques are how he adds value to the business and increases revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this was covered around the 24 minute mark.  If you’re an entrepreneur, I’d highly recommend listening to this podcast.  Noah’s stuff is always great but this particular episode was golden.  There’s also a great segment on how he identifies people to hire and why he doesn’t hire A players.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/saas/2017/09/06/saas-business-best-practices-from-jonathan-siegel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/saas/2017/09/06/saas-business-best-practices-from-jonathan-siegel.html</guid>
        
        <category>saas</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>best_practices</category>
        
        <category>business</category>
        
        
        <category>saas</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reclaiming Docker Disc Space on OSX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few nights ago, after a truly horrible night’s sleep complete with my first ever incidence of acid reflux, I woke to find my Mac nattering at me about being &lt;strong&gt;out of disc space&lt;/strong&gt;.  And by out of disc space I mean that I was down to about 3 gigs out of a terabyte sized SSD.  Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a look at the normal culprits yielded no surprise increases and I can distinctly recall having in excess of 30 gigs just a day or two ago.  Given all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/docker/2017/08/30/running-out-of-disc-space-with-docker.html&quot;&gt;server side problems with respect to Docker and disc space&lt;/a&gt; that I have written about previously, I had a strong hunch that somehow Docker was involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;logs&quot;&gt;Logs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought was that perhaps Docker logs are huge.  On OSX, Docker logs are stored here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/log&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a quick:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;09:41 $ du -shc ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/log
 20K	/Users/sjohnson/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/log
 20K	total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope – clearly 20K isn’t anything for disc space usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;containers&quot;&gt;Containers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next thought was that perhaps Docker has some massive backing store for containers.  I did a bunch of searches and ran across this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.docker.com/t/consistently-out-of-disk-space-in-docker-beta/9438/67&quot;&gt;Docker thread&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.docker.com/t/consistently-out-of-disk-space-in-docker-beta/9438/36&quot;&gt;another thread&lt;/a&gt;, both of which pointed me to the Docker.qcow2 file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what a du -shc showed me on this file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
 57G	/Users/sjohnson/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
 57G	total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;futile-attempts-to-reclaim-space&quot;&gt;Futile Attempts to Reclaim Space&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried the normal things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;docker system prune&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when that failed, I tried a bash based approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;item &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;docker ps -aq&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do
&lt;/span&gt;docker stop &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$item&lt;/span&gt;
docker rm &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$item&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;done

for &lt;/span&gt;item &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;docker images --filter &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;dangling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; -q&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do
&lt;/span&gt;docker rmi &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$item&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even after both of these, I still had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
 57G	total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-solution&quot;&gt;My Solution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here was the approach that I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quit Docker for Mac entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rm /Users/sjohnson/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As best as I can tell this is actually safe because containers can always be rebuilt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restart Docker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verify space usage:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
  1.3G total&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then built a container and then reverified disc space usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
1.3G	total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then built some more containers and then checked disc space usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
3.0G	total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then started my overall “build all containers” shell script and tracked progress as it went:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
3.0G	total

09:58 $ du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
3.1G	total

du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
3.4G    total

du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
5.4G    total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time all containers were built:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
7.2G    /Users/sjohnson/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, several days later and even more deploys, it has increased again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;du -shc     ~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
8.2G	/Users/sjohnson/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/com.docker.driver.amd64-linux/Docker.qcow2
8.2G	total
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;read-more&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.docker.com/t/consistently-out-of-disk-space-in-docker-beta/9438/67&quot;&gt;Great Docker Thread about Disc Space Usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.docker.com/t/where-does-docker-keep-images-containers-so-i-can-better-track-my-disk-usage/8370&quot;&gt;Docker Thread about Disc Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/docker/2017/09/06/reclaiming-docker-disc-space-on-osx.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/docker/2017/09/06/reclaiming-docker-disc-space-on-osx.html</guid>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
