<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 04:37:12 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 04:37:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings - Four Things that Betsy Devine Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I’m now happily ensconced in the mid west, once upon a time, in a vastly different personal universe, I lived in Boston.  And I think the happiest times I had in Boston were the brief period where I was part of the informal Boston blogging crowd centered around &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/&quot;&gt;Berkman Center at Harvard&lt;/a&gt; and a random crew of people that drifted into that orbit.  Among those people were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://betsydevine.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Betsy Devine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://halleyscomment.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Halley Suitt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rura.org/shimon/&quot;&gt;Shimon Rura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markbernstein.org/&quot;&gt;Mark Bernstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.harvard.edu/jkbaumga/&quot;&gt;Jessica Baumgart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Myself and many others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of us were drawn together to the hotness of a new medium and it had, as best as I can tell, the feeling of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salon_(gathering)&quot;&gt;18th century salon&lt;/a&gt;.  Everything was new; the people were excited and it felt like something was brewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betsy_Devine&quot;&gt;Betsy Devine&lt;/a&gt; and what I learned from her.  I first met Betsy in roughly May 2003 as dated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/story.radio.weblogs.com/2003/05/11/boston-beach-blogging-bingo.html&quot;&gt;this url&lt;/a&gt; where she was present; the pictures aren’t present any more – I’ll fix that some other time so you’ll have to take my word for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I didn’t really know Betsy very well but here’s what I did and didn’t know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I knew she was pleasant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I knew she was clearly smart as a whip but I was in my mid 30s and Betsy was my Mom’s age so I suspect I didn’t give all the respect I should have.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t know that she was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Longing-Harmonies-Themes-Variations-Physics/dp/0393305961/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1479718439&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Longing+for+the+Harmonies&quot;&gt;published author&lt;/a&gt; (yes I just ordered it and you likely should to if you’re bothering to read this).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And I knew she was kind which is a character trait all to often overlooked and all too often ignored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then in 2004 Betsy’s life changed dramatically – her &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Wilczek&quot;&gt;husband&lt;/a&gt;, someone I knew slightly from having carved &lt;a href=&quot;http://betsydevine.com/blog/page/89/?s=devine&quot;&gt;this pumpkin at their house on October 22, 2003&lt;/a&gt;, won the &lt;strong&gt;Nobel Prize&lt;/strong&gt; in Physics.  At the time I met him, I was told “hey - here’s Betsy’s husband - he teaches at MIT”.  And, yes, MIT is impressive but he’s a teacher (and a very pleasant fellow).  And so Betsy went from being just Betsy to being the wife of a legitimate celebrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-first-celebrity-changes-things&quot;&gt;Learning the First: Celebrity Changes Things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In modern culture celebrity is an odd thing.  I work alone, from home, in a pitch dark room, most days so I clearly fall into the introvert camp and I’ve never cared much for it but I’ve had a few random encounters with celebrities over the years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My first partner physically crashed into Bill Gates at a CD-ROM conference back in maybe ‘91 and almost took him out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I stayed on Ted Turner’s yacht once upon a time when my Dad and I were hunting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My Dad’s best friend, Jim Mattingly, &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.sailingscuttlebutt.com/cgi-bin/gforum.cgi?post=7816#7816&quot;&gt;skippered Tenacious in the Fastnet Race in ‘79&lt;/a&gt;.  He was then featured in posters that ran for years in the boating industry (I grew up in boating)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andy_Rooney&quot;&gt;Andy Rooney&lt;/a&gt; used to shop at one of my family’s wood working businesses and he was exactly the same in person as on 60 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, even with some exposure to celebrities all through my youth, I suspect on some level, post 2004, I viewed Betsy at least a little bit as “wife of a nobel laureate” instead of as “Betsy”.  Apologies for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally this is where I end this type of post but not this time.  Upon reflection I learned at least two more things from Betsy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-second-never-ever-underestimate-the-brains-people-have&quot;&gt;Learning the Second: Never, Ever Underestimate the Brains People Have&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Joy&quot;&gt;Bill Joy&lt;/a&gt; is a computer scientist, a co-founder of Sun Microsystems, the primary author of BSD unix and too many other technical achievements to write down and the author of Joy’s Law:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Joy’s law is the principle that “no matter who you are, most of the smartest people work for someone else,” \ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joy's_law_(management)&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Bill Joy wrote this in the context of Sun, Microsoft and technical nerds and who they work for but I would actually expand it to be something far more expansive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are smart people all around you.  And at least one of them is almost certainly smarter than you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my initial perspective Betsy was a mom, heck, she even looked like my mom.  What I didn’t realize at the time, and wouldn’t realize for literally years to come, was just how &lt;strong&gt;damn smart&lt;/strong&gt; she was.  I should have taken a clue from the fact that she wrote humor professionally.  Comedians are always smart and that should have tipped me off.  Or I should have taken a clue from the fact that she had a Masters in Materials Science Engineering from Princeton.  How smart did she have to be to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get into princeton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get into a technical field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get into a technical field as a woman in 1978??&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get a master’s degree that almost certainly required a thesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that by any measure there’s far more depth to Betsy’s smarts then I’ll ever know. There are literally smart people all around you; never, ever, underestimate the brains people have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-third-what-might-betsy-have-done&quot;&gt;Learning the Third: What Might Betsy Have Done?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender and identity politics is a dicey subject in America in 2016 so I write this with no small degree of trepidation.  It is the reason that as a profoundly white male of privilege – the only college nickname I ever had was, I kid you not, &lt;em&gt;Captain Whitebread&lt;/em&gt; – I actually had Betsy read this in advance of posting since I didn’t want to stick my foot in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my third learning is more of a zen like question – Why Might Betsy Have Done?  As a woman, even an accomplished woman, in the late 1960s / 1970s, Betsy went down a fairly traditional route of wife and mother but also kept herself as a distinct entity.  That’s a challenge because raising a family is an all consuming past time.  I say that as a father and husband who has seen that his wife has a harder “job” that he has.  And my wife certainly has a more important job than I have.  My work product is literally ephemeral – I write lines of code that often don’t survive a week.  My wife?  She’s takes little people and day by day turns them into big people.  Every product I’ve ever written – and I’ve written a lot of them – will be gone someday, generally soon – but my wife’s “work product” will last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have damn near infinite respect for what Betsy did.  But when I see how smart she is and how smart she has to be it makes me wonder what she might have done.  Perhaps in a slightly different universe she might have the Nobel prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next time you see a wife and mother and look at the accomplishments that their husband has you should really wonder what that wife and mother might have done on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-fourth-engage-more-with-women-at-work&quot;&gt;Learning the Fourth: Engage More with Women at Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a brief period Betsy helped out with Feedster back in 2003 / 2004 and she added very real value.  One of the things I noticed was that she made a great team player and brought a very different perspective to things.  So the next time you see a woman at work, whether she’s “technical” or not, recognize that she’s almost certainly smart and there is a fair chance you’re underestimating her.  Men are notorious for that and there’s no reason for it in this day and age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the fourth learning.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/11/29/startup-learnings-two-things-that-betsy-devine-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/11/29/startup-learnings-two-things-that-betsy-devine-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Tech Note - Problems with Ubuntu 16.04 and Ansible</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When i started going heavy down the path of AWS, Ubuntu 14.04 was the default Ubuntu in AWS and it appeared at the top of the Operating System list when you built a new EC2 server.  I’ve run Ubuntu for &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt; ever since I asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://ma.tt/&quot;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt; what distro WordPress used and he replied Ubuntu.  &lt;em&gt;blink&lt;/em&gt;  At the time I looked at Ubuntu as a personal distro but, hey, if it is good enough for WordPress then it is good enough for my crappy, little farm of boxes.  And so I’ve been in Ubuntu ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was the first bad Ubuntu experience that I’ve really ever had.  What happened was I went to bring up a new EC2 instance and I noticed that the default Ubuntu was now 16.04.  Hm… That’s different but I’ll try it.  So I trot out my ansible playbook and here’s what happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ansible-playbook -i inventories/proxy playbook_appdata_proxy.yml

PLAY [all] *********************************************************************

TASK [setup] *******************************************************************
fatal: [adproxy2]: FAILED! =&amp;gt; {&quot;changed&quot;: false, &quot;failed&quot;: true, &quot;module_stderr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, &quot;module_stdout&quot;: &quot;/bin/sh: 1: /usr/bin/python: not found\r\n&quot;, &quot;msg&quot;: &quot;MODULE FAILURE&quot;, &quot;parsed&quot;: false}
fatal: [adproxy1]: FAILED! =&amp;gt; {&quot;changed&quot;: false, &quot;failed&quot;: true, &quot;module_stderr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, &quot;module_stdout&quot;: &quot;/bin/sh: 1: /usr/bin/python: not found\r\n&quot;, &quot;msg&quot;: &quot;MODULE FAILURE&quot;, &quot;parsed&quot;: false}

NO MORE HOSTS LEFT *************************************************************
[WARNING]: Could not create retry file 'playbook_appdata_proxy.retry'.         [Errno 2] No such file or directory: ''


PLAY RECAP *********************************************************************
adproxy1                   : ok=0    changed=0    unreachable=0    failed=1
adproxy2                   : ok=0    changed=0    unreachable=0    failed=1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What??? There error is here: &lt;strong&gt;“/bin/sh: 1: /usr/bin/python: not found\r\n”&lt;/strong&gt;.  Apparently Python is NOT a default install on Ubuntu 16.04 LTS.  That means that you can’t use Ansible to bootstrap a box into functionality until you’ve first installed Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the single best attributes of Ansible is that you don’t have to install anything to use it – until now.  Unlike tools like Chef or Puppet which require an agent to be installed, Ansible has always just required nothing but python.  And since python used to be a default install you could trivially just “ansible-ize” a box into functionality.  This is a huge deal.  Happily Ubuntu 14.04 is still available – you just have to dig down to the very bottom of the Operating Systems list to find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes I’m absolutely certain that there are very real reasons why I want 16.04 instead of 14.04 but at least for now the operational benefits of being able to bring a box up with Ansible far, far outweigh them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/11/29/aws-tech-note-problems-with-ubuntu-16-04-and-ansible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/11/29/aws-tech-note-problems-with-ubuntu-16-04-and-ansible.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>ubuntu</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code Monkey, Software Engineer, Computer Scientist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So my buddy Nick mentioned to me that he wrote a blog post titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/are-you-a-computer-scientist-or-a-code-monkey&quot;&gt;Are You a Computer Scientist or a Code Monkey?&lt;/a&gt; and I almost instantly had typed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jekyll post “Code Monkey, Software Engineer, Computer Scientist”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t actually think that he had finished talking before I had my take on this going.  So:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go read &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/are-you-a-computer-scientist-or-a-code-monkey&quot;&gt;Nick’s post&lt;/a&gt;; it is good and I’ll wait.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Come back because my take on it is different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick looked at this in terms of are you a code monkey or are you a computer scientist.  Personally I think that this is more nuanced than that.  And I don’t think that it is impossible to actually be all of these at once depending on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;science-versus-engineering&quot;&gt;Science Versus Engineering&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a great many people on the Internet who can talk to you about the difference between science and engineering.  To me the fundamental difference is that science is concerned with the &lt;strong&gt;WHY&lt;/strong&gt; and engineering is concerned with the &lt;strong&gt;HOW&lt;/strong&gt;.  As an example consider a hashing algorithm like MD5.  A computer scientist can explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it works but a software engineer just cares about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;code-monkey&quot;&gt;Code Monkey&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Software Engineer
# Computer Scientist
# An Example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at my recent Poor Man’s Load Balancer post, I think this is a nice illustration of shifting between Computer Scientist and Software Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 19:03:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/11/28/code-monkey-software-engineer-computer-scientist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/11/28/code-monkey-software-engineer-computer-scientist.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parenting Actually Does Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there is a parent alive, certainly not a parent of a teenager, who doesn’t at some point want to throw their hands up in the air and go &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WHY AM I BOTHERING!!!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are a parent then you know the drill – you talk and you talk and you talk and your kid never seems to get it.  Sometimes it feels like you are talking to a brick wall and other times it feels worse.  I have a teenage boy, 15, myself so I say this with a fairly high degree of authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I wanted to pass on to other parents tho is that you actually &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt; getting thru but it may take &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt; for you to realize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example from my own life.  As a young child I was tremendously clumsy.  And I’m not not sure that I am any better now but that’s a different story.  As a clumsy child I had a tendency to knock glasses off the kitchen table which led to shattered glass &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;.  And my mother, bless her heart, always had the same reaction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone freeze!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The furthest person away grabs the shoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleanup with paper towels for the wet, then broom and then vacuum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this afternoon I was assembling Christmas lights and the strand I was working on fell and &lt;strong&gt;WHAM&lt;/strong&gt; about 10 1 1/2” colored bulbs all exploded.  There was glass from one end of the kitchen to the other.  And you know what I did?  Well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone freeze!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The furthest person away grabs the shoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleanup with broom and then vacuum (there was no wet so no paper towels).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t gone thru this with my mom in maybe 35 years now but, today, when I needed it, it was there like a &lt;strong&gt;reflex&lt;/strong&gt;, as automatic as breathing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what I mean by &lt;strong&gt;parenting actually does work&lt;/strong&gt;.  Keep in mind that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You need to be consistent in what you do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have to stay at it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You won’t see the pay off for literally years.  You might never see it; I doubt I’ll ever tell my Mom about today and she’s the last person in the universe to read my blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if your kids appear not to be listening or even caring, if you stay at it, they’ll pick it up even if it is by osmosis that they aren’t even aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/parenting/2016/11/28/parenting-actually-does-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/parenting/2016/11/28/parenting-actually-does-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
        <category>fatherhood</category>
        
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Poor Man's Load Balancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I’ve spent the last few days dealing with proxy servers and trying to get a group of AWS instances, all running squid, to hide behind a load balancer.  And, alas, this seems to not be possible with AWS.  There are two basic issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The proxy protocol header cannot be enabled via the AWS Console; why I do not know.  You have to script it and even though I did it, it does not seem to work.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing/latest/classic/enable-proxy-protocol.html&quot;&gt;AWS Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The proxy request doesn’t seem to get to squid – at least based on the squid log files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation is that a number of my IP addresses seem to have been dropped on a perma-ban list.  You can get around this a number of ways but one of the easier ones is to use a proxy server in between your content fetch and the content source.  Most of my content fetching software relies on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sparklemotion/mechanize&quot;&gt;Ruby Mechanize library&lt;/a&gt; so all I have to do is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;agent = Mechanize.new
agent.set_proxy(proxy_url, proxy_port)
page = agent.get(url)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that will cause the fetch to go thru the proxy server first and then to the content source.  This nicely gets around the block at the expense of some performance due to the proxying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for wanting a load balancer in the mix is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eliminate the need for a giant box as the proxy server; more, cheaper nodes is a better model, more amenable to the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide more discrete ip addresses involved the proxying so we don’t appear to have a single ip address doing everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the AWS load balancer doesn’t work then there are options.  One option is to get up HA Proxy once again.  I’ve done this time and time again and it usually works at the expense of configuration woes and a moderate level of cursing. Not sailor cursing mind you and certainly not “The Tree House Fell On Me Again” level of cursing.  But after you’ve put together a load balancer with the AWS Console web forms, you don’t ever want to use HA Proxy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this brings us to the title of this article - a &lt;strong&gt;poor man’s load balancer&lt;/strong&gt;.  Here’s how we go about this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a list of proxy server urls in a config file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A routine which loads the urls into an array and returns a random element i.e. calling .sample.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pass that random proxy server into the create mechanize routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what I’m now using.  This is by no means the degree of elegance that I was looking for but sometimes you don’t always get what you want – but you still have to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/11/28/a-poor-man-s-load-balancer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/11/28/a-poor-man-s-load-balancer.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>proxy</category>
        
        <category>load_balancer</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So You Want to Get Rid of RVM Server Side and Still Use Capistrano</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot express to you just how much I despise certain parts of the ruby ecosystem.  I love ruby the language but I have very real issues with parts of the ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I regard typing bundle exec as a damn &lt;strong&gt;tax&lt;/strong&gt; on my productivity; every single time I look at it as 11 fewer characters than I should have to enter.  It is a tax.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, rant aside, I have to say that I am fundamentally grateful for RVM.  RVM enabled a whole host of&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 09:27:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ruby/2016/11/27/so-you-want-to-get-rid-of-rvm-server-side-and-still-use-capistrano.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ruby/2016/11/27/so-you-want-to-get-rid-of-rvm-server-side-and-still-use-capistrano.html</guid>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>rvm</category>
        
        <category>system_ruby</category>
        
        <category>capistrano</category>
        
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cloud Hosting Price Comparisons Are Utterly False</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I’ve now started to see all kinds of articles about cloud pricing.  Here are just two examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/2016/11/18/google-cloud-is-50-cheaper-than-aws/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud is 50% Cheaper than AWS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://welcome.linode.com/pricing-comparison/?r=6b44fd00604f7059c77db8cb6e821a8c91fa5f8b&quot;&gt;Linode Pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And seeing these makes me want to comment that cloud pricing comparisons, generally speaking, are entirely false.  There are two aspects to any kind of pricing comparisons for something like cloud pricing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The $$$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take each of these in turn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-&quot;&gt;The $$$&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I disputing &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/2016/11/18/google-cloud-is-50-cheaper-than-aws/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by THEHFTGUY?  I mean he has graphs and all and I suspect that he understands cloud pricing really, really well.  I do think that this statement is actually quite unfair:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Google has been designing networks and manufacturing their own equipment for decades. It’s fair to assume than AWS doesn’t have the technology to compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he rounds out his article with two interesting comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;AWS was the first generation of cloud, Google is the second. The second generation is always better because it can learn from the mistakes of the first and it doesn’t have the old legacy to support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2016 should be remembered as the year Google became a better choice than AWS. If 50% cheaper is not a solid argument, I don’t know what is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-skills&quot;&gt;Your Skills&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading my nerdy ramblings then it is a pretty fair bet that either you are a personal friend, in which case – &lt;strong&gt;Hello Friend&lt;/strong&gt;!, or you are a professional developer or you want to be.  Now here’s the reality of being a professional developer – your single greatest asset is &lt;strong&gt;your skills&lt;/strong&gt;.  And here’s what I mean by that – my skills in Ruby have made me damn near a million dollars in the past decade.  I’m not bragging, I’m not boasting, I’m stating a fact.  I look at anything I do technically thru a fairly focused lens – is this going to make my skills better or worse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally made the decision to buckle down and really learn AWS, not simply piddle around the edges with S3, that was actually a tough decision for me.  You see as a professional I’ve made this type of decision before.  From 1987 to 1999 I committed to Microsoft and Windows for all my development activities.  Then in 1999 I found that Windows, at least for me, had run its course and that was when I went all open source for everything, save one brief, damn lucrative engagement.  That was the last time in my life that I went down the proprietary route.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 04:24:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/11/27/cloud-hosting-price-comparisons-are-utterly-false.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/11/27/cloud-hosting-price-comparisons-are-utterly-false.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>cloud</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Automating Google Takeout</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/gaubert/gmvault&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 13:54:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/26/automating-google-takeout.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/26/automating-google-takeout.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Native Apps Are Not Doomed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/native-apps-are-doomed-ac397148a2c0#.knd91wksx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/why-native-apps-really-are-doomed-native-apps-are-doomed-pt-2-e035b43170e9#.iipzbyled&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13002598&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 13:52:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/26/native-apps-are-not-doomed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/26/native-apps-are-not-doomed.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anistrano Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/ansistrano/deploy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ansible-galaxy install carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-deploy carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-rollback
- downloading role ‘ansistrano-deploy’, owned by carlosbuenosvinos
- downloading role from https://github.com/ansistrano/deploy/archive/1.10.1.tar.gz
- extracting carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-deploy to /usr/local/etc/ansible/roles/carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-deploy
- carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-deploy was installed successfully
- downloading role ‘ansistrano-rollback’, owned by carlosbuenosvinos
- downloading role from https://github.com/ansistrano/rollback/archive/1.5.0.tar.gz
- extracting carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-rollback to /usr/local/etc/ansible/roles/carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-rollback
- carlosbuenosvinos.ansistrano-rollback was installed successfully&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also looked at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nicolai86/ansible-rails-deployment&quot;&gt;https://github.com/nicolai86/ansible-rails-deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=deploy+rails+with+ansible&amp;amp;oq=deploy+rails+with+ansible&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.5104j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Google Search on Deploying Rails with Ansible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codementor.io/devops/tutorial/deploying-ruby-application-with-ansible&quot;&gt;CodeMentor Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 13:49:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/26/anistrano-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/26/anistrano-review.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
