<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc / Hyde.
</description>
    <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 12:46:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 12:46:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>So You Want to Delete Temp Files - An Excursion into Software Engineering Suckitude</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So today was a day of epic software engineering failure.  Let’s consider, just for a second, this string of commit messages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;feature/ATT-1551-f - And goodbye ... it all goes away like the bad dream that it was
feature/ATT-1551-e - It is called a constant; sigh; oh and an entire rewrite
feature/ATT-1551-d - And let's go again - there are still hours in the day to get this wrong ...
feature/ATT-1551-c - hopefully, possibly the last iteration on this humiliating bit of work
feature/ATT-1551-b - Argggh !!!!
feature/ATT-1551-a - Debugging hooks for understanding this bit of madness
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any experienced engineer can read between the lines of that level of &lt;em&gt;gallows humor&lt;/em&gt; in these commit messages and know, I mean &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;, what’s coming.  This whole blog post is an illustration of how something that is drop dead simple can really, really bite you in the ass.  And you can take away from this either a smug feeling of “I’m smarter than that” or you are raising a glass to me somewhere and saying “you poor damn bastard, there, there”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all started with the git branch &lt;em&gt;feature/ATT-1551&lt;/em&gt; which added a feature to our architecture which cleaned up straggling temp files that had been left behind by a variety of different processes that generated data locally that was then queued up to S3.  Yes, yes, yes I know fix the cause not the symptom but that was out of the scope of the defined work; you know the drill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a Rails application and I made the decision to implement this as a Capistrano post deploy hook that executed a Capistrano rake task.  That was, unbeknownst to me, my &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; mistake.  The specification on the ticket said that the need was to clean up any files in shared/tmp that were older than 10 days.  My initial pass on this ended up being about maybe 25 lines of ruby implemented in lib/capistrano/tasks/tmp_files.rake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-heres-where-it-all-began&quot;&gt;And Here’s Where It All Began&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My code went thru the pull review process just fine until there was a comment that said something to the effect of “Wouldn’t it be better if the 10 days was not fixed in the code but could be adjustable from outside so we didn’t have to redeploy if we needed a different amount of days”.  That sounds logical, right?  The pull request discussion thread diverged between passing in a parameter or using an environment variable and it ultimately converged on an environment variable because a parameter didn’t work since this was already buried inside an Ansible based deploy engine that executed a Capistrano task (that then called a post deploy hook).  So with that decision, the descent into madness truly began.  And if my description of Ansible spawning Capistrano spawning a post deploy hook feels virtually Cthulian to you, well, &lt;em&gt;yep&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sidebar:&lt;/em&gt; I’d love to tell you that all of this was easily resolved but that wouldn’t be fun, now would it?  Instead, while the initial code was written by me, getting this actually debugged and solved took two senior software engineers most of a day. And it is an excellent illustration of just how complex even something simple can be in today’s world.  The second engineer got pulled in right about here, after the pull review process centered around environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nothing-is-actually-simple-anymore&quot;&gt;Nothing is Actually Simple Anymore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a file of environment variables that are automatically defined by our application using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/laserlemon/figaro&quot;&gt;Figaro gem&lt;/a&gt;.  Normally I’m not an environment var fan but this really works well so I followed our normal process for this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go into our Ansible stack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decrypt the environment variable files (these are YAML files and that becomes relevant later on)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the new variable to each of our environments (production, training, staging)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encrypt the environment variables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move the environment variable files up to our Jenkins deployment box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for the convoluted process is that we don’t have these files as part of our Capistrano deployment since they expose serious credentials.  Instead our Ansible wrapper around the deployment handles moving these up and in place.  And this uses Ansible’s transparent encrypting / decrypting as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few go arounds of “what should this variable be named”, I added to our Ansible stack two shell files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;decrypt_all.sh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;encrypt_all.sh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at least that makes this process suck less given that each command line for this is about 112 characters long and I have to do it three times every single time.  I try and follow a boy scout’s approach to code where you leave things better than you found them whenever possible.  And this did make things better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-the-environment-variables&quot;&gt;Using the Environment Variables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this was done, that led to modifying the code to pull the value out of the environment variable.  Now this should have been nothing more than reading ENV[‘DELETE_TMP_FILE_DAYS’] for the value TRUE, couldn’t be easier, right?  Ha!  &lt;em&gt;Shudder&lt;/em&gt;. Given that this was implemented as a Capistrano post deploy hook, getting any bit of this tested boiled down to this process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a new branch for every single debugging attempt (because we have to go thru a pull review process)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Git commit / add / push&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go thru pull review process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deploy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait thru a roughly 11 minute deploy cycle for something to fail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read logs to analyze failure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lather / Rinse / Repeat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that this is a post deploy hook executed Rake task there is no way to debug this easily.  Yes you can check the code.  And you can execute it manually in Rails console but that’s not quite the same as it actually running in the environment … or is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cutting-to-the-chase-or-11-steps-into-madness&quot;&gt;Cutting to the Chase Or 11 Steps Into Madness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is getting kind of long already so I’m going to cut to the chase and bullet point the issues as we hit them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first issue was that we kept defaulting to the if / else case where our environment variable wasn’t being set.  And since I was casting this to a constant for safety (remember this code deletes files on a file system so it is wise to be damn careful with it), this meant that the constant kept failing a defined? check.  We had put in a raise “Constant not defined” unless defined?(CONSTANT_NAME) check before anything got deleted as a safe guard and that one line of code entirely saved us.  Kudos to my coding partner, Sean Kennedy, for that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This first issue ultimately ended up being tied to recognizing that a Capistrano post deploy hook &lt;em&gt;DOES NOT RUN UNDER RAILS&lt;/em&gt;!  And that means that anything loaded by a Rails initializer isn’t available — meaning the Figaro gem never executed so the values in our environment variable file weren’t even being seen.  But since our environment variable file syntax was read from using ENV[‘VARIABLE_NAME’] we weren’t getting failures due to ENV not existing (ENV always exists, even in an IRB environment).  We would just get a nil value instead of the expected string value of TRUE or FALSE.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out that we weren’t in a Rails environment was one of those face palm moments — you’ve seen the meme, the one with Picard.  I’m more than a bit embarrassed to point out how long that took so we’re just going to move on past that issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once we recognized that Figaro wasn’t available and that we would never get a value for our environment variable key, it wasn’t hard to write our own YAML reading routine.  That went thru a deploy cycle and we were fairly certain that it would be solved any minute now — what a crock!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What we found was that even though our YAML file had a structure of KEY_NAME=TRUE, we weren’t getting back TRUE, we were getting back true.  So, of course, our if test which matched on ‘TRUE’ would fail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;At this point we started testing using the IRB (remember you aren’t using Rails) console and YAML parsing.  And this led us to realize that YAML has automatic type coercion for a range of possible true / false values. The first clue was when my editor showed color coding on the YAML value we had, but not when we changed it to something odd like “ASDF”.  And we ultimately found the &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaml.org/type/bool.html&quot;&gt;YAML spec&lt;/a&gt; which takes about booleans.  Who even knew there was a spec for YAML???  Any of these in a YAML file will automatically get coerced into a boolean: *y&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;n&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;True&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;TRUE&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;False&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;FALSE&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;on&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;On&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;ON&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;off&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Off&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;OFF*&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t know about any other developer but to hell with that noise!  I changed our value from TRUE to 1.  And because I wasn’t sure if that would come to me as a value or a string, I ended up with a logical check like this: [1,”1”].include?(ENV[‘DELETE_TMP_FILE_DAYS’]).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The next hurdle was that we realized that it was ambiguous where we should be looking for the YAML file.  The backtrace indicated that the YAML file should be found on the box where Capistrano was executing but logically because the post deploy hook executes each node being deployed, it should be on that machine.  And given that there was an 11 minute minimum cycle time per attempt to figure this out, we simply said to heck with it and tested for each directory and read from whichever existed.  And don’t even bring up the fact that the exception Ruby throws on an invalid directory isn’t Errno::ENOENT but instead a system call exception.  Sheesh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once we finally got past nothing more than the boolean test of whether or not to run this (remember that’s all we’ve been trying to do so far, isolate a boolean from inside the code base to an environment variable), we found the code failing entirely.  And this time the failure was weird and unclear.  It had the feeling that Capistrano itself was swallowing at least one exception.  Doing a read of the code line by line made is realize that the date time math was using a Rails-ism, 10.days.  And, remember, we aren’t in Rails now (even though this is a Rails app), this is a Capistrano post deploy hook so we are really running an an IRB context without ActiveSupport.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And that brought in the need to treat this not as logical days but instead as old school Unix epoch math.  So it become a matter of comparing a File.ctime(path_to_file).to_i (for the epoch conversion) against Time.now.to_i - (10 * 86400).  My pairing partner wanted to bring in ActiveSupport for the clarity of the 10.days expression but I was having none of that, ActiveSupport is a beast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With each of these changes, we would make the code better and better, each time and we were finally at a point where the code was actually what even I would call good.  It was well structured, well written and clean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sidebar-what-about-test-coverage&quot;&gt;Sidebar: What About Test Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone out there reading this is pounding their desk and shouting “YOU SHOULDA WRITTEN TESTS DUMB ASS!!!”.  Now normally I would agree with you but there are a few problems with that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rake tasks aren’t well testable; God bless Jim Weirich but rake tasks have always been an aside to testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There isn’t, to my knowledge, a way to test a rake task that is executing under Capistrano and isn’t actually part of Rails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-that-brings-us-to-the-final-solution&quot;&gt;And that Brings Us to The Final Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with the code finally rewritten and being actually implemented in a very service object pattern, my co worker said “WAIT!  Why are we doing this as a Capistrano post deploy hook anyway?  Why isn’t this just a CRON job calling a rake task”  This led to a discussion of the issues around CRON and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbenv/rbenv&quot;&gt;RbEnv&lt;/a&gt; and the need for the DevOps around getting a CRON job installed on N boxes.  And then he said the magic incantation: “Why don’t we just use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; for this and execute it regularly via &lt;a href=&quot;https://jenkins.io/&quot;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt;?”  Ansible is an outstandingly good DevOps environment and one that I actually taught him.  My initial argument to him against Ansible was because this was fundamentally an imperative task and Ansible was declarative.  His counter was why not just use Ansible to solve this via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzyblog.io/blog/linux/2019/05/09/linux-tip-find-all-files-older-than-10-days-and-delete-them.html&quot;&gt;bash shell expression&lt;/a&gt;.  I thought about it for a few, and, son of a bitch, he was right.  In about 40 minutes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We tossed out all of the Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We tossed out the entire Capistrano post deploy task&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We tossed out the invocation of the call back (ok I remembered this right now as I wrote this section of the blog post)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We spun up an Ansible Playbook and Role that executed a shell one liner and had it running on a dozen plus boxes.  This included researching and testing how to do this with shell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We defined a Jenkins scheduled task that ran this every 7 days at an off time using a simple CRON syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the before / after on the final Ansible implementation showing the change in our disc space utilization:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;before&quot;&gt;BEFORE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ok: [194.55.22.38] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 5.3G'
ok: [194.55.19.230] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 5.6G'
ok: [194.55.23.18] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 5.6G'
ok: [194.55.23.10] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.5G'
ok: [194.55.30.164] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.5G'
ok: [194.55.20.214] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 11G'
ok: [194.55.30.119] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.2G'
ok: [194.55.29.248] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.7G'
ok: [194.55.26.185] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 6.7G'
ok: [194.55.24.235] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 6.6G'
ok: [194.55.30.37] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 2.3G'
ok: [194.55.31.216] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 2.4G'
ok: [194.55.29.170] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 11G'
ok: [194.55.29.107] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 11G'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;after&quot;&gt;AFTER&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ok: [194.55.22.38] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 5.3G'
ok: [194.55.19.230] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 5.8G'
ok: [194.55.23.18] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 5.8G'
ok: [194.55.23.10] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.5G'
ok: [194.55.30.164] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.5G'
ok: [194.55.20.214] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 11G'
ok: [194.55.30.119] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.3G'
ok: [194.55.29.248] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 8.7G'
ok: [194.55.26.185] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 6.7G'
ok: [194.55.24.235] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 6.6G'
ok: [194.55.30.37] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 7.2G'
ok: [194.55.31.216] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 7.0G'
ok: [194.55.29.170] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 11G'
ok: [194.55.29.107] =&amp;gt;
  msg: 'Actual free disc space: 11G'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that boxes 194.55.30.37 and 194.55.31.216 went from 2 odd gigs of free disc space to 7 odd gigs of disc space.  That’s a huge win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part about debugging anything is when your mental model doesn’t match what’s actually going on under the hood.  The actual epiphany moment was when I realized that this wasn’t running under Rails itself.  After that things started to fall into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-yous&quot;&gt;Thank Yous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big shout out to Sean Kennedy who did a fantastic job debugging this with me and came up with a great final solution.  Kudos also to various friends who im’d with me over the course of the day and provided moral support on an extremely frustrating day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2019/05/09/so-you-want-to-delete-temp-files-an-excursion-into-software-engineering-suckitude.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2019/05/09/so-you-want-to-delete-temp-files-an-excursion-into-software-engineering-suckitude.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails, Migrations, Multiple Developers and the Schema WTF Moment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing Rails now since 2007.  However for much of that time I was a project lead and one of the tasks that I reserved for myself was &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; schema changes.  One of the benefits of that was that because I did all the primary schema changes, I rarely, if ever, had schema conflicts.  I am now on a project where, while I am a Senior Software Engineer, I am not the lead and the schema changes are done by everyone on the team, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consequence of this is that while Rails should handle any schema conflicts correctly, well, &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; is the operative term.  In practice we have found that depending on how you do your git pull and git branching, you often (like every damn branch you make) end up with a schema conflict.  And since our schema file is enormous (think over 3,000 lines in schema.rb), figuring this out can be brutal.  This moment where you realized that your schema is borked is what I call the &lt;em&gt;Schema WTF Moment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve struggled with this for a while and never found a decent solution, today, I was speaking with another senior guy (my buddy Sean Kennedy) and he very cogently explained the issue in a way that made sense.  This is my write up of his description.  He described it thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you do a git pull, you should already have the latest schema, affected by any migrations that came in via the pull, but your database tables may not be updated. So, you do need to run the migrations after pulling, but this will often change db/schema.rb. If all you’ve done is pull and migrate, there’s no reason you should be responsible for committing any of the resultant schema changes as they don’t technically belong to you, and they may end up being extraneous/incorrect, so resetting the schema diff makes the most sense.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you understand our approach to git, we use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All work is done in a branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All branches are created from develop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once a branch is approved, it is merged into develop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The develop branch is automatically deployed to staging with every merge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A production deploy automatically merges develop into master.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The master branch is only deployed to production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my step by step version of what to do before beginning a branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Switch your code base over to the develop branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull the latest code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run bundle exec rake db:migrate.  This updates your schema.rb file locally but you want to throw these changes away before beginning any work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a git checkout db/schema.rb to throw away the changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create your new branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change to your new branch and begin work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2019/05/09/rails-migrations-multiple-developers-and-the-schema-wtf-moment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2019/05/09/rails-migrations-multiple-developers-and-the-schema-wtf-moment.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>schema</category>
        
        <category>migration</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux Tip - Find All Files Older than 10 Days and Delete Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is easy to forget at times just how powerful simple Linux shell commands here.  Here’s one I used recently that finds all files in a single directory that are older than 25 days and deletes them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;find /apps/foo/shared/tmp/ -mtime +25 -maxdepth 1 -exec rm {} \;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The -mtime param takes a number of days.  The maxdepth takes the number of directories below this to look (1 means the specified directory).  The exec takes the list of files produced and runs rm on each of them.  For reference, this was discovered from &lt;a href=&quot;https://serverfault.com/questions/122824/linux-using-find-to-locate-files-older-than-date/122854#122854&quot;&gt;ServerFault&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in case you’re curious, I tested this on a system with more than 11,000 files in a single directory and it executed flawlessly — no problems at all and it cleaned up more than 5 gigs of disc space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you don’t just have to delete files of course.  If you wanted to say find all the files older than 25 days and list them out with the date and time stamp then you could use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;find /apps/cas-seas3/shared/tmp/ -mtime +10 -maxdepth 1 -exec ls -al {} \;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was how we debugged this courtesy of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/20893022/how-to-display-modified-date-time-with-find-command/20893429#20893429&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2019/05/09/linux-tip-find-all-files-older-than-10-days-and-delete-them.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/linux/2019/05/09/linux-tip-find-all-files-older-than-10-days-and-delete-them.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So You Get Ideas In the Car And Don't Want to Die</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my very best friends has a great saying “There’s no dying in xyz” and I firmly agree with her. The topic today is “I get ideas in the car and I forget them / I don’t want to die trying to write them down”.  A friend recently referenced this and this is my approach to this.  I also have a teenage son who is working on his license.  And while I will tell him “phone in glove box while driving”, I’m also realistic enough to know that he might not follow that.  And perhaps this will help him also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The safest approach is to use your phone’s voice recorder.  But the key thing is to move the voice recorder app to your home screen.  It can’t be buried on the fifth page of icons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put your phone’s notepad on your home page.  And then trigger voice to text when you get in the car.  This way if you don’t talk, it doesn’t type anything.  But it can sit there, waiting patiently for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a phone mount which attaches to your car’s dash.  I used to think these things were absolute crap – until someone made me get one and then it was like “how the hell did I live without this?”.  Happily the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00WP2A39E?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share&quot;&gt;simplest, cheapest phone mount&lt;/a&gt; I’ve seen is also fantastic.  Even if you’re not actually typing, you’d be surprised at how much this can help you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put a pen and paper in the car.  Technology sometimes fails.  Or we’re on a call and we can’t switch contexts to use an app.  Often just a jotted down keyword or two is sufficient to capture the memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/phone/2019/05/08/so-you-get-ideas-in-the-car-and-don-t-want-to-die.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/phone/2019/05/08/so-you-get-ideas-in-the-car-and-don-t-want-to-die.html</guid>
        
        <category>phone</category>
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
        
        <category>phone</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HTTPS And Your Custom Domain on Github Pages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Github for sometime now has supported https for *.github.io (aka GitHub pages).  And they have allowed it for custom domains as well.  However I was never able to figure this out until yesterday.  Here was the magic process and well as some references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My issue was that I had three “sites” hosted on GitHub pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/&quot;&gt;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/&lt;/a&gt; - my personal home page and resume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/blog/&quot;&gt;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt; - my blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/recipes/&quot;&gt;http://www.fuzzyblog.io/recipes/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to look at my online presence mostly as my blog / recipes.  I had actually forgotten that the root personal home page site even existed.  And the issues preventing me from having https working amounted to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changing the A records on my DNS provider (Amazon’s Route 53)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waiting 24 hours for a certificate to be generated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clicking the Enforce Https option on the GitHub Settings for the repo that drives fuzzyblog.io.  This has to be done first&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clicking the Enforce Https option on the GitHub Settings for all other GitHub Pages repos (for me this was blog and recipes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: If you can’t remember which git repo drives your GitHub Pages, look in the directory and file .git/config. It will be right there; look for a url / .git filename.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: In case you were wondering why you want https, there are lots of reasons but the best is that it should give your content at least a small boost in page rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recommended-reading&quot;&gt;Recommended Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the recommended tech notes from Github on all this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/en/articles/about-supported-custom-domains&quot;&gt;Supported Custom Domains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/en/articles/adding-or-removing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site&quot;&gt;Adding Custom Domains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/en/articles/troubleshooting-custom-domains#https-errors&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting Custom Domains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2018-05-01-github-pages-custom-domains-https/&quot;&gt;Press Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/https/2019/05/07/https-and-your-custom-domain-on-github-pages.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/https/2019/05/07/https-and-your-custom-domain-on-github-pages.html</guid>
        
        <category>https</category>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>GitHub</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        
        <category>https</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Managing An Attack of Hives</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/em&gt; I am not a doctor.  I am not a nurse.  I do not even play a doctor or a nurse on the Internet.  But I have been unlucky enough to suffer from poison ivy on N (N rounds up pretty high; it involves the number of fingers on both hands) occasions so I know a lot about suffering through itchiness.  And I’ve had hives myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently watched a dear, dear friend come down with hives out of the clear blue.  One day they were fine and the next day there were “an itchy, splotchy mess”.  Hives are one of those things that generally are an allergic reaction that you never quite understand.  They come over you, your life sucks beyond belief and then they go away.  As another friend would say, “How Rude!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ultimately figured out a good way to help deal with the itchiness but it took about a day so I thought I’d write down some tips and recommendations.  I know this is not the sort of content I usually produce but it made at least one person’s life better so …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;managing-hives-or-poison-ivy&quot;&gt;Managing Hives or Poison Ivy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some techniques for managing hives or poison ivy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool water; never hot.  Getting under a hot shower with an itchy condition actually feels good but it is a complete mistake. It seems to reactivate the underlying cause.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Benadryl-Ultratabs-Antihistamine-Allergy-Diphenhydramine/dp/B001F1DV72/ref=sr_1_2_sspa?keywords=benedryl&amp;amp;qid=1556977968&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-2-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Benedryl&lt;/a&gt;.  If you’re looking for a medicine and don’t mind the associated drowsiness, Benedryl really does help.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Aveeno-Soothing-Treatment-Itchy-Irritated/dp/B000UEAARO/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3GVFYJIK6BNCE&amp;amp;keywords=aveeno+oatmeal+bath&amp;amp;qid=1556977411&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=aveeno+ot%2Caps%2C138&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;Colloidal Oatmeal Bath&lt;/a&gt;.  If you have the ability to soak in a tub, a cool tub filled with the Aveeno Oatmeal works well.  Or you can make your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.verywellfamily.com/how-to-make-your-own-oatmeal-bath-289466&quot;&gt;own&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Benadryl-Relief-Spray-Extra-Strength/dp/B00MHYLOMA/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=FG56ZRO8EATG&amp;amp;keywords=spray+benedryl&amp;amp;qid=1556977467&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=spray+bene%2Caps%2C139&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;smid=ASEVS99O6FS73&quot;&gt;Spray Benadryl&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a topical spray and while it makes you sticky, it provides solid relief.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Gold-Bond-Ultimate-Eczema-Protectant/dp/B00GIHMOGW/ref=sr_1_5?keywords=gold+bond+eczema+ultimate+relief&amp;amp;qid=1556979092&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-5&quot;&gt;Gold Bond Ultimate Eczema Relief&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a colloidal oatmeal lotion and it has specific ingredients (since its an eczema solution) to “deal with the itches”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/ZANFEL-Poison-Ivy-Sumac-Wash/dp/B000GCPWUU/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?keywords=zanfel&amp;amp;qid=1556977531&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;smid=A188ED3JB77RWM&amp;amp;th=1&quot;&gt;Zanfel&lt;/a&gt;.  I listed this last but it is ABSOLUTELY THE BEST THING EVER for hives or poison ivy.  It is ridiculously expensive ($50 for a tube in downtown Chicago) but it is completely worth it.  Follow the directions exactly and it provides fantastic relief.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the recommendations above, #6, Zanfel, is the best.  You won’t want to spend the money but it really is worth it. #5 also comes very, very highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/health/2019/05/04/managing-an-attack-of-hives.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/health/2019/05/04/managing-an-attack-of-hives.html</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>hives</category>
        
        
        <category>health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting AWS Costs Under Control</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; AWS is an abbreviation for Amazon Web Services, the Amazon cloud computing platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am presently responsible for a monthly AWS budget that is running about $20,000 per month.  And that is up from about $11,000 per month only eight months ago.  I was recently tasked with bringing that down through &lt;em&gt;reserved instances&lt;/em&gt; and I thought that writing up the learnings from doing a deep dive into reserved instances and AWS Cost Control was worth writing up.  Even though I’ve worked with AWS now since 2008, I found the results of my research pretty damn surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note that when I say “responsible”, I mean that I have technical / implementation responsibility in my role as a Senior Software Engineer. I’m not actually a cost control / accounting person in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-reserved-instances&quot;&gt;What are Reserved Instances&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand is that Reserved Instances are poorly named, very poorly named.  Reserved instances are nothing more than &lt;em&gt;coupons&lt;/em&gt; for the use of an instance of the type of the coupon.  You actually aren’t reserving a specific instance but instead saying to Amazon “Ok I’ll buy this much of instance type X”.  And it is important to understand that reserved instances aren’t a simple volume discount.  They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massively complex and confusing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expensive, requiring an up front payment to get the maximum discount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Available in multiple flavors such as convertible and non convertible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complex enough that after researching them in depth you will want to drink and drink heavily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Such a big deal that there actually is a secondary market where you can resell and purchase reserved instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I looked into how much reserved instances could save us, I generally found between a 15% to 20% savings with our current approach to things.  Given our current spending rate, that could easily amount to nearly $40,000 per year.   And while that’s nothing to sneer at, my research into reserved instances told me to keep digging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most interesting thing about reserved instances with respect  to AWS cost control is that universally the recommendation I found was this: &lt;em&gt;Don’t start with reserved instances&lt;/em&gt;.  Even though reserved instances directly reduce your costs, you should never start with reserved instances.  And that brings us to the next section, AWS Cost Control Strategy.
￼
## AWS Cost Control Strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a considerable amount of research, I came up with the following approach for reducing AWS costs. Please note that where I say “we”, you should substitute your own organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need to designate someone as the person responsible for managing / monitoring AWS costs.  Right now, for example, we have a quarter of a million dollar budgetary line item that &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; is responsible for.  This isn’t a technical problem; this is an accounting problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need to correctly tag all instances by name, by product family, by application and more so that there is the metadata to properly examine and drill into costs using the AWS or third party accounting tools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need to implement a lights on / lights off strategy where you turn off resources when they aren’t in use.  As an example, our staging and training environments clusters of machines only need to be available some of the time (staging needs to be available Mon - Friday, 9 to 6 EST; training needs to be available only when specifically scheduled).  Right now all those environments are powered up and available 24x7x365.  Admittedly these aren’t as many boxes as our production environment but if you don’t have something turned on, you’re not paying for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need to implement a Right Sizing strategy where we dig into machine utilization and figure out if we’re actually using the correctly sized instances or if we are over spending by using machines that are too large.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We should only implement reserved instances when &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the above steps are implemented.  Otherwise you are over buying capacity that you likely don’t need.  Also it is not widely understood that you can buy reserved instances not only for your EC2 boxes but also for your RDS boxes; keep that firmly in mind when you plan your reserved instance purchases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally we need to realize that AWS Cost Management is a task you need to do regularly whether that is monthly, quarterly or annually.  It needs to be not only someone’s actual job (or portion of their job) but as an activity, it needs to be done consistently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools-and-recommended-reading&quot;&gt;Tools and Recommended Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tools to investigate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/instance-scheduler/&quot;&gt;AWS Instance Scheduler&lt;/a&gt; - This is a code based tool to configure turn on / turn off of your cloud instances&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parkmycloud.com&quot;&gt;Park My Cloud&lt;/a&gt; - This is a tool which can turn on / off your cloud instances automatically with an easy user interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudhealthtech.com&quot;&gt;CloudHealth&lt;/a&gt; - this is an AWS management and analytics tool with specific features for reserved instance analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudability.com&quot;&gt;CloudAbility&lt;/a&gt; - this is an AWS management and analytics tool with specific features for reserved instance analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CloudAbility and CloudHealth tools are seriously pricey, they are generally priced as a percentage of your AWS bill, but they have outstanding analytics features and the ability  to analyze your reserved instance needs more powerfully than the built in AWS tools for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the better research materials to investigate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3jhKM1rgpEw&quot;&gt;AWS Cost Optimization Levers, Tools and Strategies&lt;/a&gt;.  This is an excellent video from the AWS Australia branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L5rlqaC6uNs&quot;&gt;Saving at Scale with Reserved Instances by Cloudability&lt;/a&gt;.  This is also excellent and it illustrates two key points - a) that reserved instances can actually increase your bill and b) that you really need to have someone responsible for AWS cost control on an ongoing basis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://get.cloudability.com/rs/064-CAC-529/images/the-complete-guide-to-saving-with-aws-reserved-instances-ebook.pdf&quot;&gt;Reserved Instance Ebook&lt;/a&gt;.  A great read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/aws/2019/05/04/getting-aws-costs-under-control.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/aws/2019/05/04/getting-aws-costs-under-control.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Job Hound Feature - Create Cover Letters More Easily</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you are a product creator, there is something wonderful about building a product that people are really using and implementing a new feature that you &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; will make their lives easier.  I am very, very please to announce the new Job Hound feature Cover Letters More Easily.  Yes I know that’s an absolutely crap name but it does describe what this does.  Let me walk you through how this works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of Job Hound is an underlying database of the jobs you apply for and how successful you are with them.  Success is measured by your interactions with the job and Job Hound understands that the type of interaction that you have matters.  Every job has a number of status fields like “got_hr_screen” or “passed_technical_interview”.  As each job gains additional status fields, the underlying “score” associated with how successful you are &lt;em&gt;for this job&lt;/em&gt; grows.  And that is how Job Hound can do things like generate a report of cover letters organized by most successful to least successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s walk through the cover letter creation process as it has been and then let’s walk through it with the new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;before&quot;&gt;Before&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to create a cover letter, you start at your list of Jobs to Apply For:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_all_jobs.png&quot; alt=&quot;cover_letter_all_jobs.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you want to apply for the Eezy job so you click on it giving you the details of the job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious next step is to click on the Add Cover Letter button:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_eezy.png&quot; alt=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_eezy.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking that Add Cover Letter button takes you into the Cover Letter writer where you can see the job description but you start with a totally blank screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_blank.png&quot; alt=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_blank.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The Job Description above is something that Job Hound always tries to provide so that you can write your cover letter to respond to the requirements of the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing anything from a blank state is always harder than starting from a template so let’s see how this has been improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;with-the-new-feature&quot;&gt;With the New Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new feature you can start creating your cover letter for a job you want to apply for by going to the Successful Cover Letter report (click Report in the menu bar):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_all_reports.png&quot; alt=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_all_reports.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the Successful Cover Letters report from the links and you’ll see the report of all your cover letters organized from most successful to least successful.  In this case we want to use the Wedding Wire cover letter as a template for the job we want to apply to – Eezy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_select_from_report.png&quot; alt=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_select_from_report.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just select the Eezy job from the drop down list (yes I realize now that I didn’t show Eezy in the drop down; apologies; it is there) and click the Create Cover Letter from this button.  That will take you to the Cover Letter Writer with the selected template loaded in.  You can now adjust the the cover letter for your new job.  You’ll notice an alert message at the top that reminds you to make adjustments like the company name and job title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_create_from_template.png&quot; alt=&quot;https://jobhound.io/assets/cover_letter_create_from_template.pngg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can easily start from your list of cover letters, choose the one that works best for the job you want to apply to and instantly create a new cover letter from it.  Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jobhound/2018/05/03/new-job-hound-feature-cover-letters-from-templates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jobhound/2018/05/03/new-job-hound-feature-cover-letters-from-templates.html</guid>
        
        <category>jobhound</category>
        
        
        <category>jobhound</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anatomy of an Accidental Product Launch with Metrics - Day 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a software engineer and I am decidedly &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a marketing guy (I play one on the Internet from time to time but I really just write code).  I recently launched a side project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;Job Hound&lt;/a&gt;, that had an unexpectedly successful first day and I thought documenting it might help someone out there (and certainly help me; that’s usually why I blog anything; it helps me understand things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-job-hound&quot;&gt;What is Job Hound?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job Hound is a tool that I wrote recently as a way to “make getting a tech job suck less”.  I recently went out to get a full time gig and I found the process &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html&quot;&gt;just so plain awful&lt;/a&gt; so I wrote software as a way to put myself in control of it.  After finding it incredibly useful for my own needs, and then showing it a few friends to positive feedback, I figured that I’d throw it on a cheap Digital Ocean box and see what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;timing-for-metrics&quot;&gt;Timing for Metrics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this after the first 16 hours the product was live.  All marketing activities were done around 8 am EST.  There’s a bit in the Metrics section that gives the numbers after a full 24 hours but this was initially written at the 16 hour mark and then published a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-launch-plan&quot;&gt;My Launch “Plan”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week an article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://work.qz.com/1254663/job-interviews-for-programmers-now-often-come-with-days-of-unpaid-homework/&quot;&gt;Quartz talking about the rise in homework for job seekers&lt;/a&gt; took off on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16874015&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; with 989 comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here was my launch plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:  You should document your story on your struggle to find a job and then post it on Hacker News&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me&lt;/strong&gt;: Ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly there wasn’t more to it than that.  This isn’t a humblebrag by any means.  Someone I respect suggested it and, well, that is how it started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had about 500 words of a very crufty blog post in draft form right in my coding editor so I polished that up from 5 am to 7 am and that became my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html&quot;&gt;Ten Things I Learned from a Job Hunt for a Senior Engineering Role&lt;/a&gt; blog post.  I also submitted it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16912546#16913834&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; where over the course of the next 16 hours, it got 638 comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should point out that this is the first thing I’ve ever submitted to Hacker News that has gotten &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; traction at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did tweet my blog post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twiiter.com/fuzzygroup/&quot;&gt;my personal twitter&lt;/a&gt; and I also made a Job Hound specific tweet and then pinned the Job Hound tweet so it stayed at the top of my twitter feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly never even thought to put my blog post on Facebook.  I did that 24 hours later so I don’t have any metrics on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final launch action, one I had no hope for at all, was that I also tossed Job Hound up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/job-hound&quot;&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; where it got 56 up votes during roughly the same period (it may have been on Product Hunt 1 day longer; the whole day is kind of a blur right now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fine-tuning&quot;&gt;Fine Tuning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did relatively little tuning of the content.  My buddy Nick suggested that I emphasize the free nature of Job Hound in the blog post and that I add the Product Hunt link into the blog post.  Both of these were good ideas and done around 2 pm EST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-metrics&quot;&gt;The Metrics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since roughly 8 am this morning (sixteen hours so far), Job Hound has had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;204 user accounts created (email / password)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;98 jobs added&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An average of 0.48 jobs per user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a full 24 hours, the numbers were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;236 user accounts created (email / password)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;119 jobs added&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An average of 0.50 jobs per user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of social media metrics, I started the day with 163 twitter followers and I ended it a full 24 hours later with 187.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are these numbers good?  I think that absolutely depends on your perspective.  For a side project that I publicly launched with absolutely zero planning – I’m absolutely delighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Followup after 4 days&lt;/strong&gt;: The numbers have continued to steadily grow and I’ve gotten quite a few emails, linked in messages, tweets and other feedback that all indicates to me that I have hit on something.  My plan is that keep working Job Hound as a side project and just making it better and better.  Maybe something comes of this; maybe not but helping people get jobs is a &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;other&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received a number of emails and messages via LinkedIn and I tried to respond to everyone on the same day.  I’ve always found that talking to users is the best damn marketing you can do.  This is the root of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io/pages/thank_you&quot;&gt;Job Hound Thank You&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably wondering “what about the web traffic?”  I’m sorry to say that my Google Analytics skills just aren’t all that good so I haven’t been able to dig into them with any success as of yet.  I’m sure the data is there but I’m too brain dead to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion---content-does-work&quot;&gt;Conclusion - Content Does Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my overall conclusions from all this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating content on the Internet as a marketing tool really does work but the content has to have value of its own.  You can’t simply shill your product; embed it in something that is interesting all on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Telling a personal story works.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lucky is better than smart.  I was extremely lucky in getting coverage from Hacker News.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timing matters.  I was lucky to be able to ride a wave of hiring interest from the Quartz article.  This didn’t occur to me and it took the pushing of a good friend for me to put this out.  Thanks Nick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jobhound/2018/04/27/anatomy-of-an-accidental-product-launch-with-metrics-day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jobhound/2018/04/27/anatomy-of-an-accidental-product-launch-with-metrics-day-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>jobhound</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>metrics</category>
        
        
        <category>jobhound</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ten Things I Learned from a Job Hunt for a Senior Engineering Role</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently went on a search for a new full time gig and I learned that today’s job search is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; what it used to be.  Here’s the quick summary of what I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The job search takes much, much longer than it used to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one believes that anyone can actually code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Tests Can Trip Up Even Good Engineers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extensive homework is now normal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every company’s “process” is different&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outsourced hiring “services” are very much in vogue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Companies Really Want to Know Your Salary; Don’t tell Them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interviews Matter Much, Much More to You Than to the Company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Age discrimination really exists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll never really know why you weren’t hired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of full disclosure, at the end of this article, I’m going to pitch you on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;new tool&lt;/a&gt; I built for managing your personal job hunt, but don’t worry, it’s &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; to use.  I found the job hunt process so &lt;strong&gt;absolutely distasteful&lt;/strong&gt; that the only way I could get through it was to actually create some software based on what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-am-i&quot;&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s just a bit about myself so you can understand my job search.  I’m a senior software guy who’s still writing code after all these years.  My platform is generally Ruby / Rails and my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/resume.html&quot;&gt;resume&lt;/a&gt; is here in case you care.  I’ve been a consultant for the last few years and I wanted to get back to a full time gig in a senior engineering role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the stats from my job search:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Applied For: &lt;strong&gt;82&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Where You Got an HR Interview	&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Where You Got a Technical Interview:	&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Where You Got an Onsite Interview: &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Job Offers: &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-1-it-takes-longer-than-ever-to-get-hired&quot;&gt;Number 1: It Takes Longer than Ever to Get Hired&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in high tech a long time and other than the few really bad times, the general rule in high tech hiring has been “fill an engineering slot as fast as possible”.  The industry may talk a good game about culture fit but other than a few firms, it always has been about quickly putting bodies in seats.  That is absolutely no longer the case.  HR departments now seem to be focused on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initially getting a large number of candidates to review as the first step (and nothing, even when you seem to be a perfect requirement match, happens until they get that large group of candidates).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marching the entire group of candidates, step by step, through their entire process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Putting as many barriers in place before hiring anyone.  I discuss this more below under process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just so you’re aware, the HR departments will not own up to the process taking longer than ever.  They will spin you a song and a dance about how quickly things are going to progress and it just isn’t true.  My two observations in this area are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Companies today, despite what they might say, are pickier about candidates than ever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Companies are less willing to hire than I’ve ever seen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One helpful thing I did during my job hunt was track everything so I actually had dates all along.  Here’s an example of what I commonly saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/5 was my initial application to Company W&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/1 was when I completed my homework project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/2 was when I got scheduled for an onsite interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/23 was when I found out that I didn’t get it (two weeks after my onsite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s almost two months start to finish!  And today that job remains on the company’s web site – they still haven’t hired anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-2-no-one-believes-anyone-can-actually-code&quot;&gt;Number 2: No One Believes Anyone Can Actually Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general thing that I saw from everyone that I talked to is that no one actually believes that anyone can code.  At every stage in the interview process, you’re going to need to &lt;strong&gt;prove&lt;/strong&gt; that your resume isn’t a lie and that you can actually do what you say you can.  I find this ludicrous because it is like interviewing an attorney and then saying to him “Please prove that you can cite a Supreme Court precedent”.  When did an entire industry of people get pre-judged as lying?   Don’t we exist in a country where the default assumption is innocence not guilt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-3-coding-tests-can-trip-up-even-good-engineers&quot;&gt;Number 3: Coding Tests Can Trip Up Even Good Engineers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extremely common thing that you’re going to find as part of a job search are coding tests and I’d urge you NOT to take them lightly.  These coding tests tend to bear &lt;strong&gt;no resemblance&lt;/strong&gt; to anything you’ll do in the work place and even good engineers can get tripped up by them.  I found that part way through my job search I had to buckle down, hit the books and start practicing on different coding tests to get my scores up.  Once upon a time I would have said that any engineer should be able to pass a coding test but that’s just not true.  The longer you are in industry, I would argue the less likely you may be to pass a coding test.  I suspect I could have done much better on a coding test fresh out of college when my “test taking skills” were actually something I used.  Now?  The last test I passed was for a driver’s license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; You should note that since most tests come from an outsourced service like Codility, you can google for practice questions, sample exams and more.  And I’d strongly encourage you to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t underestimate coding tests at all.  I did and it was to my disadvantage.  You really, really need to practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-4-extensive-homework-is-now-normal&quot;&gt;Number 4: Extensive Homework is Now Normal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a hiring manager, I’ve given homework assignments to weed out candidates from the pack but I always kept it reasonable, just a few hours in length.  I’ve now regularly seen homework assignments ranging from 8 hours to “spend a week on this and really show us what you can do”.  Over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://work.qz.com/1254663/job-interviews-for-programmers-now-often-come-with-days-of-unpaid-homework/&quot;&gt;QZ&lt;/a&gt; there is an excellent article about this along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16874015&quot;&gt;984 comments on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.  And yes that’s a huge amount of comments on any one topic since the current amount of comments on the top 30 items on Hacker News is &lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be aware that your coding submission will be judged all kinds of ways, often unfairly.  For one application I built, I was told “you didn’t allow for proper performance given a 500x increase in data”. This came after being specifically told “use no technologies other than the database itself” (it was a search application). And what good engineer allows for an arbitrary 500x increase?  That is massive, unnecessary over engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; One thing that I did do to stand out from the crowd for almost all my homework assignments was to record a screencast talking through my work and illustrating what I thought were the best points.  I had several interviewers tell me that “thank you; I’ve never seen that before”.  This gets the interviewer past any issues with getting code installed / setup, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should comment that even though I don’t like the trend towards homework, I vastly prefer it to coding tests.  You shouldn’t think, however, that just because you passed the homework assignment, you won’t face a whiteboard challenge - every place I did a home assignment for, I also got a whiteboard challenge, sometimes multiple ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-5-every-companys-process-is-different&quot;&gt;Number 5: Every Company’s Process Is Different&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that getting a coding job boiled down to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send in resume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HR Screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical Interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a pretty standard process and I saw (and hired) a lot of people with this approach.  Apparently though times change and now the “process” is all over the map.  One of the most useful things I learned to ask companies early on was “Please explain your hiring process to me” and then I wrote it down for each company.  This let me know “for company X, the process is”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HR Screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Test&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical Interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical Interview with the Team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onsite Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you’re going to find is that while there are common elements (currently homework) in the hiring process, everyone’s process is different.  If you know what a company cares about then you can start to get ready before it happens.  For example, if you know in advance that you have a coding test in front of you, this lets you know that you may need to study.  If an HR person says to me “Oh and we administer a coding test” then my first response is “I’ve taken a bunch of those, which one do you use?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-6-outsourced-hiring-assessment-services-are-very-much-in-vogue&quot;&gt;Number 6: Outsourced Hiring Assessment Services Are Very Much in Vogue&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that really surprised me was how many companies rely on outsourced hiring services.  I saw this all over the place from companies that sent me a link to a coding test, often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codility.com/&quot;&gt;Codility&lt;/a&gt;, to “personality assessment” tools, often &lt;a href=&quot;www.predictiveindex.com&quot;&gt;Predictive Index&lt;/a&gt;.  I suppose this is the natural evolution of SAAS companies into the hiring space.  When I was recruiting, in years past, my HR department always strongly warned me against administering coding tests on the grounds of legal issues / fairness.  Now that these are outsourced, I suspect that HR departments aren’t concerned at all about legal issues since they come from a vendor not themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that you’ll find is that these outsourced assessment services are being stuck into the hiring process at &lt;strong&gt;ANY&lt;/strong&gt; point in the process.  I’ve seen things ranging from HR screen to initial technical interview to coding test to send in a resume and get a personality test fired back at you before you ever talk to a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-7-companies-really-want-to-know-your-salary-dont-tell-them&quot;&gt;Number 7: Companies Really Want to Know Your Salary; Don’t tell Them&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started my job search, I was lucky enough to read Josh Doody’s fabulous book &lt;a href=&quot;https://fearlesssalarynegotiation.com/&quot;&gt;Fearless Salary Negotiation&lt;/a&gt; and the best thing I got from it was “Never disclose your current salary or expectations”.  I never disclosed it but I found HR people absolutely relentless on this point.  I finally said to one California company “You do realize that legally you can’t ask me that” and they shamelessly replied “Yes I can; you aren’t in California”.  And you’ll find that there are web forms which require you to fill it in (I always put in a minimal, crazy number like 1234).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you haven’t read Josh’s book then I strongly encourage you to do so.  It is a short but fantastic read.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fearless-Salary-Negotiation-step-step/dp/0692568689/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1524566767&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=fearless+salary+negotiation&quot;&gt;Here’s an Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-8-interviews-matter-much-much-more-to-you-than-to-the-company&quot;&gt;Number 8: Interviews Matter Much, Much More to You Than to the Company&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it is entirely true that any given interview matters far more &lt;strong&gt;to you&lt;/strong&gt; than it does &lt;strong&gt;to the company&lt;/strong&gt; that is interviewing you.  Any candidate has only a relatively small number of jobs they can even apply for where as the company has all of the Internet applying (this is particularly true if the company is any good).  I couldn’t even count how many interviews companies missed, were late on, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-9-age-discrimination-is-real&quot;&gt;Number 9: Age Discrimination is Real&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: I recently turned 50 and I’m still a hands on engineer who writes code just about every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One very surprising thing to me was just how much I discovered that age discrimination in high tech hiring is real.  There were all too many times when jobs that I was an absolute perfect match for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I never got an interview at all&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was mysteriously ghosted midway though the process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got all the way to the end, nailed everything perfectly and then never found out why I didn’t get it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that you never can prove and no one will ever own up to I do think that is very, very real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;number-10-youll-never-really-know-why-you-werent-hired&quot;&gt;Number 10: You’ll Never Really Know Why You Weren’t Hired&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are lots of actually good reasons why companies don’t want to tell you why you weren’t hired but this remains my single biggest issue with today’s job hunt.  I can understand that you can’t tell everyone why they didn’t get hired but when you get to the end point and pass all these hurdles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HR Screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Test&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical Interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical Interview with the Team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onsite Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would think that more information than “We all really liked you but we went in a different direction” could be said.  I saw this repeatedly on jobs that I got all the way to the end point on.  How is a candidate ever supposed to improve themselves when the company will not tell you why you didn’t get the job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;and-heres-the-pitch-for-job-hound&quot;&gt;And Here’s the Pitch for Job Hound&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result of all this was that while I did end up with a full time job, I also ended up creating a new &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;Job Hound&lt;/a&gt; to make applying for tech jobs (generally programming) easier.  Job Hound is a job application tracking system and it puts the job application firmly in charge of the process.  I built it because after I had applied for about 15 jobs, I had no idea where I was in the process and I couldn’t give my wife a decent answer about my progress because I simply had no idea.  Job Hound isn’t a SAAS product, it is 100% free and I’d encourage you to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;My new free product is Job Hound: Make applying for tech jobs suck less!  Sign Up Today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also here is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/job-hound&quot;&gt;Job Hound on Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; in case you want to toss me an upvote.  Thanks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion-and-what-this-means-for-the-industry-and-the-job-seeker&quot;&gt;Conclusion and What this Means for the Industry and the Job Seeker&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t underestimate these changes to the hiring process and their impact on the industry as a whole.  Here’s how I see things changing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decreased job mobility&lt;/strong&gt;.  If jobs are harder to get then engineers will be less willing to change roles than they have been in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower salaries&lt;/strong&gt;.  Generally speaking the easiest way to get a raise as an engineer is to leave your job.  If jobs are harder to get then less people will leave and that will drive salaries down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Cross Pollination of Ideas&lt;/strong&gt;.  While companies may not like job mobility, I would argue that on the whole it has been good for high tech in general.  By engineers moving freely across companies, we’ve seen a great dissemination of engineering techniques and approaches.  If engineers lose job mobility then that will absolutely change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how high tech has been such a tool for job creation over the past few decades, I really don’t like the implication of these trends but I do see them as very, very real.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html</guid>
        
        <category>jobhound</category>
        
        <category>jobs</category>
        
        
        <category>jobhound</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
