<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:59:20 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:59:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding MySQL's Alter Table</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;all mysql alter tables are the same:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-a) lock table against writes
a) copy to tmp table
b) modify
c) copy back
d) unlock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so this means that at a minimum its another almost 24 hours because the copy back is as long as the copy to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;                                                |    0.000 | | 2163 | appdata | ip-172-31-47-83.us-west-2.compute.internal:55637  | banks_production                  | Sleep   |    8497 |                   | NULL                                                           |    0.000 | | 2166 | appdata | ip-172-31-45-225.us-west-2.compute.internal:39423 | banks_production                  | Query   |   75956 | copy to tmp table | ALTER TABLE `link2016_q1s` ADD `data_source` int(11) DEFAULT 1 |   16.747 | | 2173 | appdata | localhost                                         | banks_production                  | Query   |       0 | NULL              | show full proce
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:59:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/understanding-mysql-s-alter-table.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/understanding-mysql-s-alter-table.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Non Standard Numerical Metrics for Valuing Acquisitions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As you’re aware my knowledge of the marina business is very limited these days – I live in Indiana.  The one thing that I was concerned with is that Safe Harbor doesn’t have enough open positions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://safeharbormarinas.companycareersite.com/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BYY has I think actually more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.byy.com/about-employment/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve done a fair bit of work with venture capitalists helping them with due diligence and one of the ways I learned to look at companies was by their non obvious numerical metrics.  Example - if you look at the number of parking spaces a company has and then multiply by an average salary it gives you their staffing costs.  Similarly if you look at parking lots in silicon valley and you see that no one is working late / after hours, it says something about their drive to succeed (this is mostly true in pre publicly held companies).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I would tend to take the position that any company of a sufficient size has some level of structural turn over – if you have 1,000 people on staff, not all of them, by definition, can be happy.  So some measurably percentage should be in flux at any time and I would think that the number of open positions should reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway you know your business and you know how many staff they should have and the seasonality.  I don’t know if the number of open positions they have is right or wrong but from an external perspective it feels low to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love and congratulations again.  My very, very best to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:32:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/non-standard-numerical-metrics-for-valuing-acquisitions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/non-standard-numerical-metrics-for-valuing-acquisitions.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS Tutorial 016 SQL Injection</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;sql-injection&quot;&gt;SQL Injection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Student,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL Injection can be confusing to understand but it is actually very, very simple.  Let’s think about a simple web page which lets you search for something.  At the html level, this web page is going to look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Search&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;form&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;action=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/search.php&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;What do you want to search for?&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;text&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;q&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;submit&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, what we’ve got here is a form with one input element called q and a submit button.  When the submit button is pressed, an HTTP get request is sent back to the server and given the back end url /search.php.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider this in the context of a PHP application.  If you were going to process this server side then you will have a variable called $_REQUEST[“q”].  Now you might&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:28:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/cs-tutorial-016-sql-injection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/cs-tutorial-016-sql-injection.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS Tutorial 015 Storage Is Hard or Good Old dtResource Files</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(good old DtResource files),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why I use sql and mysql specifically&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineering practices are that diret code submissions normally not accepted&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:25:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/cs-tutorial-015-storage-is-hard-or-good-old-dtresource-files.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/cs-tutorial-015-storage-is-hard-or-good-old-dtresource-files.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Money with a Pressure Washer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ride your bike around the neighborhood looking for ugly sidewalks and take a picutre and make a flier and tell your story&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:23:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/making-money-with-a-pressure-washer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/making-money-with-a-pressure-washer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS Tutorial 002 - Applying O(N) to Arrays vs Regex for Name Splitting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;def self.split_full_name_iterative(full_name)
    parts = full_name.split(“ “)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;first_name_bits = []
last_name_bits = []

parts.each_with_index do |part, ctr|
  if ctr == parts.size - 1
    last_name_bits &amp;lt;&amp;lt; part
  else
    first_name_bits &amp;lt;&amp;lt; part
  end
end

return first_name_bits.join(&quot; &quot;), last_name_bits.join(&quot; &quot;)   end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def self.split_full_name_regex(full_name)
    first_name = ‘’
    last_name = ‘’
    full_name.scan(/(.+) ([^ ]+)$/){ first_name = $1; last_name = $2;}
    return first_name, last_name
  end&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:17:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/cs-tutorial-002-applying-o-n-to-arrays-vs-regex-for-name-splitting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/cs-tutorial-002-applying-o-n-to-arrays-vs-regex-for-name-splitting.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Start Learnings - Two Thinks that Betsy Devine Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two levels - 7 degrees of separation to a Nobel Prize Winner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the surface and when confronted with celebrity, well, its easy to only see the surface.  There’s a deeper lesson here – WMBHD - What Might Betsy Have Done?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 07:17:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/14/start-learnings-two-thinks-that-betsy-devine-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/14/start-learnings-two-thinks-that-betsy-devine-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perhaps My Proudest Moment as a Father</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My youngest son, M, spent a fair bit of Saturday with me.  We went to Menard’s, a local DIY store, for a table top for my new desk and then we went to the playground at his school afterwards.  A trip to buy carpentry is never a short trip - lumber has to be evaluated, a finish has to be selected from the 1000 odd different types of polyurethane* that they sell, the tool aisle has to be perused, etc.  So for a ten year old boy, with a deep and abiding love for is iPad Mini, this is likely as close to one of Dante’s circles as you might find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suprisingly, at the end of the trip, he turned to me and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dad - they say that a dog is man’s best friend; I say that a Dad is man’s best friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still glowing / thrilled / elated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Hint: Minwax One Coat Water Based Polyurethane is absolutely brilliant.  Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/fatherhood/2016/11/14/perhaps-my-proudest-moment-as-a-father.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/fatherhood/2016/11/14/perhaps-my-proudest-moment-as-a-father.html</guid>
        
        <category>fatherhood</category>
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
        <category>max</category>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
        <category>fatherhood</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PostMac Linux Take 2 - Ubuntu Mate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, alas, Elementary OS was not what I had hoped it to be.  While I absolutely loved the look and feel, I found the stability lacking.  All too many times I would find my Macbook Pro running Elementary just locked hard.  And stability is a big deal for me.  I usually have uptime readings on OSX of 3 months or more.  Right now I’m at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;uptime
 6:28  up 19 days, 22:08, 58 users, load averages: 9.12 13.01 9.51
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to have uptime of less than 2 days – ever – was just unacceptable.  Now this might have been from my hardware or my video drivers, I never did troubleshoot it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond stability I found a few UI things questionable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The decision to eliminate the menu bar from applications bothered me a lot; there’s a lot of subtle functionality that you can’t get to now.  Example - I couldn’t recover the history from Chrome after a crash because I couldn’t get to that menu item.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No screen saver or dimming of the second monitor (no dimming is understandable at this distro’s stage); no screensaver?  Sheesh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No support for crash recovery in the default browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond questionable, I absolutely detest the scrollbar approach.  A scrollbar is supposed to give you a visual queue as to how far you are through content.  This “let’s make it small and then show up dynamically crap” is like someone walked over to the brilliant work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrollbar#History_and_Progression&quot;&gt;Alan Kay’s SmallTalk team&lt;/a&gt; and peed all over it.  Sigh.  I get that on Mobile real estate is so precious that scroll bars have to change.  This is NOT mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this makes me sad because I really loved the look and feel.  Elementary OS is really onto something but I don’t think its there yet for industrial computing like I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To eliminate the hardware from the equation I picked up an Intel NUC and I’ve about to install Ubuntu Mate on it.  Here’s the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Mate is a bit of a retro distro; Gnome 2 not 3.  They describe it as traditional desktop and that doesn’t sound all bad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to make the &lt;a href=&quot;https://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-create-a-bootable-ubuntu-usb-drive-for-pc-on-a-mac--cms-21187&quot;&gt;USB Installer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where to download &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu-mate.org/download/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Mate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you goto download the 64 bit version, confusingly, it is described as AMD.  Since I was dropping this on an Intel box I was surprised.  Apparently AMD is the default term for a 64 bit architecture.  I guess I blinked thru that industry change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been contemplating installing OSX on this but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2016/10/29/Post-Mac#c1477858058.300020&quot;&gt;Kevin Burton’s description of using Ubuntu on modern hardware&lt;/a&gt; appealed to me – “It’s INSANELY powerful. It’s like using god’s computer.”  A NUC isn’t that powerful but I’m curious how much Ubuntu versus OSX accounts for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/11/13/postmac-linux-take-2-ubuntu-mate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/11/13/postmac-linux-take-2-ubuntu-mate.html</guid>
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>ubuntu</category>
        
        <category>mate</category>
        
        <category>elementary</category>
        
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going Deeper - Debugging Saml</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post expands on my current interest in &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/saml/2016/10/28/understanding-saml-and-sso.html&quot;&gt;SAML&lt;/a&gt; with a more detailed investigation of SAML, IdP versus SP initiation and how you actually debug it.  In the process of writing this, I reached out to two companies that support SAML in their products and I wanted to express a special thanks to Scott G at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtouch.com/&quot;&gt;MindTouch&lt;/a&gt; who did an absolutely fantastic job of answering questions – honestly the best technical support I’ve received in years.  Kudos and thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tools-for-working-on-saml&quot;&gt;Tools for Working on SAML&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the tools for working on SAML that I recently learned about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/digidentity/libsaml&quot;&gt;libsaml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firefox SAML Tracer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chrome SAML Tracer (not as good)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.samltool.com/decode.php&quot;&gt;The SAML Decoder&lt;/a&gt;.  The UI here sucks blue monkey chunks but it does the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;not-all-vendors-are-created-equal&quot;&gt;Not All Vendors are Created Equal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I worked with SAML, my context was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was creating the IdP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One vendor (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtouch.com/&quot;&gt;MindTouch&lt;/a&gt;) I worked with had us in a SP init role where they would push login stuff to us&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another vendor (who shall not be named) I worked with had us in an IdP init role where we would push login stuff to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience between the two was night and day different.  The SP Init role vendor was a dream to work with and their product line was so astonishingly forgiving and pleasant that it would tell the errors and how far it got.  The other vendor, well, you had to ask your project manager for each error one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;examples-of-how-to-make-a-ui-that-uses-saml&quot;&gt;Examples of How to Make a UI that Uses SAML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are examples of a great SAML user interface for a developer.  This is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtouch.com/&quot;&gt;MindTouch&lt;/a&gt;.  Whether we get a success or a failure there’s enough context for the developer to actually understand what’s happening:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/great_saml_ui_mind_touch_saml_success.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
If you have the debug tracer on then you can see the whole SAML transaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/saml_great_ui_shows_errors.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
If you hit errors part way thru a SAML transaction then you can see at least as far as you got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/saml_success_but_no_access.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
If you are requesting a page which requires administrative access you don’t have then you’ll get logged in but blocked access to the requested resource.  See below under “Local Users Haven’t Gone Away - Local Login Has Gone Away”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;debugging-a-saml-transaction&quot;&gt;Debugging a SAML Transaction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first thing you want to do if you’re debugging saml stuff is use FireFox and get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjS3Lbu3pPQAhVL0oMKHTOtAwgQFggdMAA&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Faddons.mozilla.org%2Fen-US%2Ffirefox%2Faddon%2Fsaml-tracer%2F&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHN7JDX_TkQIZOiPV2tMSVDyfgwkA&quot;&gt;SAML tracer&lt;/a&gt; plugin.  This tool shows you the SAML back and forth flow and it is absolutely brilliant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/saml_tracer.png&quot; alt=&quot;saml_tracer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Scott G was helping me, his first suggestion was “Ok – go and get the FireFox SAML tracer” and with that we were off to the races.  Good tools always make things better and this was excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/saml-chrome-panel/paijfdbeoenhembfhkhllainmocckace?hl=en&quot;&gt;Chrome SAML tool&lt;/a&gt; which I haven’t tried yet.  It doesn’t appear to be as complete as SAML Tracer since it only supports post requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;local-users-havent-gone-away---local-login-has-gone-away&quot;&gt;Local Users Haven’t Gone Away - Local Login Has Gone Away&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to understand about SAML is that local users, at the level of the Service Provider, have not gone away.  What has gone away is &lt;strong&gt;local login&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;local passwords&lt;/strong&gt;.  Your application will, almost certainly, still have a local set of users that you have to administer.  This becomes most apparent when you want to grant administrative rights to a user who has logged in via saml.  Even my SAML poster child for a great implementation, MindTouch, says this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Can I automatically seat users as pro members?
Users cannot be seated by a SAML assertion. A user must be explicitly seated by an administrator using the control panel. If automatic seating is required, this can be accomplished via our API.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://success.mindtouch.com/Documentation/MindTouchResponsive/Authentication/Authenticate_via_SSO/Implement_SAML_SSO?=&quot;&gt;Mindtouch Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way that admin rights are granted to a SAML user is that the Service Provider has an admin tool where a user can be located by whatever is the unique identifier for a user (generally email or username) and then administrative rights are granted to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;idp-versus-sp-initiation&quot;&gt;IdP versus SP Initiation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first get involved with SAML one of the initial things you’ll be asked is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;IdP init or SP Init?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may remember from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/saml/2016/10/28/understanding-saml-and-sso.html&quot;&gt;last post on SAML&lt;/a&gt;, IdP is the identity provider, the bit of software that owns the user information and SP is the service provider, the bit of software that us trying to use identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really, really big deal in the SAML community and what sounds like a network protocol question is actually a &lt;strong&gt;user flow&lt;/strong&gt; question that centers on a chicken and egg issue of what happens first.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webhp?sourceid=chrome-instant&amp;amp;ion=1&amp;amp;espv=2&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#q=saml%20idp%20vs%20sp%20initiated&quot;&gt;almost 7,000 results&lt;/a&gt; in Google for this very simple thing indicates just how many people are confused about it.  As always Stack Overflow has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/12779532/differences-between-sp-initiated-sso-and-idp-initiated-sso&quot;&gt;great page on this topic&lt;/a&gt; but let me try and paraphrase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For IdP Init:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best advice I can give you is read &lt;a href=&quot;http://saml.xml.org/wiki/idp-initiated-single-sign-on-post-binding&quot;&gt;this old web page&lt;/a&gt;.  When I found this and implemented it exactly this way then IdP Init just fell in to place for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For SP init:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The user starts on a url on the service provider and when access is needed they are pushed BACK to the IdP to a special login page which is run by the SAML side of the house.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A SAML assertion is generated and pushed to the SP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the assertion is valid the user is granted access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the rub from a technical perspective: &lt;strong&gt;IdP Init is MUCH MUCH HARDER&lt;/strong&gt;.  When you are doing IdP Init you need to do all the low level SAML junk yourself.  When you are doing SP init then they do the SAML junk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to illustrate how much work the SP versus IdP approach changes things, you should look at these two configuration UIs below.  One is for SP Init and one is for IdP Init.  The IdP Init one is trivial to configure – all you have to do is set a few urls.  The SP Init one is much harder to configure – it requires your certificate and more low level details.  But there’s an inversion here – the more complex it is to configure the SP, the less code you have to write yourself.  Repeat that after me – the less code you have to write.  I got the SP Init up and running in a matter of hours.  The IdP init took days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration-screen-when-you-are-the-idp-and-the-sp-wants-sp-init&quot;&gt;Configuration Screen when You Are the IdP And the SP wants SP Init&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/mindtouch_saml_config.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration-screen-when-you-are-the-idp-and-the-sp-wants-idp-init&quot;&gt;Configuration Screen when You Are the IdP and the SP wants IdP Init&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/saml_idp_init_configuration.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;example-of-a-saml-assertion-when-you-are-the-idp-pushing-to-an-sp&quot;&gt;Example of a SAML Assertion When You Are the IdP Pushing to an SP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a full example of a SAML assertion.  This, if you updated the time stamps, would correctly validate (a few urls have been changed, however):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;samlp:Response xmlns:samlp=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:protocol&quot; ID=&quot;_a4f7e48e0-88e7-0134-4eb1-22000ab35e7b&quot; Version=&quot;2.0&quot; IssueInstant=&quot;2016-11-10T19:21:13.116Z&quot; Destination=&quot;https://community-staging.foo.com/auth/saml/SSO&quot; Consent=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:consent:unspecified&quot; &amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;Issuer xmlns=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:assertion&quot;&amp;gt;http://sso.foo.com/saml/auth&amp;lt;/Issuer&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;samlp:Status&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;samlp:StatusCode Value=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:status:Success&quot;/&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/samlp:Status&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;Assertion xmlns=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:assertion&quot; ID=&quot;_a4f7e4b30-88e7-0134-4eb1-22000ab35e7b&quot; IssueInstant=&quot;2016-11-10T19:21:13.116Z&quot; Version=&quot;2.0&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;Issuer&amp;gt;http://sso.foo.com/saml/auth&amp;lt;/Issuer&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;ds:Signature xmlns:ds=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/09/xmldsig#&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;ds:SignedInfo xmlns:ds=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/09/xmldsig#&quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ds:CanonicalizationMethod Algorithm=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2001/10/xml-exc-c14n#&quot;/&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ds:SignatureMethod Algorithm=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/09/xmldsig#rsa-sha1&quot;/&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ds:Reference URI=&quot;#_a4f7e4b30-88e7-0134-4eb1-22000ab35e7b&quot;&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;ds:Transforms&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ds:Transform Algorithm=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/09/xmldsig#enveloped-signature&quot;/&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ds:Transform Algorithm=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2001/10/xml-exc-c14n#&quot;/&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;/ds:Transforms&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;ds:DigestMethod Algorithm=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/09/xmldsig#sha1&quot;/&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;ds:DigestValue&amp;gt;IxemD9eHnPTFaA9Th4+2mQncXuI=&amp;lt;/ds:DigestValue&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/ds:Reference&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ds:SignedInfo&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;ds:SignatureValue&amp;gt;jrTDXKvv2wevCIIJ48gL1kIvgBwMMtl+RO6wligTVQp7iYglReUIKdnEZo9vuFucd+ocWkg7EQ3N3WWsZiBvyVGTJ80jC8QRTD+CtTEEMMVgtS2BkLFUv7gfH5yZ9Affk+qF+uAEK4Ij2Zy+0Zq6jleQlUTyCoZNDOFzNF1zWHo=&amp;lt;/ds:SignatureValue&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;KeyInfo xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/09/xmldsig#&quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ds:X509Data&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;ds:X509Certificate&amp;gt;MIICrzCCAhgCCQCAZjKq3Nb4xTANBgkqhkiG9w0BAQsFADCBmzELMAkGA1UEBhMCVVMxCzAJBgNVBAgMAkNBMRUwEwYDVQQHDAxSZWR3b29kIENpdHkxEDAOBgNVBAoMB0ludGVybmExFDASBgNVBAsMC0VuZ2luZWVyaW5nMRowGAYDVQQDDBFzc28uaW50ZXJhbmlhLmNvbTEkMCIGCSqGSIb3DQEJARYVc2pvaG5zb25AaW50ZXJhbmEuY29tMB4XDTE2MTEwMzExMDAwN1oXDTE3MTEwMzExMDAwN1owgZsxCzAJBgNVBAYTAlVTMQswCQYDVQQIDAJDQTEVMBMGA1UEBwwMUmVkd29vZCBDaXR5MRAwDgYDVQQKDAdJbnRlcm5hMRQwEgYDVQQLDAtFbmdpbmVlcmluZzEaMBgGA1UEAwwRc3NvLmludGVyYW5pYS5jb20xJDAiBgkqhkiG9w0BCQEWFXNqb2huc29uQGludGVyYW5hLmNvbTCBnzANBgkqhkiG9w0BAQEFAAOBjQAwgYkCgYEA1NaloseOtTva09VahTNozzHbO6rpuT7/FpQOi3eHKWwU4zHgEvOI2biUkTRYocZkunilBxqtTrCgbDay4MqXFykt+lKujnV10OG4+cVUxds8a50nkHXVbpMC48m5gfkUfut4EIURE5RHjLJ/nCpgC67QUl1/ztkFvJaNDJeWoQMCAwEAATANBgkqhkiG9w0BAQsFAAOBgQCTkZmrFEhmW4MoX6OovuKwCNwQBWPXju/po8d7YTVpRf7tIfGsD/4x8jBgUaeSPQ4QXCMQqB6244win3u1veVQd5UYRP37RteEP+F302Gw2MbOl2fYUQoSwINayWA/CinYBQAlzTAJovIsc/P8dNFUsSQzqme2aF1nIuH3h/8/Kg==&amp;lt;/ds:X509Certificate&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/ds:X509Data&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/KeyInfo&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/ds:Signature&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;Subject&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;NameID Format=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:nameid-format:transient&quot;&amp;gt;scott_johnson&amp;lt;/NameID&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;SubjectConfirmation Method=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:cm:bearer&quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;SubjectConfirmationData NotOnOrAfter=&quot;2016-11-10T19:25:13.116Z&quot; Recipient=&quot;https://community-staging.foo.com/auth/saml/SSO&quot;/&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/SubjectConfirmation&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/Subject&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;Conditions NotBefore=&quot;2016-11-10T19:21:13.116Z&quot; NotOnOrAfter=&quot;2016-11-10T20:07:13.116Z&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;AudienceRestriction&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Audience&amp;gt;https://community-staging.foo.com/auth/saml&amp;lt;/Audience&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/AudienceRestriction&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/Conditions&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;AttributeStatement&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;Attribute Name=&quot;email&quot; NameFormat=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:attrname-format:uri&quot; FriendlyName=&quot;email&quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;AttributeValue&amp;gt;sjohnson@foo1.com&amp;lt;/AttributeValue&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/Attribute&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;Attribute Name=&quot;first_name&quot; NameFormat=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:attrname-format:uri&quot; FriendlyName=&quot;first_name&quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;AttributeValue&amp;gt;Scott&amp;lt;/AttributeValue&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/Attribute&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;Attribute Name=&quot;last_name&quot; NameFormat=&quot;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:attrname-format:uri&quot; FriendlyName=&quot;last_name&quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;AttributeValue&amp;gt;Johnson&amp;lt;/AttributeValue&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/Attribute&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/AttributeStatement&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;AuthnStatement AuthnInstant=&quot;2016-11-10T19:21:13.116Z&quot; SessionIndex=&quot;_a4f7e4b30-88e7-0134-4eb1-22000ab35e7b&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;AuthnContext&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;AuthnContextClassRef&amp;gt;urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:ac:classes:PasswordProtectedTransport&amp;lt;/AuthnContextClassRef&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/AuthnContext&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/AuthnStatement&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/Assertion&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/samlp:Response&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing to understand about SAML assertions is that they are very, very precise – you have to exactly and correctly match values between the assertion, the response and the metadata signature.  So when you have a problem you need to look for mis-matches.  Even when you think they aren’t there they likely are.  SAML, for all of its difficulty, is a well thought out, time tested standard.  It is more likely that you have an implementation problem than SAML itself being broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;example-of-a-debugging-flow&quot;&gt;Example of a Debugging Flow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start to do this a lot you need to think hard about how to make your debugging flow easier.  I burned a lot of time thinking that I was &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; there.  And if you’re almost there then why do you need to make debugging easy?  Well, honestly, I probably had another 50+ odd debugging sessions before I actually got there.  I finally ended up writing a simple rake task which generated the SAML assertion I needed to validate so instead of logging into a web ui, tailing logs, capturing base64 encoded data, pasting it into ruby as a string, decoding it and then using an editor to make it viewable, I could just type something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle exec rake saml:go1 --trace
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot express what a huge improvement that was.  So, even if you think you’re almost there, you’re likely not and you should work on your debugging tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you’re going to do it the hard way then Base64.decode64(encoded_assertion) is your very best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;writing-your-own-idp&quot;&gt;Writing Your Own IdP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve open sourced &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/saml_idp&quot;&gt;my fork of the Ruby IdP&lt;/a&gt; I based this all on and I’ll be updating it at least somewhat regularly.  I put a bunch of advice on the home page there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 16:47:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/11/going-deeper-debugging-saml.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/11/going-deeper-debugging-saml.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
