<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff.  Ruby / Rails / Elixir.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 04:00:24 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 04:00:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software Worth Purchasing 02 - Enpass</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Password Managers are one of those categories of tools that provoke fierce debate among us nerd folk.  Personally now that I’ve figured out how to remember a different password for every web site I log into, I’ve needed one less than I used to but the recent move to a monthly billing plan for 1 Password just plain made me furious.  Not only is that ridiculous but 1 Password, at least in my experience, doesn’t work worth a damn.  I spent the time and money to buy it for my wife and myself about a year 
ago and we had nothing but problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The task that flipped my need for a password manager was actually traveling to the recent Elixir Conf and realizing at the airport that I don’t know my TSA Pre number:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And even if I knew it where in the rabbit’s maze of tiny text files that surround my daily life would it go?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then would I really pull out a whole laptop at the airport just to get it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then even if it was in a text file how would I get it onto my phone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly a way to store information securely was needed.  A discussion on Hacker News of the 1 Password billing changes led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enpass.io/&quot;&gt;Enpass&lt;/a&gt; and I tried it.  And it worked.  Not only did it give me a way to store away my passwords but it nicely solved the TSA Pre number storage needs.  Their business model is that desktop is free they only charge for mobile when you need to sync beyond either 10 or 20 passwords.  They charge on a lifetime model which is likely a mistake and will definitely cause them business model issues over time but it is a great little product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and I recently tested out their support and got an answer all the way from India where it is written in about a half hour which is fantastic considering the time zone.  And the answer was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an endorsement if anyone over at Enpass wants a quote for their website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Enpass is a fantastic product.  It is the first password manager that not only works but works consistently well.  I’m now using it across my laptop, iPhone and iPad and am just delighted with it.  And they have great support.  &lt;strong&gt;Recommended&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_worth_purchasing/2016/09/15/software-worth-purchasing-02-enpass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_worth_purchasing/2016/09/15/software-worth-purchasing-02-enpass.html</guid>
        
        <category>software</category>
        
        <category>tools</category>
        
        <category>password_managers</category>
        
        
        <category>software_worth_purchasing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails2Elixir - Generating a New Elixir Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things where there isn’t a direct equivalent in the Rails world.  To generate a new Rails project you, of course, use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rails new
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that brings in, well, Rails.  And all of the plethora of stuff that entails.  What if you just wanted to generate a standalone application say a page fetcher that talked to Redis and got back a url to fetch so you could store it away.  In that case you wouldn’t want all of the whole Rails stack.  You might want say just redis or just rake but not everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As discussed previously, mix is the integrated version of rails, rake and bundler and that’s what we’re going to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix new page_fetcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that will work but if you really want something reliable – and if you don’t, why would you bother with Elixir at all – then you really want to add a supervision tree which makes this an OTP application.  OTP is the core Erlang libraries that related to building distributed, reliable code.  Here’s how to do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix new page_fetcher --sup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the official reference to &lt;a href=&quot;http://elixir-lang.org/docs/stable/mix/Mix.Tasks.New.html&quot;&gt;mix new&lt;/a&gt; in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails2elixir/2016/09/15/generating-a-new-elixir-project.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails2elixir/2016/09/15/generating-a-new-elixir-project.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails2elixir</category>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        
        <category>rails2elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elixir Tutorial 02 - Adding Redis Support to our Page Fetcher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails2elixir/2016/09/15/generating-a-new-elixir-project.html&quot;&gt;last elixir post&lt;/a&gt; I documented how to generate a standalone Elixir project for a page fetcher.  Technically that would have been Elixir Tutorial 01 but I’m too tired right now to go back and rename it since this is my middle of the night, can’t sleep coding time while on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a description of what we’re planning to build.  What is a page fetcher?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A page fetcher is a bit of software that pulls content (pages) from the Internet and stores them some where for processing by something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do we actually need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bit of software that runs reliably&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And doesn’t require writing low level libraries as we’re just not there yet with our Elixir skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And pulls content from Redis that describes what to fetch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And fetches a page off from a url&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And stores it away for processing.  Likely in a database or some such place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t sound so hard, does it?  Here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/artemeff/exredis&quot;&gt;redis library&lt;/a&gt; we’re going to use.  Let’s start by adding redis support to what we generated last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change into your working directory.  For me that is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/me/fuzzygroup/elixir/page_fetcher
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run mix test to make sure everything is still working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix test    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the file mix.exs in your editor and add the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;:exredis,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;gt;= 0.2.4&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This needs to go between the [] in the defp deps routine.  Think of it this way – you are updating Gemfile.  That’s all this is.  Only its a more reliable Gemfile without the cruft and crap of bundler.  I love you Ruby but good lord the packaging infrastructure lately blows monkey chunks.  Not a day goes by that I don’t hit some Gemfile / bundler crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run mix test again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’re going to see a failure like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sjohnson@ScottJohnsonMacbookAir:~/me/fuzzygroup/elixir/page_fetcher$ mix test
Unchecked dependencies for environment test:
* exredis (Hex package)
  the dependency is not available, run &quot;mix deps.get&quot;
** (Mix) Can't continue due to errors on dependencies
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’re going to do what I think of as the &lt;em&gt;deps dance&lt;/em&gt; and type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix deps.get
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’ll see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A new Hex version is available (0.13.0), please update with `mix local.hex`
Running dependency resolution
Dependency resolution completed
  eredis: 1.0.8
  exredis: 0.2.5
* Getting exredis (Hex package)
  Checking package (https://repo.hex.pm/tarballs/exredis-0.2.5.tar)
  Fetched package
* Getting eredis (Hex package)
  Checking package (https://repo.hex.pm/tarballs/eredis-1.0.8.tar)
  Fetched package    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mileage may vary with respect to the “please update …” stuff.  Please bear in mind that Hex isn’t perfect at present.  I’ve see issues but they are few and far between at least in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step up is to modify your project to talk to your Redis server.  Do that by modifying config/config.exs with your server params.  Here are mine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;config :exredis,
  host: &quot;127.0.0.1&quot;,
  port: 6379,
  password: &quot;&quot;,
  db: 0,
  reconnect: :no_reconnect,
  max_queue: :infinity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re connecting on 127.0.0.1 you need to run this on the same machine where your redis server lives or adjust the ip address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always when you change anything run your test suite which will compile your code and show you any errors.  Here’s what mine looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix test
==&amp;gt; eredis (compile)
Compiled src/eredis_sub.erl
Compiled src/eredis_parser.erl
Compiled src/eredis_sub_client.erl
Compiled src/basho_bench_driver_erldis.erl
Compiled src/eredis.erl
Compiled src/basho_bench_driver_eredis.erl
Compiled src/eredis_client.erl
==&amp;gt; exredis
Compiling 5 files (.ex)
Generated exredis app
==&amp;gt; page_fetcher
Compiling 1 file (.ex)
Generated page_fetcher app
.

Finished in 0.05 seconds
1 test, 0 failures

Randomized with seed 697093    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at this point we have an elixir application with a supervision tree for reliability and a redis client.  Given that I’m a strong believer in “deploy early; deploy often”, I’ll handle getting all this deployed onto an Ubuntu server.  After that I’ll tackle getting this to run continuously popping things from the redis queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All code can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/elixir_page_fetcher&quot;&gt;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/elixir_page_fetcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/15/elixir-tutorial-02-adding-redis-support-to-our-page-fetcher.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/15/elixir-tutorial-02-adding-redis-support-to-our-page-fetcher.html</guid>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dad - Why Do You Read the Newspaper?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My youngest son has taken to asking me questions.  And, since he’s my son, I find them infinitely interesting and they make me &lt;strong&gt;think&lt;/strong&gt;.  He isn’t really cognizant of my blogging at present nor do I find it necessary for him to know.  After all, what I write about, isn’t of general interest; I’m nerd folk  Still I like to think that on some far off distant day he finds this on the Internet and knows that Dad actually listened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a reader of print newspapers all my life but I only got serious about it when I changed my major in college from mechanical engineering to management.  One of my first professors, intro to accounting, said to all of us in class “If you’re a serious student of business then you read the Wall Street Journal” and, to this very day, &lt;em&gt;I read the Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;.  I don’t always read every page but I try to at least skim it.  Sometimes it might take me a week or more to get to a back log of papers but I do actually get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my son looks at me, reading a physical paper, and I suspect he thinks something like this”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They just get thrown out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have an iPad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Behind the times Dad, behind the times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They’re expensive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not customized to what you care about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in some ways he is definitely right.  The Wall Street Journal is expensive.  And it isn’t searchable and, as a physical artifact, it has tons of problems.  But the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadsheet&quot;&gt;broadsheet&lt;/a&gt; newspaper format has evolved over literally hundreds of years to its present form.  And I would argue that the broadsheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the fastest way to come up to speed on an knowledge domain that changes constantly (i.e. Daily news)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doesn’t limit me to &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; information that agrees with me; that’s vitally important in this world of micro-focused content.  No one should only read about things that agree with them.  Example - I may or may not like either Hillary or Donald but as an informed citizen I should know the issues for each so that any decision I make come November is actually an informed one.  Ever since I’ve followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fuzzygroup&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; aggressively I can see both the pros and cons of a world where you only follow things that agree with you and what a damn &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Echo_chamber_(media)&quot;&gt;echo chamber&lt;/a&gt; it can be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It keeps me informed in a knowledge domain that I can talk to literally anyone about.  Much of what I actually care about in this world is so bloody obscure(1) that who in the real (i.e. physical) world am I ever going to discuss it with?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more responsible you are, and I’m a husband and father who internalized catholic(2) levels responsibility back when I was in single digits, I find it all the more important to keep up to date on things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A good newspaper, say the New York Times or Wall Street Journal, even today is still tremendously well written and like anyone who writes, I can appreciate a well written bit of content whether or not I’m explicitly interested in the topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example - Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Open Source / AWS.  I live in Indiana.  Most folks here don’t know what any of that is and the chance of discussing pros and cons of functional programming with anyone I know in the real world except for &lt;a href=&quot;http://work.stevegrossi.com/&quot;&gt;Steve Grossi&lt;/a&gt; ranges from slim to none.  And he and I don’t run in the same social circles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was raised episcopalian or the closet thing to Catholic since &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Episcopal_Church&quot;&gt;episcopal&lt;/a&gt; means “American version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_England&quot;&gt;Church of England&lt;/a&gt;”.  Anyway as a husband and father, I view it as my role to understand what’s going on in the world and be able to explain things like “Dad - what is ISIS?”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/dad_why_do_you/2016/09/15/dad-why-do-you-read-the-newspaper.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/dad_why_do_you/2016/09/15/dad-why-do-you-read-the-newspaper.html</guid>
        
        <category>dad_why_do_you</category>
        
        <category>m</category>
        
        
        <category>dad_why_do_you</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings - What Kevin Burton Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I got to know &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/burtonator&quot;&gt;Kevin Burton&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spinn3r.com/&quot;&gt;Spinn3r&lt;/a&gt; fame back in my Feedster days and while I don’t know him tremendously well, I absolutely learned from him.  Interestingly, unlike a lot of my Silicon Valley contacts where I learned from them at the time, the learnings from Kevin came later, much later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classic valley business model is what I’d describe as “up or out” i.e. you either get big fast become wildly successful or your flame out.  Either way you either go up or you go out.  But what if you are actually passionate about what you do?  What if you don’t want to go out or even to get tremendously big?  What if you want to do the kind of work you love and that you are great at?  Well, while in Silicon Valley, this would generally be viewed with derision as a “lifestyle business”, there isn’t anything wrong with it.  Hell, running a business successfully for years at a time, is a hell of an accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin is a search engine guy and he’s smart.  He’s at the level of understanding that can be described as “Let’s write the search engine from scratch”.  Now that is &lt;strong&gt;smart&lt;/strong&gt;.  And when I first got to know him back in 2005 / 2006, he was just getting started with Spinn3r and he’s still at it.  He’s building a great product that solves a real problem.  And he’s even become a part of academia in being cited in over &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=spinn3r&quot;&gt;350 papers&lt;/a&gt; that are studying the rise of the social web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s what I learned from Kevin Burton:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do what you love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love the myth of the overnight success but real life isn’t like that.  Succeeding at anything takes copious amounts of time and persistence.  Doing what you love makes persistence easier and Kevin has taught that to me in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/14/starting-learnings-what-kevin-burton-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/09/14/starting-learnings-what-kevin-burton-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>learnings</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>iPad for Productivity Take Two</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ipad/2016/09/13/is-an-ipad-a-serious-productivity-tool.html&quot;&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I posited that an iPad could be a serious productivity tool and I later realized “well that’s interesting and all but have you really ever created anything on one?”  So to quell my inner self doubt, I set out to try and even though I had my laptop right next to me, I opted to use my iPad and, in about an hour, I had produced 1091 words of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/parenting/2016/09/14/childhood-memories.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.  No real need to read it – it is a personal piece on parenting and childhood.  Not my average bit of word flow but something that just raced off my finger tips in an inspiring flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Given that I was sitting in the dark next to a sick child as I wrote this, the fact that I could do it so quickly even using a less than perfect keyboard says something.  And while I say less than perfect, that doesn’t mean its bad.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Belkin-QODE-Ultimate-Keyboard-Black/dp/B00Q5CZ0LQ/ref=sr_1_1?s=pc&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1473849549&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=belkin+qode&quot;&gt;Belkin keyboard&lt;/a&gt; I’m using is as good as I’ve found and I really do love it.  The editor I used was &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/notesy-for-dropbox/id386095500?mt=8&quot;&gt;Notesy for Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; and its seamless sync meant that I could write on the iPad and then do a cat ~/me/notesy/childhood_memories.txt&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;pbcopy to let me paste it into TextMate on my mac for final editing before using Jekyll to publish it.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notesy is actually quite good.  It is vastly better than editors I used to live in like ScripSit on a TRS-80 Model I where everything I wrote from high school thru my first two years of college was published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I put my money where my mouth is and I actually did create content using nothing but an iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ipad/2016/09/14/ipad-for-productivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ipad/2016/09/14/ipad-for-productivity.html</guid>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>ipad</category>
        
        
        <category>ipad</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Childhood Memories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing this at 4 am sitting by my youngest’s bedside,  Yesterday was a fabulous day from the parents perspective and from his I suspect had a &lt;em&gt;high degree of suck&lt;/em&gt;.  We are at DisneyWorld right now and my wife arranged for us to take an end of day safari.  This is a new offering from DisneyWorld’s Animal Kingdom and it was a limited person safari (just 10 people) that finished with a private meal on a viewing platform in the middle of Animal Kingdom’s Serengeti area.  We had a fantastic guide, Jason, who was not only knowledgeable but just plain beyond entertaining.  My boys liked him so well that they even wanted his picture with him at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the animals we saw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;birds, birds, birds and more birds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;giraffes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wildebeests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;elephants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;zebras&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;springboks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a rhino&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hyenas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rabbits (ok Florida native but still, bunnies!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lions sitting proudly out in the rain - clearly not water phobic house cats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s just what I can blearily remember as I’m sitting up with him.  On the way back there was even a torrential rainstorm and it made off us feel like we were in deepest Africa.  My oldest kept making media references like 
“Jurassic Park” and others.  And, according to our guide, rain brings out the critters and it sure did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, you ask, if the boys liked it so well would my youngest describe it as  “a high degree of suck”. Well the poor little guy didn’t take too well to the food.  The meal was all African inspired and by the walk out of the park he was looking queasy.  And, horrifyingly, on the cab home he had reached full on exorcist level of spewage – yes I caught it all in my hands using a Disney poncho as a mock bucket.  He then spent the rest of the night vomiting repeatedly.  I think the issue was the food because the last time we had African food at Disney, &lt;a href=&quot;https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/dining/animal-kingdom-lodge/boma-flavors-of-africa/&quot;&gt;Booma&lt;/a&gt;, I didn’t even make it out of the parking lot before I lost my entire meal in much the same fashion.  I think he clearly got my stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now since my youngest has been raised in an environment of media on demand (thanks &lt;a href=&quot;http://plex.tv&quot;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roku.com&quot;&gt;Roku&lt;/a&gt;), video games (thanks iPad) and similar distractions there were times when he was bored - “No you can’t play Pokemon Go when we’re on Safari!”.  And then there was the whole exorcist level of spewage so that is why I think he would, today, describe it as a “high level of suck”. But I’m going to put on my parental “look into the future goggles” and predict that in 15 or 20 years this will be one of his fondest childhood memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would I make such a claim given the tale above?  Well it just so happens that I have a similar childhood memory - actually a set of childhood memories - around when my father and I used to go duck hunting.  Starting when I was in fifth grade, my Dad and I used to take off for a week and go down to the eastern shore of Maryland to stay in a cabin on an island, Fishhook Island and go duck hunting.  We had a professional guide, John Holgrapher, and, at the time, these were miserable experiences for a 10 year old boy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I remember being so cold that I would crawl in the very nose of the boat under what little decking there was and breathe on my hands to keep them from freezing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I wasn’t old enough to use a gun for the first two years so there was, well, just waiting around; no toys, electronics, books or anything; just waiting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that would be my equivalent child hood memory to M’s Safari. And, yeah it was miserable, as I look back on it.  But those few, precious trips with my father, are some of favorite memories of growing up with him.  I’ve told the tales to my wife and kids over and over again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sitting at the long breakfast table in the cabin doing my homework and listening to AM radio – that’s where I was when I learned that Mark David Chapman had killed John Lennon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being trapped out by low tide shifts on a full moon from 3 pm past 4 am and having to cook our dinner - a duck we had shot hours earlier - on a campfire that I started&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seeing an enormous flight of 30 plus black duck settle into our decoys and our not getting even one of them (buck fever); my Dad who grew up hunting with his Dad hadn’t seen such a large flight of black duck in over 25 years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hunting with my grand uncle and his best friend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rising before the sun - 3 am - to be out in the duck blind before the birds could see us&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting into a tiny aluminum skiff and setting out for the blind in total darkness and yet the guide always getting us precisely there on the first try; to this day I don’t know how&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hearing our guide ask us “You like oysters?” and then reach over the side of the boat and pull up, with his bare hands, what seemed like a half bushel which he fed us on the spot.  He then, I kid you not, reached into his chest high waders and pulled out a bottle of cocktail sauce.  First oyster I ever ate,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being connected to the mainland only by a CB radio so we were really, truly alone for a week at a time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No bathing facilities at all - we used to get home from a week’s hunting and stinking to high heaven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on.  I have like 20 of my most precious memories and they are all rooted in those trips.  I suspect that fifteen or twenty years from now, M will tell the tale of the Disney Safari and how his parents took him to see tigers, giraffes and elephants oh my!  And how we headed back thru a rain storm so fierce that it came thru the roof the jeep we were in.  I hope he leaves out the spew just as I never mention the cold and the waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/parenting/2016/09/14/childhood-memories.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/parenting/2016/09/14/childhood-memories.html</guid>
        
        <category>m</category>
        
        <category>disney</category>
        
        <category>safari</category>
        
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is an iPad a Serious Productivity Tool?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just had a friend email me something including this text:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will be interesting to see how the iPad unfolds.  I find it hard to believe it’ll be a serious productivity tool until voice rec or a fast method of input becomes a thing.  But I wouldn’t want to bet against it either :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been debating with him about a tool he’s building and talking about how important I think the iPad is and he is disagreeing.  I get it.  It took me a long time to grok the overall nature of an iPad but I think I finally have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this I’m on vacation and the family is at rest (it’s a little past 5).  I’m doing my normal vacation thing - making progress on a recreational coding project.  Here’s what my “desk” looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ymU9Fng.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ymU9Fng.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the left is a Macbook and on the right is an iPad Air 2 wrapped in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Belkin-Ultimate-Wireless-Keyboard-Display/dp/B00BWHILCY&quot;&gt;Belkin keyboard case&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the Belkin case is an add on product so its hard to argue that its a general purpose productivity tool.  But what adding a keyboard case to your iPad does is make it into:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;1 pound micro laptop an 8+ hour battery with wireless connectivity anywhere you are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used an iPad in this configuration to pull off the highway in the middle of absolutely nowhere West Virginia and ssh into a server to terminate a runaway process.  I didn’t have to worry about a separate data plan for my “real” laptop.  I didn’t have to worry about pairing my iPhone with laptop.  I just whipped out my iPad and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com/prompt/&quot;&gt;Prompt from Panic&lt;/a&gt;.  Even tho there are lots of places where I’m hesitant to bring a full fledged laptop, there’s pretty much nowhere these days where you can’t bring a tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s say that you don’t want to add a keyboard case to your iPad, well, there are still lots of productivity reasons to use an iPad aggressively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Passwords.  Add a password manager like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enpass.io&quot;&gt;Enpass&lt;/a&gt; coupled with Dropbox and you can have all of your passwords with you everywhere.  That’s powerful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodnotesapp.com&quot;&gt;Good Notes&lt;/a&gt;.  Add a stylus and you have a pen based not taking solution for conferences where you can hold your iPad up, capture the projected screen and then add your own notes.  I saw this at ElixirConf and asked the individual (I forget his name but he was from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.basho.com/&quot;&gt;Basho&lt;/a&gt;; nice folks).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The app store in general.  It took me a long time to understand this but the cutting edge of software development no longer happens on OSX or Windows or even Linux.  Its happening at the app store level.  Now from a business perspective I find tying your business to this type of walled garden terrifying but developers are doing it in droves.  And you’re seeing real changes like that iOS Twitter clients seem to be updated more frequently than the OSX versions.  There are great productivity apps out there like Good Notes but you do have to look for them.  One great example is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener_ios.php&quot;&gt;Scrivener for iPad&lt;/a&gt; which has finally shipped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s an aspect to modern productivity which doesn’t involve tons of data input - things like reviewing tweets, keeping up with your facebook feed, etc can readily be done on an iPad.  Any type of information consumption can arguably be done more easily on an iPad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ipad/2016/09/13/is-an-ipad-a-serious-productivity-tool.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ipad/2016/09/13/is-an-ipad-a-serious-productivity-tool.html</guid>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>ipad</category>
        
        
        <category>ipad</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elixir Sips - Fantastic Customer Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my quest to actually embrace Elixir as a working language for myself, I’ve taken a number of avenues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;conference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blog reading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blog writing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;books - currently up to 3; new favorite Elixir in Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of the learning effort in any language is not just the language but the ecosystem as a whole.  You would correctly note that I’ve written relatively little elixir as of late.  As much as I’m still grokking the whole functional stuff, I’m also trying to understand the ecosystem.  Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;who the key people are&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the package system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;relevant technical standards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;trying to get my head around core Erlang concepts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;conferences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;application areas where Elixir shines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;phoenix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;phoenix presence - more important than I had ever suspected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how testing works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any programming language these days is the sum of its parts.  A great language can be crippled by a horrible package ecosystem or a great package library could be crippled by the language itself (cpan / perl).  And since I’ve spent 10+ years in Ruby now, I’m looking for my next “10 year language”.  And to make that type assessment means “look at the language of course but then look at everything”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I haven’t done is explore screen casts.  A lot of what I know about Rails, I know from the late, lamented RailsCasts by Ryan Bates.  Back in 2007 or so it seemed like Ryan was changing the world with RailsCasts and for a lot of us, he really did.  Watching someone quickly and easily get ajax running in 2008 when it was still mysterious seemed like magic.  So its accurate to say that I have a lot of love for the medium of screencasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elixirsips.com/&quot;&gt;ElixirSips&lt;/a&gt; by Josh Adams, its fair to say that I was pretty damn overjoyed.  And then I started digging in and I was initially disappointed.  Being a beginner, I wanted to start at the beginning so I hit one of the free podcasts near the start and I had, well, issues.  So I did it again.  Same thing.  And then again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I drafted an email to Josh Adams and said what amounts to “Dude - am I dumb or does your stuff not really work?”.  And much to my surprise I got a fantastically written email owning up to the problem and actually agreeing.  What he said was that he has a strong audience with ElixirSips that has moved past the intro stuff and he doesn’t want to let them down by taking the time to update the early work – &lt;strong&gt;even though he knows he’d make more money by doing just that&lt;/strong&gt;.  Wow.  Now that’s customer service and loyalty to your installed base.  Dang!  So heres what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it meet all my needs as an absolute newbie?  Today, no.  However Josh is listening which is key and I think he’s going to get there.  &lt;strong&gt;Recommended&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/13/elixir-sips-fantastic-customer-service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/13/elixir-sips-fantastic-customer-service.html</guid>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        <category>elixir_sips</category>
        
        <category>josh_adams</category>
        
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Inserting NO-OPs Into Your Programming Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the better development techniques that I’ve ever found has nothing to do with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;programming language&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;editor / tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;methodology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;anything internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is what I refer to as a &lt;strong&gt;personal no op&lt;/strong&gt;.  A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NOP&quot;&gt;no op is an assembly language instruction&lt;/a&gt; that does nothing and since I Z-80 assembly was my second language, I feel comfortable using term.  A personal no op is when you know that you’re about to go dangerously down the wrong path and you decide “All righty then – time to leave the keyboard before I screw something up.”  This is one of those lessons that you only get by experience and, yes, it is a bit of a gray beard thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me illustrate with an example.  I’ve been wrestling with a data indexing issue with respect to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sphinxsearch.com&quot;&gt;Sphinx Search&lt;/a&gt; and a very large data set.  The time cost of an end to end index is about 20+ hours and, in the process, it trashes the previous index making previous to current comparisons hard if not impossible.  So what did I do?  I went upstairs and I made a sandwich.  And since I wanted a sandwich based on last night’s meatballs and we were all out of tomato sauce, I thought nothing of grabbing a can of tomatoes and cooking them down with spices and a bit of sugar.  And, all the while, I was thinking these issues thru, partially in the foreground and partially in the background.  And, sure enough, as the sauce neared completion, the answer came to me.  I won’t bore you with the details but the answer lies in an arcane aspect of how we do database sharding.  With a handful of new models and some code injected dynamically I should be able to preserve old and new indices concurrently.  And now I’m back at my desk writing this up and getting read to code it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the harder truths to recognize as a software engineer is that you’re not actually a typist.  You’re not even actually a programmer.  If you really are an engineer then all your real work happens in your own head and typing it out is just a side effect.  Being a software engineer isn’t all that different I would argue from being an attorney.  Just as an attorney’s real work happens not with Lexis / Nexis / Microsoft Word but in his or her head, so too does your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next time you’re struggling with something, get away from the keyboard and take a personal no op.  It really does help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/12/the-importance-of-inserting-no-ops-into-your-programming-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/12/the-importance-of-inserting-no-ops-into-your-programming-day.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
