<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc / Hyde.
</description>
    <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 08:43:17 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 08:43:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gluten Warning - Mushrooms May Not Actually Be Gluten Free</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://startcooking.com/public/IMG_0474.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;http://startcooking.com/public/IMG_0474.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t often write about food issues here – I have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/recipes/&quot;&gt;recipe blog&lt;/a&gt; for that.  But sometimes I find something so egregious that I feel compelled to write something.  My wife suffers, quite badly, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://celiac.org/celiac-disease/understanding-celiac-disease-2/what-is-celiac-disease/&quot;&gt;Celiac disease&lt;/a&gt;.  And, as with any auto-immune condition, it is always a running battle where the symptoms change and you’re always in responsive mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately my wife has been having odd stomach issues and we finally managed to correlate it to mushrooms.  Our whole kitchen is gluten free and the few gluten based ingredients we do have are physically &lt;strong&gt;stored&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;used&lt;/strong&gt;, on a different &lt;strong&gt;floor&lt;/strong&gt; of the house.  So we knew it wasn’t a normal cross contamination issue.  We also hadn’t eaten out in weeks so that was off the table as well.  A bit of googling turned up this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.verywell.com/are-mushrooms-gluten-free-562814&quot;&gt;Very Well post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Answer: There’s no question that plain mushrooms ought to be gluten-free — after all, they’re a fresh vegetable, right? But lots of people report getting glutened after eating fresh mushrooms … enough people that it’s worth looking into how mushrooms are grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In fact, once you learn how they’re grown, you’ll understand why many people react, especially those who are particularly sensitive to trace gluten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You see, mushroom spores are grown either directly on gluten grains, or on a medium that’s derived at least in part from gluten grains. Rye is used most commonly for this purpose, but growers also use wheat and occasionally on a combination of the two grains (barley, the third gluten grain, doesn’t seem to be in common use for growing mushrooms). And this cultivation method leads to gluten cross-contamination on the finished fungi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the article goes on to say that the presence of gluten in mushrooms is below the 20 ppm standard that defines gluten.  But my wife is admittedly very, very sensitive to ingredients and she can taste the presence of things that I can’t so it doesn’t surprise me that she has problems with mushrooms.  But, even so – what have things come to when a vegetable (ok a fungus) – in its “natural” state – contains gluten?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This only emphasizes to me just how &lt;strong&gt;very, very careful&lt;/strong&gt; you have to be when you have celiac or any food related issue – what you think you’re buying may not be exactly what you expect.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/gluten_free/2017/03/21/gluten-warning-mushrooms-may-not-actually-be-gluten-free.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/gluten_free/2017/03/21/gluten-warning-mushrooms-may-not-actually-be-gluten-free.html</guid>
        
        <category>warning</category>
        
        <category>gluten_free</category>
        
        
        <category>gluten_free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Around OSX Bash Fork Issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever seen this error under OSX:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;-bash: fork: Resource temporarily unavailable
-bash: fork: Resource temporarily unavailable
-bash: fork: Resource temporarily unavailable
-bash: fork: Resource temporarily unavailable
-bash: fork: Resource temporarily unavailable
-bash: fork: Resource temporarily unavailable
-bash: cannot make pipe for command substitution: Too many open files
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then you know that it usually signals “Oh crap - restart the box”.  If you’re a Rails developer then you may be hitting this due to problems with the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/puma/puma-dev/issues/56&quot;&gt;Puma development server and the evented listener&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to change the listener in config/environments/development.rb from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;config.file_watcher = ActiveSupport::EventedFileUpdateChecker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;config.file_watcher = ActiveSupport::FileUpdateChecker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also want to kill the listen gem as well (read the linked issue above).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/osx/2017/03/20/getting-around-osx-bash-fork-issues.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/osx/2017/03/20/getting-around-osx-bash-fork-issues.html</guid>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        <category>bash</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>fork</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Disabling Spring in Rails</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I now have more than a decade at building Rails apps and, since most of that time was a consultant, I think its fair to say that I’ve seen, worked on and built from scratch a lot of Rails applications.  My single least favorite part of Rails is the monolith application pattern.  While it can be incredibly productive to have every aspect of your source code in a single place, monoliths are an inherent anti-pattern:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They are brittle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They are fragile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gems can conflict with each other&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby is a dynamic, late bound, garbage collected language – the more lines of code you have the more likely you are to have some kind of conflict&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monoliths seem to work great for building BaseCamp but I am immensely unhappy with them and I’ve spent the past several months going down a service oriented architecture (SOA) approach for my side project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is an application pre-loader which loads a chunk of your Rails code into memory in order to speed up development.  By having things preloaded, for example, you can get into rails console faster, or run tests faster, etc.  And this works fine when you have a monolith application pattern.  In my case, however, I’m partitioning my data at the user level into individual databases and using an environment variable to specify the database at load time with this trick in database.yml:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;database: cartazzi_web_app_&amp;lt;%= ENV[‘CARTAZZI_USER_ID’] %&amp;gt;_development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this works perfectly – until Spring rears its ugly head.  Since Spring has things cached, you can go into rails console and execute a User.first and find the wrong user.  It becomes even more confusing when you check the database with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rails.application.config.database_configuration[Rails.env][“database”]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it reports back a database that you &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; isn’t the one where the user you just found doesn’t exist.  What’s going on is that the Rails console is talking to its in memory configuration which reports back something from earlier, not your current configuration.  And then you scratch your head for quite a bit until you cobble together enough brain cells to recall “oh crap – SPRING!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to disable Spring entirely.  Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the shell level, do this: &lt;strong&gt;pkill -f spring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edit your Gemfile and comment out all the spring references.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the shell level, do this: &lt;strong&gt;bin/spring binstub –remove –all&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/30302021/rails-runner-without-spring&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other ways around this including an environment variable which temporarily disables it but given the number of spring related processes I keep having to kill, I think getting it out entirely is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/03/20/disabling-spring-in-rails.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/03/20/disabling-spring-in-rails.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>monolith</category>
        
        <category>hyde</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Questioning the Nature of Gem'ified JavaScript</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2017 you can’t be doing web development and not at least be doing some JavaScript.  I bloody well hate JavaScript and even I’m dipping my toe into the JS water.  Way, way, way back in the mid 90s I got very badly burned by JavaScript compatibility issues and I’ve never looked back but it is time.  So I’ve been mucking about with d3 and it has been a hellish weekend indeed.  When I learn a new technology I like to start with the simplest possible example so I started with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.overfitted.com/blog/?p=302&quot;&gt;Overfitted Rails / D3 example&lt;/a&gt; because its only about 10 files total.  And this example works perfectly in Rails 4.2.  Kudos to the author.  Now while it works perfectly in Rails 4.2, it entirely fails to render the world’s simplest bar graph in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/rails5_d3_seed&quot;&gt;Rails 5&lt;/a&gt; and nothing I do makes it work.  This has the feel of some type of “Rails Magic” that changes from 4 to 5 so something that was implicit is now explicit and Ghu only knows what the &lt;em&gt;censored&lt;/em&gt; it is.  I’ve put probably 3+ hours into making this example work and I’m now at the point of wanting to take a hammer to a Macbook – clearly time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The saddest part of all this is that the author of the overfitted example is clearly a bright, bright guy as based on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/users/1583239/qwwqwwq&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow profile&lt;/a&gt; - top 12%, better than &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/users/409644/fuzzygroup&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; certainly but there’s no obvious way to contact him and no comments on his blog so, sigh…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next stopping point on this d3 quest was &lt;a href=&quot;http://gregpark.io/blog/live-d3-rails-plot/&quot;&gt;Greg Park’s Adding a Live D3 Visualization to Rails&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a lot more complex than Overfitted but all the bits are there and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gregoryjpark/live-d3-example&quot;&gt;there’s a full repo&lt;/a&gt;.  So the first step was a quick fork so I could remove the postgres dependency.  An install showed that everything worked in Rails 4.  The moment of truth was to try it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/live-d3-example&quot;&gt;Rails 5&lt;/a&gt; – and it worked brilliantly!  Thank you Greg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a JS expert in any way – it would more more accurate to say “I’m a self professed JavaScript hater who feels he has no alternative but to try and use it (finally)” so my first thought was “Why not use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iblue/d3-rails&quot;&gt;d3rails gem&lt;/a&gt;”.  Given that I had this in git, the path was clear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;take my rails 5 exmaple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make a branch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;delete the vendor/javascripts/d3.js file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;update gemfile and add d3-rails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bundle install&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;try the app and see if the graphs display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, what do you know, the result was the same as my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/css/2017/03/16/when-your-font-awesome-etsy-icon-doesn-t-display.html&quot;&gt;Font Awesome issues recently&lt;/a&gt; – the graphs didn’t display.  This is really making me question gems that wrap JavaScript libraries.  I would be certain that the problem here is that something changed in d3 and d3-rails isn’t current enough so something is broken.  But given that I’ve now hit this twice in the same week, it feels like either a CDN or vendor/assets/javascripts is the right approach for JavaScript inclusion.  Our historical method of wrapping JavaScript into gems for “inclusion” into the rails ecosystem is really feeling broken right now.  Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/03/19/questioning-the-nature-of-gem-ified-javascript.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/rails/2017/03/19/questioning-the-nature-of-gem-ified-javascript.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>d3</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Your Font Awesome Etsy Icon Doesn't Display</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://fontawesome.io/&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt; and I think enough of it that it was actually the &lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt; bit of software I purchased for use on my side project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the situation where most of my Font Awesome icons would show up but a few wouldn’t.  I knew it wasn’t a layout problem because the code was all machine generated and the Amazon icon was showing up just a few lines earlier.  An example of an icon which wouldn’t show up is the Etsy icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with almost all my crazy CSS / Bootstrap issues, I reached out to my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://dasari.me/&quot;&gt;Dv&lt;/a&gt; and a quick pairing session set it right.  The first solution we found was to add the following snippet to custom.scss in /app/assets/stylesheets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.fa-etsy:before {
  content: &quot;\0045&quot;
  font-family: georgia, serif
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that fixed the Etsy icon – but it was really a work around and the credit goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hayley.cc/2016/10/05/Font-Awesome-No-Etsy-icon-No-problem/&quot;&gt;Hayley.cc&lt;/a&gt; (brilliant but still a work around).  But only fixing the Etsy icon clearly wasn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dv did some digging and came up with the thesis that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bokmann/font-awesome-rails&quot;&gt;font-awesome-rails gem&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t up to date and suggested I replace it with the CDN.  So by adding this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link href=&quot;https://maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome/4.7.0/css/font-awesome.min.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; integrity=&quot;sha384-wvfXpqpZZVQGK6TAh5PVlGOfQNHSoD2xbE+QkPxCAFlNEevoEH3Sl0sibVcOQVnN&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was entirely fixed.  Given the problems with CloudBleed, a month ago, I’m mildly paranoid with a CDN but this did simply and brilliantly fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Dv!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/css/2017/03/16/when-your-font-awesome-etsy-icon-doesn-t-display.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/css/2017/03/16/when-your-font-awesome-etsy-icon-doesn-t-display.html</guid>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
        <category>fontawesome</category>
        
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Developer Employee Transitions When You're an AWS Shop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I find myself advising a former employer on how to lock out an employee with fairly pervasive access (and, yes, I am the employee).  Here was my advice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The safest option would be to move to white listing &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; ip addresses needed for SSH login.  That would be an absolute ban on any incoming SSH logins from the old employee and, while inconvenient, is a wonderful means to lock down a system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/ec2-key-pairs.html#having-ec2-create-your-key-pair&quot;&gt;Re-issue a new SSH pem file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete the old SSH pem file on your machine and then verify login to at least 2 systems with the new PEM file.  I’d make sure to verify access to the primary db server using the new PEM file but that’s just me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/31912037/how-to-delete-deactivate-the-current-pem-file-and-create-new-one-in-aws&quot;&gt;De-authorize the old PEM file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/apigateway/delete-api-key.html&quot;&gt;Delete the API keys that the employee had access to&lt;/a&gt;.  Make sure that you delete them in all regions where they were valid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/14/developer-employee-transitions-when-you-re-an-aws-shop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/14/developer-employee-transitions-when-you-re-an-aws-shop.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ansible Error with AWS, AMI Creation and Encrypted</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a bizarre Ansible / AWS error I just found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;An exception occurred during task execution. To see the full traceback, use -vvv. The error was: TypeError: __init__() got an unexpected keyword argument 'encrypted'
fatal: [localhost]: FAILED! =&amp;gt; {&quot;changed&quot;: false, &quot;failed&quot;: true, &quot;module_stderr&quot;: &quot;Traceback (most recent call last):\n  File \&quot;/tmp/ansible_prCPvG/ansible_module_ec2_ami.py\&quot;, line 560, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt;\n    main()\n  File \&quot;/tmp/ansible_prCPvG/ansible_module_ec2_ami.py\&quot;, line 552, in main\n    create_image(module, ec2)\n  File \&quot;/tmp/ansible_prCPvG/ansible_module_ec2_ami.py\&quot;, line 381, in create_image\n    bd = BlockDeviceType(**device)\nTypeError: __init__() got an unexpected keyword argument 'encrypted'\n&quot;, &quot;module_stdout&quot;: &quot;&quot;, &quot;msg&quot;: &quot;MODULE FAILURE&quot;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick google revealed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ansible/ansible-modules-core/issues/1773&quot;&gt;this solution&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;pip install boto –upgrade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which I had to execute as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo pip install boto –upgrade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/14/ansible-error-with-aws-ami-creation-and-encrypted.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/14/ansible-error-with-aws-ami-creation-and-encrypted.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dropbox for the Software Developer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An old friend asked me a great question recently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I saw you mentioning your use of Dropbox the other day. I’ve been using GitHub as my “cloud device”: when would I find Dropbox a better option?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the single best decisions that I made in 2016 was to adopt &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; as the key part of my personal computing environment.  I last talked about this back on &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/postmac/2016/11/05/life-in-a-postmac-world.html&quot;&gt;November&lt;/a&gt;, see the section “Conclusion - A Synchronized Computing Environment For Me” but it really does bear further description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My use for Dropbox is exactly what it is designed for – synchronization.  I’ve always had multiple machines but one has always been my “primary”” machine.  Since all my code was on Github, I could generally get to my code from any machine but what about my spreadsheets?  Or my documents?  Or just about any other file that I needed.  Here’s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signup for a 1 Terabyte Dropbox account (roughly $50 / year so dirt cheap).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Dropbox on all my machines including my ChromeBook, my Linux box, my iPhone and iPad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Symlink ~/Dropbox to ~/me so I have an easier path to type.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move all the files that matter to me into ~/me under a logical file structure related to my usage context - ~/me/blogging for all my blogs, ~/me/Documents for Documents, ~/me/consulting for consulting work, ~/me/fuzzygroup for anything I do online and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move important things like SSH keys under ~/me and then use symlinks to insert them back into their correct location.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a ~/me/transfer directory to copy transitory data from one machine to anther.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move all the git repos that matter underneath ~/me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My working set of data for Dropbox is about 40 gigabytes and I suspect that could be made smaller but I haven’t seen the need.  This approach has meant that literally no matter what computing device I am on, I always have access to the data that actually matters to me.  True I don’t have, for example, my iTunes music synchronized or my Photos but in terms of the data that I, as a software developer, actually rely on, this is about as perfect an environment as I could dream up.  The only objection I have is that on one of my machines, oddly the most powerful, Dropbox refuses to fully sync, always stalling out on two files that never complete.  Since there are no user facing logs on Dropbox for OSX, well, I have no idea what they are.  And, worse, it spikes my CPU past 100% always running up the fan and down the battery life.  But, other than that, I’m ridiculously happy with this as an approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that this was supposed to be what Apple was going to give us with iCloud but iCloud:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doesn’t seem to work particularly well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removes local file storage of documents into the cloud solely thus absolutely screwing you over if you don’t have internet access&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has no cross platform support – I really wanted all my data on my ChromeBook and my Linux box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is astonishing to me that the cross machine synchronization environment that I’ve been searching for most of my professional life is nothing more than a simple Dropbox subscription but that’s all it took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still do full OS level backups periodically but I don’t generally worry about it terribly since the data that matters is always safe being mirrored across all my computing devices and into the Dropbox cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/dropbox/2017/03/13/dropbox-for-the-software-developer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/dropbox/2017/03/13/dropbox-for-the-software-developer.html</guid>
        
        <category>dropbox</category>
        
        
        <category>dropbox</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leveling Up as a Developer Part 2 - Interstitial Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/software_engineering/2017/02/24/leveling-up-as-a-developer.html&quot;&gt;Leveling Up as a Developer&lt;/a&gt;.  Leveraging Interstitial Time is another approach to improve your skills.  As a developer there are at least two very different types of learning that you have to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep, Focused Learning&lt;/strong&gt;.  The classic example here is the syntax of a language.  Some of us can do that by simply reading a book but most of us need the focused, “muscle memory” effort of actually doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness Learning&lt;/strong&gt;.  A huge part of the IT or Information Technology space is simply being aware that something exists.  Whether it is a tool, a particular library, an algorithm or merely a way to approach a problem, awareness is often all you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know how to do deep focused learning – you sit, generally alone, in a quiet space with a computer and lots of time and you work at it.  Some of us have a set of problems that we like to solve to teach ourselves.  Others focus on working through tutorials.  And there are certainly other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you tackle &lt;em&gt;awareness learning&lt;/em&gt;?  Given how vast the world of IT is in 2017, how can you possibly be aware of everything you need to know to be an effective software engineer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of this post talks about awareness learning and my approach to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understanding-interstitial-time&quot;&gt;Understanding Interstitial Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as an interstitial ad is the ad that shows up between page transitions, I view interstitial time as the &lt;em&gt;time between times&lt;/em&gt;.  A good example of this came up last night – I had to peel two pounds of shrimp for dinner.  This was easily 30 minutes of time when my hands were occupied and I really couldn’t do much.  Given that my hands were nasty dirty, I couldn’t even turn the pages of a book while I did it.  To me that’s interstitial time – normally it would be entirely wasted.  What I do, however, is turn interstitial time into awareness learning because while I can’t do much, I can &lt;strong&gt;listen&lt;/strong&gt; – and that’s at the heart of awareness learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;required-items&quot;&gt;Required Items&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the things you need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/smart_phone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smart_phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some type of smart phone; doesn’t have to be iOS, android is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/bluetooth_headset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bluetooth_headset.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bluetooth headset.  Personally I favor the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Plantronics-Universal-Cancelling-Wireless-Bluetooth/dp/B010XDJTWS&quot;&gt;Plantronics M180&lt;/a&gt; but any one will work.  This one has good volume, easy pairing and a 7 hour battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/icatcher-podcast-player/id414419105?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/icatcher.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;icatcher.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need some kind of podcasting listening tool.  Personally I Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/icatcher-podcast-player/id414419105?mt=8&quot;&gt;iCatcher&lt;/a&gt; on iOS but &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/overcast-podcast-player/id888422857?mt=8&quot;&gt;OverCast&lt;/a&gt; by Marco Arment is also excellent and I recently bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/apple-store/id1080840241?mt=8&amp;amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4&quot;&gt;Castro&lt;/a&gt; but haven’t used it as well.  There are great ones on Android as well but none that I have personally used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/podcast_feed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;podcast_feed.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is some podcast feed that’s going to download new things to learn right into your phone on an ongoing basis.  Thankfully, in 2017, that essentially means any podcast on the planet – since they pretty much all have an RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From top to bottom this is a smart phone, a bluetooth headset and a podcast feed or podcast feeds of things that for your type of software engineering you should be aware.  I’m a generalist with a focus on web and back end so I find &lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/&quot;&gt;Software Engineering Daily&lt;/a&gt; to be outstanding.  But here are some more great learning sources by category:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DevOps - &lt;a href=&quot;http://packetpushers.net/datanauts-podcast/&quot;&gt;Datanaughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big Data - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drilltodetail.com/&quot;&gt;Drill to Detail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online Marketing - &lt;a href=&quot;http://okdork.com/podcast/&quot;&gt;Noah Kagan Presents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine Learning - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetalkingmachines.com/&quot;&gt;Talking Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Science - &lt;a href=&quot;https://dataskeptic.com/podcast&quot;&gt;Data Skeptic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript - &lt;a href=&quot;https://devchat.tv/js-jabber&quot;&gt;JavaScript Jabber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby - &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/rubyonrails&quot;&gt;5by5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elixir - &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/elixirfountain&quot;&gt;Elixir Fountain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you can see that there is a podcast for almost any time of IT learning.  For example I just googled for Embedded System podcast and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://embedded.fm/&quot;&gt;Embedded.fm&lt;/a&gt; which is 189 episodes long on Embedded Systems and is currently covering Soft Robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just google for what you need to learn about and then “podcast” and you’re very likely to find something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pulling-off-awareness-learning-on-an-ongoing-basis&quot;&gt;Pulling Off Awareness Learning On an Ongoing Basis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to this is that you need to develop a &lt;strong&gt;habit&lt;/strong&gt; around applying interstitial time to learning.  Here’s all you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the things above&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your headset and phone regularly charged&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whenever you’ve got at least 5 minutes doing something crappy – commuting, dishes, peeling shrimp, raking leaves, building your kids tree house, widening your driveway with a pickaxe, sitting with your kids while the fall asleep – it can be anything, you &lt;strong&gt;listen&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;learn&lt;/strong&gt;.  And, yes, I did build a tree house while listening to Ruby podcasts and I widened a driveway doing the same thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep at it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last one, Keeping at it, is the hard part.  If you work in IT then your days tend to be long and there are times that your brain just hurts and you don’t want to listen to, well, YMITC (yet more IT crap).  It doesn’t matter, this only works if you stick with it.  So you suck it up and build it into a habit where you just keep at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s pretty much it but let me finish up with a concrete example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-example&quot;&gt;An Example&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently listening to Software Engineering Daily, their podcast on &lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/02/28/heroku-autoscaling-with-andrew-gwozdziewycz/&quot;&gt;Heroku AutoScaling&lt;/a&gt; and Andrew Gwozdziewycz gave their algorithm for determining when to auto scale.  He described it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Time point: 35:40 Autoscaling like I said is a little bit more complicated.  The only data we use for auto scaling is your response time, the p95 response time, the number of requests that you’re serving be it errors or successful requests and the number of dynos that you currently have.  And what we do is utilize Little’s Law, this thing from queueing theory that basically  says (gives example of bank tellers and queues) - think of the arrival rate as through put and think of the latency as the time a teller takes to make a deposit or withdrawal.  These things are interrelated into this relationship – Little’s Law.  We look at the actual number of bank tellers versus the theoretical number if the latency is zero.  If you’re app starts responding greater than that latency then we’ll scale it up to get that latency down.  We put that into an exponential weighted moving average and we plot a regression line and the slope of that regression line gives us whether or not its ok to scale up or scale down.  (Time point: 38:50)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I may have munged the description a bit but if you start listening at minute 35 and go thru it once or twice, you’ll pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just having heard that much, I can think of about a dozen different ways to apply that algorithm to my daily work as I’m sure you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s why I listen to podcasts so avidly – trying to come up with something like this on your own is truly hard but just knowning that this exists often gives you the critical first step to solving this type of problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2017/03/12/leveling-up-as-a-developer-part-2-interstitial-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/software_engineering/2017/03/12/leveling-up-as-a-developer-part-2-interstitial-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using ngrok for Web Development</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 17:22:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/11/using-ngrok-for-web-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fuzzyblog.io//blog/2017/03/11/using-ngrok-for-web-development.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
