<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 01:55:40 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 01:55:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>In Defense of Facebook's Fake News Policy</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 01:34:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/22/in-defense-of-facebook-s-fake-news-policy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/22/in-defense-of-facebook-s-fake-news-policy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>visudo On OSX Sierra</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having just gotten OSX Sierra on my new Macbook Pro, I added myself to the sudoers file and key getting sudo issues.  I found the answer on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/39474074&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;.  Essentially there is an undocumented change where you need to add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Defaults !tty_tickets
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to the sudoers file when you run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo visudo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joy oh undocumented joy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/osx/2016/11/22/visudo-on-osx-sierra.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/osx/2016/11/22/visudo-on-osx-sierra.html</guid>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        <category>visudo</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying a Mac as a Developer in Fall 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So my buddy Nick &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/i-almost-rage-bought-a-macbook-pro&quot;&gt;almost rage purchased a Mac&lt;/a&gt; the other day and I thought that given that I sit at an 8 foot long custom built computing desk with six different MacBook computers on it, and a nerd closet of doom with 3 on the shelf and 2 more upstairs for the family’s use, perhaps I should write down for him the different issues with respect to buying a developer machine in Fall 2016.  As I write this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am in my PostMac phase where I’m actively trying to use an Ubuntu-Mate install on an Intel NUC as a primary development tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I just bought a brand new MacBook Pro (last generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m clearly deeply divided but perhaps writing all this down will help either myself or at least someone else sort it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this Apple has the following offerings each of which is a possibility for a developer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook 2016&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Air 2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro w/o TouchBar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro w/ Touchbar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro 2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iMac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these is discussed below.  Just as an overview, my buddy Nick isn’t part of the “Apple Faithful” at present.  He doesn’t bleed six colors as we used to say (I date back to the Apple II days and my first Mac was a Plus) which means there are all aspects of the ecosystem which he doesn’t yet get.  Nick is a Windows user, a Docker Captain, a Udemy instructor and an all around good guy.  His almost rage buy was inspired by frustration with Microsoft and its not dissimilar to my rage moving to Ubuntu-Mate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;developer-or-tourist&quot;&gt;Developer or Tourist?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand if you’re going to enter the Apple ecosystem is are you doing it as a developer or as a tourist.  If you just want a Mac for light consumption, for syncing an iPhone or for just answering the question - “is this for me” then you could easily buy either of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook 2016&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Air 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new MacBook 2016 is the one I just bought my wife as she decided to goto graduate school this past October for her master’s degree.  It is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tiny&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;elegant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beautiful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I despite the new Apple low travel keyboard but in time I could likely move from despise to gentle loathing.  Given that I still use ThinkPad keyboards with trackpoints for my “desktop” Mac usage, that’s actually a fair compliment.  The new MacBook 2016 is limited to 8 gigs of RAM which I don’t feel is acceptable for a developer but if your needs aren’t serious then that is likely ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tying this out on a MacBook Air 13” Early 2014 model which has been an absolute workhorse beast of a computer for me.  Even though it only has 8 gigs of RAM, I’ve done more with this MacBook I think than any other and it has been a rock star for me.  If Apple had just offered an upgrade of this exact machine with 16 gigs of RAM, I’d have bought it in a heart beat – I love it just that much.  When my 15” MacBook Pro decided that it was useless, and only redeemable by &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/11/05/life-in-a-postmac-world.html&quot;&gt;installing Elementary OS&lt;/a&gt;, this was the box that saved my professional life.  It runs I can’t tell you how many different code bases and the only drawback is really the amount of RAM.  It also has the advantage of a fantastic keyboard and an ok battery.  The CPU kind of sucks and the fan makes a bunch of noise but I do love this damn little box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sidebar-understanding-what-mac-you-have--upgrade-tools&quot;&gt;Sidebar: Understanding What Mac You Have / Upgrade Tools&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first weird things about Apple hardware to understand is that Apple has relatively few model names and they just keep reusing them with internal, non visual suffixes like Mid 2013 / Early 2015, etc.  What you have to do is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Apple Menu
About this Mac
Support
Specifications
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the visual flow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/which_mac_01_apple_menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;which_mac_01_apple_menu.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/which_mac_02_about_this_mac.png&quot; alt=&quot;which_mac_02_about_this_mac.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/which_mac_03_specifications.png&quot; alt=&quot;which_mac_03_specifications.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/which_mac_04_specifications_browser.png&quot; alt=&quot;which_mac_04_specifications_browser.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will take you to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://support-sp.apple.com/sp/index?page=cpuspec&amp;amp;cc=G5RP&amp;amp;lang=en_US&quot;&gt;web page like this&lt;/a&gt; which explains exactly what your Mac is.  The name at the top like &lt;em&gt;MacBook Air (13-inch, Early 2014)&lt;/em&gt; is what you can give to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crucial.com/&quot;&gt;Crucial&lt;/a&gt; if you’re looking to upgrade something.  Yes Crucial is still vital if you’re using a Mac.  Another great resource is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ifixit.com&quot;&gt;iFixit.com&lt;/a&gt; if you’re looking to understand exactly how to install the upgrade from Crucial you just bought.  And yes there are special tools involved – just do whatever iFixit tells you to do and its usuallk ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: RAM on MacBooks is soldered in.  If you don’t get it at purchase time you aren’t upgrading.  Crucial’s upgrades on RAM or Macs are either for older models or for Desktop Macs (the iMac line).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-you-want-to-develop-on-a-mac&quot;&gt;So You Want to Develop on a Mac&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re serious about dipping into the Apple waters then here are your options in Fall 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro w/o TouchBar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro w/ Touchbar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro 2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iMac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these has distinct pros and cons.  They all have pros but I think the cons are more illuminating so let’s elaborate on them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MacBook Pro w/o TouchBar&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pros
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;available today&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;cheaper&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Light&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;At the time of this writing no ability to run Linux; maybe it will get sorted out; maybe not&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cons
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Not really a Macbook Pro imho&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Really a big Macbook Air&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Only 2 USB c ports&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Dongle, Dongle, Dongle&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No HDMI port&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MacBook Pro w/ Touchbar&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pros
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;4 USB C ports&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The Touchbar&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Light&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;At the time of this writing no ability to run Linux; maybe it will get sorted out; maybe not&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cons
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;4 USB C ports - only 2 of which are the high speed thunderbolt flavor&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Expensive&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The Touchbar&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No function keys&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No esc key&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Only 16 gigs of RAM; DAMN YOU APPLE!&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Dongle, Dongle, Dongle&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No HDMI port&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MacBook Pro 2015&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pros
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Great Keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A full array of ports - USB, Thunderbolt, HDMI&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;16 gigs of RAM is supported&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cons
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Older Hardware&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMac&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pros
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;More than 16 gigs of RAM&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;It really is pretty&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cons
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Its a desktop&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Painful to upgrade; I’m looking into upgrading a Mid 2011 iMac my family uses and the process scares the hell out of me&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I look at this list I have to wonder if my decision to try working on an Intel NUC using Ubuntu-Mate was entirely rational.  An iMac would have gotten me the more than 16 gigs of RAM which I personally felt was necessary and that would have addressed my &lt;strong&gt;immediate&lt;/strong&gt; needs.  Now, that said, I’m a professional developer and, recently, it feels that Apple’s path and mine are diverging, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the increasingly locked down nature of OSX is at direct odds with what a developer needs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t feel that Apple is remotely “fair” with respect to storage capacities on boxes / iPhones given modern picture density; there’s a huge space / capacity mismatch between high megapixel phones and lots of videos with respect to selling computers with paltry SSD capacity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;poor Unix support.  I can’t find the links right now but we’re seeing poor support / broken libraries for core Unix stuff that shouldn’t be broken.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/osx/2016/11/22/visudo-on-osx-sierra.html&quot;&gt;visudo issues on Mac OS Sierra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the only one who feels this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/tag.html#postmac&quot;&gt;My Post Mac Writings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12825849&quot;&gt;End of the Line for Macbook Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12822913&quot;&gt;Ask HN: What Do I Do Know That Apple Macs Suck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12818724&quot;&gt;Thinking of Going Purely Open Source in 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12810732&quot;&gt;What Will You Use Next for Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there’s some level of whining here – and I’m clearly among them – because I did just hand Apple almost $3,000 of my hard earned personal money for a new MacBook but there is one thing that I haven’t mentioned about Apple Hardware and it is one of the two close out topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;apple-hardware-is-fantastic&quot;&gt;Apple Hardware Is Fantastic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you separate out RAM, price and performance, one thing stands out about Apple hardware – when it matches what you need – the pure hardware is fantastic.  Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Macs just plain feel good; they have a level of fit and finish that I don’t don’t think I’ve ever seen else where (Intel’s NUC is a happy exception)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Macs tend to last a long time.  Examples:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My family 2011 iMac which the kids use daily is still running strong&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Every Macbook or Macbook pro I’ve bought back to Snow Leopard still works&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Generally a Linux version installs well on older MacBooks which is a great way to revive an older machine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Screws don’t come out; the chassis’s don’t bend or flex; this sounds minor but in the 90s I lost 3 separate Toshiba / Dell laptops due to screws coming loose and rattling around until they caused a short&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Macs have a high resale value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-should-nick-buy-a-mac&quot;&gt;So Should Nick Buy a Mac?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started this with the tale of my buddy Nick almost buying a MacBook Pro.  That wasn’t a metaphor for what should I do – Nick is a real person who is telling his own tale &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/i-almost-rage-bought-a-macbook-pro&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  My recent choice was clear – &lt;strong&gt;buy the top end of the previous generation&lt;/strong&gt;.  This got me the RAM upgrade I wanted, the keyboard I adore and it freed me from Dongle, Dongle, Dongle Hell.  Apple’s choice of USB-C everywhere is bold but it isn’t for me.  I do too many public facing events to NOT have an HDMI port on my primary travel machine.  And the incremental hardware advance isn’t sufficient in my opinion to justify the cost in Fall 2016.  If Apple had been able to give me more than 16 gigs of RAM then I could have dealt with likely everything else but more than 16 gigs was my key issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if Nick should buy a Mac.  For a professional developer buying into a platform is a major decision.  The amount of learning that you have to do if you’re serious is immense and the cost of the machine, unfortunately, is a rounding error when compared to the value of your time.  I remember how hard it was to transition from Windows to OSX back in 2006 in my post Feedster days and it was expensive in terms of time.  Personally I find it hard to think of Apple as a professional developer ecosystem in Fall 2016.  It feels like Apple is trying to become a mobile computing company and developers are just a wart on that.  I remember discussing this with colleagues as early as 2012 / 2013 and it does seem to be coming to pass.  Honestly it feels to me that committing to a Linux platform makes more sense for Nick but that’s just me.  His opinion likely varies as it should.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/mac/2016/11/22/buying-a-mac-as-a-developer-in-fall-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/mac/2016/11/22/buying-a-mac-as-a-developer-in-fall-2016.html</guid>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        <category>rage</category>
        
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings - Two Things that Betsy Devine Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I’m now happily ensconced in the mid west, once upon a time, in a vastly different personal universe, I lived in Boston.  And I think the happiest times I had in Boston were the brief period where I was part of the informal Boston blogging crowd centered around &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/&quot;&gt;Berkman Center at Harvard&lt;/a&gt; and a random crew of people that drifted into that orbit.  Among those people were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://betsydevine.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Betsy Devine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://halleyscomment.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Halley Suitt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rura.org/shimon/&quot;&gt;Shimon Rura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markbernstein.org/&quot;&gt;Mark Bernstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.harvard.edu/jkbaumga/&quot;&gt;Jessica Baumgart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Myself and many others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of us were drawn together to the hotness of a new medium and it had, as best as I can tell, the feeling of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salon_(gathering)&quot;&gt;18th century salon&lt;/a&gt;.  Everything was new; the people were excited and it felt like something was brewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betsy_Devine&quot;&gt;Betsy Devine&lt;/a&gt; and what I learned from her.  I first met Betsy in roughly May 2003 as dated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/story.radio.weblogs.com/2003/05/11/boston-beach-blogging-bingo.html&quot;&gt;this url&lt;/a&gt; where she was present; the pictures aren’t present any more – I’ll fix that some other time so you’ll have to take my word for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I didn’t really know Betsy very well.  I knew she was pleasant.  I knew she was clearly smart as a whip but I was in my mid 30s and Betsy was my Mom’s age so I suspect I didn’t give all the respect I should have.  For example I didn’t know that she was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Longing-Harmonies-Themes-Variations-Physics/dp/0393305961/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1479718439&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Longing+for+the+Harmonies&quot;&gt;published author&lt;/a&gt; (yes I just ordered it and you likely should to if you’re bothering to read this).  And I knew she was kind which is a character trait all to often overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then in 2004 Betsy’s life changed dramatically – her &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Wilczek&quot;&gt;husband&lt;/a&gt;, someone I knew slightly from having carved &lt;a href=&quot;http://betsydevine.com/blog/page/89/?s=devine&quot;&gt;this pumpkin at their house on October 22, 2003&lt;/a&gt;, won the Nobel Prize in Physics.  At the time I met him, I was told “hey - here’s Betsy’s husband - he teaches at MIT”.  And, yes, MIT is impressive but he’s a teacher (and a very pleasant fellow).  And so Betsy went from being just Betsy to being the wife of a legitimate celebrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-first-celebrity-changes-things&quot;&gt;Learning the First: Celebrity Changes Things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In modern culture celebrity is an odd thing.  I work alone, in a pitch dark room, most days so I clearly fall into the introvert camp and I’ve never cared much for it but I’ve had a few random encounters with celebrities over the years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My first partner crashed into Bill Gates at a CD-ROM conference back in maybe ‘91 and almost took him out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I stayed on Ted Turner’s yacht once upon a time when my Dad and I were hunting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My Dad’s best friend, Jim Mattingly, &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.sailingscuttlebutt.com/cgi-bin/gforum.cgi?post=7816#7816&quot;&gt;skippered Tenacious in the Fastnet Race in ‘79&lt;/a&gt;.  He was then featured in posters that ran for years in the boating industry (I grew up in boating)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andy Rooney used to shop at one of my family’s wood working businesses and he was exactly the same in person as on 60 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, even with some exposure to celebrities all through my youth, I suspect on some level, post 2004, I viewed Betsy at least a little bit as “wife of a nobel laureate” instead of as “Betsy”.  Apologies for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally this is where I end this type of post but not this time.  Upon reflection I learned at least two more things from Betsy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-second-never-ever-underestimate-the-brains-people-have&quot;&gt;Learning the Second: Never, Ever Underestimate the Brains People Have&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Joy&quot;&gt;Bill Joy&lt;/a&gt; is a computer scientist, a co-founder of Sun Microsystems, the primary author of BSD unix and too many other technical achievements to write down and the author of Joy’s Law:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Joy’s law is the principle that “no matter who you are, most of the smartest people work for someone else,” \ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joy's_law_(management)&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Bill Joy wrote this in the context of Sun, Microsoft and technical nerds and who they work for but I would actually expand it to be something far more expansive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are smart people all around you.  And at least one of them is almost certainly smarter than you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my initial perspective Betsy was a mom, heck, she even looked like my mom.  What I didn’t realize at the time, and wouldn’t realize for literally years to come, was just how &lt;strong&gt;damn smart&lt;/strong&gt; she was.  I should have taken a clue from the fact that she wrote humor professionally.  Comedians are always smart and that should have tipped me off.  Or I should have taken a clue from the fact that she had a Masters in Materials Science Engineering from Princeton.  How smart did she have to be to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get into princeton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get into a technical field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get into a technical field as a woman in 1978??&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get a master’s degree that almost certainly required a thesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that by any measure there’s far more depth to Betsy’s smarts then I’ll ever know. There are literally smart people all around you; never, ever, underestimate the brains people have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-the-third-what-might-betsy-have-done&quot;&gt;Learning the Third: What Might Betsy Have Done?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender and identity politics is a dicey subject in America in 2016 so I write this with no small degree of trepidation.  It is the reason that as a profoundly white male of privilege – the only college nickname I ever had was, I kid you not, &lt;em&gt;Captain Whitebread&lt;/em&gt; – I actually had Betsy read this in advance of posting since I didn’t want to stick my foot in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my third learning is more of a zen like question – Why Might Betsy Have Done?  As a woman, even an accomplished woman, in the late 1960s / 1970s, Betsy went down a fairly traditional route of wife and mother but also kept herself as a distinct entity.  That’s a challenge because raising a family is an all consuming past time.  I say that as a father and husband who has seen that his wife has a harder “job” that he has.  And my wife certainly has a more important job than I have.  My work product is literally ephemeral – I write lines of code that often don’t survive a week.  My wife?  She’s takes little people and day by day turns them into big people.  Every product I’ve ever written – and I’ve written a lot of them – will be gone someday, generally soon – but my wife’s “work product” will last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have damn near infinite respect for what Betsy did.  But when I see how smart she is and how smart she has to be it makes me wonder what she might have done.  Perhaps in a slightly different universe she might have the Nobel prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next time you see a wife and mother and look at the accomplishments that their husband has you should really wonder what that wife and mother might have done on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively the next time you see a woman at work, whether she’s “technical” or not, recognize that she’s almost certainly smart and there is a fair chance you’re underestimating her.  Men are notorious for that and there’s no reason for it in this day and age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the third learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 08:04:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/11/21/startup-learnings-two-things-that-betsy-devine-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/11/21/startup-learnings-two-things-that-betsy-devine-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings - What Mark Bernstein Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;stay the course&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 07:51:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/21/startup-learnings-what-mark-bernstein-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/21/startup-learnings-what-mark-bernstein-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ansible for Configuring Your Mac - SO MUCH BETTER</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wow&lt;/strong&gt;.  That’s all I have to say.  &lt;strong&gt;Wow&lt;/strong&gt;.  So even tho I’m fully in the postmac world at this point with an Ubuntu-Mate box running 24/7 right alongside my Mac, I did just purchase a new mac – a top of the line previous generation PowerBook 13.  This at least got me a memory upgrade from the paltry 8 gigs on my Macbook Air to 16 gigs.  Yes it wasn’t the 32 gigs or 64 gigs that I wanted but I can suck it up – even though I still steadfastly maintain that Apple should have shipped Macbook Pros with more memory in a laptop form factor &lt;strong&gt;than they’ve been shipping since 2010&lt;/strong&gt;.  And no I’m not going to let that one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I’m now faced with configuring a brand new Mac.  I very specifically don’t want to use Time Machine in the event that any of my many recent issues are tied to cruft that has built up since my last machine.  So that’s out – damn it.  Which places me in the spot of an absolutely virgin install.  I haven’t done this in years.  And since I’m a developer that means I need a lot of stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xcode tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;all the normal unix crap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;server tools - mariadb, redis and the like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;frameworks like node&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rails / ruby / r* (note this is using rbenv / ruby build to see if I can get out of my current rvm hell; since I’m dumping rvm server side anyone this seemed like a good choice)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tmux, ah blessed tmux, the love-hate-hate relationship I have with you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to make matters worse I’m going on the road just after Thanksgiving so I really want this to be right.  I’d love to &lt;strong&gt;just&lt;/strong&gt; carry one laptop with me.  This means that it needs to be fully working – apps, data, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily data is already handled.  A few months ago &lt;a href=&quot;http://dasari.me&quot;&gt;Dv&lt;/a&gt; convinced me that Dropbox could handle everything I use on a daily basis so all my data syncs automatically as I work.  I can see the little Dropbox notices flashing by on all my boxes.  I honestly worry a hell of a lot less about Time Machine than I ever used to because the data I actually care about is a working set of 35 gigs of data which is ALWAYS in place on 1 of at least 4 development boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps are a very different matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ansible-stuff-i-learned-from-this-project&quot;&gt;Ansible Stuff I Learned From This Project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the things I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0.0.0.0 in hosts means “run this on the local box”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/homebrew_module.html&quot;&gt;homebrew module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/homebrew_cask_module.html&quot;&gt;homebrew_cask module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/playbooks_loops.html#id4&quot;&gt;file globbing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you haven’t recently been following the arcana of Mac package managers, brew installs command line things like, say, redis.  brew cask does the same thing for true mac apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references--examples-to-setting-up-your-mac-with-ansible&quot;&gt;References / Examples to Setting Up Your Mac with Ansible&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the sources I found are below.  There’s some great stuff here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/geerlingguy/mac-dev-playbook&quot;&gt;https://github.com/geerlingguy/mac-dev-playbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ricbra/mac-dev-playbook&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ricbra/mac-dev-playbook&lt;/a&gt; (I pulled my bootstrap dependencies from here; Thanks!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kojiitp/automation-of-installation-on-mac-w-ansible-21354cce0d7b#.duu26pqay&quot;&gt;https://medium.com/@kojiitp/automation-of-installation-on-mac-w-ansible-21354cce0d7b#.duu26pqay&lt;/a&gt; (great overview)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.vandenbrand.org/2016/01/04/how-to-automate-your-mac-os-x-setup-with-ansible/&quot;&gt;https://blog.vandenbrand.org/2016/01/04/how-to-automate-your-mac-os-x-setup-with-ansible/&lt;/a&gt; (also great overview)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickhammond.com/automating-development-environment-ansible/&quot;&gt;http://www.nickhammond.com/automating-development-environment-ansible/&lt;/a&gt; (solid)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fgimian/macbuild&quot;&gt;https://github.com/fgimian/macbuild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mpereira/macbook-playbook&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mpereira/macbook-playbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.vandenbrand.org/2016/01/04/how-to-automate-your-mac-os-x-setup-with-ansible/&quot;&gt;https://blog.vandenbrand.org/2016/01/04/how-to-automate-your-mac-os-x-setup-with-ansible/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up taking a slightly different approach.  I didn’t try to be as complete (I mean wow - setting your dock icons) but instead focused on the tools I use and I wanted to get my box to a usable state by morning (i.e. its 2 am when I started; I wanted to be running my code by say 8 am).  This constraint meant that I wasn’t going to get as specific as say mpereira in moving ssh keys over for example.  Nothing wrong with that approach but I want to think it over a bit more before I go there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Well I wrote the above playbook then I delved deeper into mpereira’s stuff and I thought “well this isn’t too bad” and damn it if I wasn’t moving over knownhosts pretty quick.  &lt;em&gt;chuckle&lt;/em&gt; – thanks man!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I don’t know if the SSH key stuff is right or wrong.  I still can’t push to github but I’m also having issues with even creating new ssh keys so maybe those issues are part of that.  Apologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In specific I find that Ansible stuff gets deep and confusing quickly.  I wanted to focus on the organization by clearly naming exactly what’s going on.  All my install roles, for example, start with “install_”.  I did everything with a focus on clarity right down to avoiding pkg lists; that just felt &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt; (verbose but right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s mine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/ansible-macbook-pro&quot;&gt;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/ansible-macbook-pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re at all technical I’d highly recommend this as an approach for setting up a new Mac.  I did some reading and then starting in about 4 hours I managed to get almost everything I needed setup.  Yes the per app config happened post install but I don’t think that I could have possibly installed just all the stuff I need manually in that amount of time.  Scratch that – I COULD NOT POSSIBLY HAVE DONE THIS AS QUICKLY.  &lt;strong&gt;Beyond Recommended&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/osx/2016/11/20/ansible-for-configuring-your-mac-so-much-better.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/osx/2016/11/20/ansible-for-configuring-your-mac-so-much-better.html</guid>
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
        
        <category>osx</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Engineer's Design Notebook or What's in the Notebook Scott?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past three months or so, one of my neighbors, also probably my wife’s best friend, H, has seen me walk to and fro around the neighborhood carrying with me a small notebook.  Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/spidey_notebook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;spidey_rules!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s seen me carry this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to drinks at her house&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to different kids birthday parties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to dinner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to my youngest son’s Veteran’s Day speech in his 4th grade choir where I wrote in it furiously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially it hasn’t left my side since say August 1.  Last night she finally broke down and said “So what’s in the notebook”.  Apparently she had seen me writing in it on Veteran’s day and it literally made no sense to her.  Ah and there’s the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done this most of my career starting back at NTERGAID, my first startup.  The notebook is a bound, non-removable page design notebook and the idea here is that whatever problem you’re solving, you write down whatever comes into your head.  And, here’s the smart thing, when you stop writing down the problem, that’s when you’re &lt;strong&gt;done&lt;/strong&gt; with the design phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every technical person has their own creative process, their flow if you will.  Me?  I like to nap and cook.  I know that sounds like a bit of an excuse for, well, slacking, but when I can’t solve something digital then I go entirely analog.  By getting out of own head so to speak I find that whatever the issue is, I’m better able to solve it.  Either I take a nap and wake up with the solution crystalized in my brain or I go cook something and then I’ll have it fully baked (you see what I did there ;-)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened back in August is we made the decision to go full in on AWS for our underlying server side platform. Although I’ve used AWS for years, it had always been in a supporting capacity.  This time it was damn the torpedos and learn it down to the metal / api.  This freed me from all the hardware woes that I’ve been chafing under since either 2010 or 2014 depending on how you measure my frustration level.  But it also unleashed a metric crap ton of “oh noes - how do I do X?” where X might have been:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;machine configuration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;job management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OS distro choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choice of AWS load balancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what the heck really is a vpc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/08/28/aws-tutorial-4-rds-data-loading-into-aurora-run-in-circles-scream-and-shout-the-oh-shite-moment.html&quot;&gt;Aurora - what the heck happened with our data loss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of those choices, and a whole heck of a lot more, got researched, documented and written down.  Once I stopped writing – on that topic – then I knew it was time to apply fingers to keyboard and get started.  And keep in mind that it isn’t like I wasn’t doing stuff with the code and infrastructure.  But what I did was make a very conscious choice to sit on the things that I didn’t feel I understood well enough to do competently.  Those I kept writing stuff down until I did understand them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not a proponent of an engineer’s design notebook then I’d recommend it the next time you have a hard problem to solve.  It goes everywhere with you - mine goes into the bathroom with me at times - and it is always next to my bed.  I’ve been known to wake up, write stuff down and then go back to sleep.  What you might find is that it really does help you crystalize your thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/11/19/the-engineer-s-design-notebook-or-what-s-in-the-notebook-scott.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/11/19/the-engineer-s-design-notebook-or-what-s-in-the-notebook-scott.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Nerd Humor Ever Bad Horse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Run to a terminal and type in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;traceroute bad.horse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in case you’re busy then just look below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;traceroute to bad.horse (162.252.205.157)e, 64 hops max, 52 byte packets

 1  192.168.7.1 (192.168.7.1)  20.162 ms  42.048 ms  17.285 ms

 2  router.asus.com (192.168.1.1)  12.877 ms  7.149 ms  40.287 ms

 3  64-184-12-1.dial.hrtc.net (64.184.12.1)  21.314 ms  10.632 ms  7.480 ms

 4  10.101.180.41 (10.101.180.41)  45.636 ms  8.450 ms  12.641 ms

 5  10.101.180.50 (10.101.180.50)  7.925 ms  48.465 ms  8.235 ms

 6  208-103-3-145.static.indianafiber.net (208.103.3.145)  7.889 ms  8.887 ms  9.435 ms

 7  69-160-211-29.static.indianafiber.net (69.160.211.29)  48.128 ms  9.494 ms  9.668 ms

 8  xe-10-3-0.bar2.cincinnati1.level3.net (4.59.42.17)  16.287 ms  16.806 ms  14.170 ms

 9  ae-1-24.bar1.minneapolis2.level3.net (4.69.202.201)  70.641 ms  35.369 ms  43.137 ms

10  iphouse.bar1.minneapolis2.level3.net (4.59.66.14)  29.444 ms  25.986 ms  23.918 ms

11  c4500-1.mpls.iphouse.net (216.250.189.170)  51.107 ms  56.208 ms  24.608 ms

12  egw-iphouse.mplsc1.mn.us.sn11.net (216.243.189.213)  24.495 ms  25.514 ms  60.577 ms

13  t04.nycmc1.ny.us.sn11.net (162.252.204.70)  102.675 ms  96.673 ms  100.029 ms

14  bad.horse (162.252.205.130)  101.271 ms  99.932 ms  102.332 ms

15  bad.horse (162.252.205.131)  102.326 ms  94.996 ms  101.067 ms

16  bad.horse (162.252.205.132)  107.957 ms  95.396 ms  87.307 ms

17  bad.horse (162.252.205.133)  97.516 ms  98.652 ms  99.891 ms

18  he.rides.across.the.nation (162.252.205.134)  104.673 ms  103.679 ms  99.420 ms

19  the.thoroughbred.of.sin (162.252.205.135)  108.501 ms  253.694 ms  102.826 ms

20  he.got.the.application (162.252.205.136)  114.348 ms  370.569 ms  107.795 ms

21  that.you.just.sent.in (162.252.205.137)  297.494 ms  113.336 ms  256.924 ms

22  it.needs.evaluation (162.252.205.138)  207.517 ms  374.252 ms  205.866 ms

23  so.let.the.games.begin (162.252.205.139)  205.145 ms  367.291 ms  205.401 ms

24  a.heinous.crime (162.252.205.140)  204.442 ms  361.310 ms  205.329 ms

25  a.show.of.force (162.252.205.141)  204.773 ms  371.382 ms  205.005 ms

26  a.murder.would.be.nice.of.course (162.252.205.142)  205.203 ms  373.475 ms  206.626 ms

27  bad.horse (162.252.205.143)  408.928 ms  362.920 ms  204.462 ms

28  bad.horse (162.252.205.144)  205.905 ms  370.026 ms  207.310 ms

29  bad.horse (162.252.205.145)  406.761 ms  369.261 ms  206.209 ms

30  he-s.bad (162.252.205.146)  409.015 ms  188.808 ms  393.414 ms

31  the.evil.league.of.evil (162.252.205.147)  409.592 ms  374.356 ms  293.717 ms

32  is.watching.so.beware (162.252.205.148)  320.543 ms  363.696 ms  410.274 ms

33  the.grade.that.you.receive (162.252.205.149)  410.203 ms *  271.494 ms

34  will.be.your.last.we.swear (162.252.205.150)  409.280 ms  373.618 ms  409.434 ms

35  so.make.the.bad.horse.gleeful (162.252.205.151)  409.843 ms  374.763 ms  411.339 ms

36  or.he-ll.make.you.his.mare (162.252.205.152)  408.399 ms  373.685 ms  409.575 ms

37  o_o (162.252.205.153)  408.921 ms  409.727 ms  409.859 ms

38  you-re.saddled.up (162.252.205.154)  204.202 ms  407.804 ms  408.702 ms

39  there-s.no.recourse (162.252.205.155)  410.606 ms  408.781 ms  410.039 ms

40  it-s.hi-ho.silver (162.252.205.156)  409.493 ms  352.177 ms  408.002 ms

41  signed.bad.horse (162.252.205.157)  409.040 ms  341.895 ms  407.980 ms    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/humor/2016/11/18/best-nerd-humor-ever-bad-horse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/humor/2016/11/18/best-nerd-humor-ever-bad-horse.html</guid>
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Efficiently Producing Iced Coffee</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 04:37:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/17/efficiently-producing-iced-coffee.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/11/17/efficiently-producing-iced-coffee.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Learnings - Something My Dad Taught Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My father has been an independent business man my entire life and he’s really operated in the same industry – the marine industry on the east coast of the U.S. He’s worked on the commercial side and the recreational side and he’s been both very successful and less successful depending on the venture.  One of the things he has always maintained is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All industries are small and your reputation really matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first got into computing I disregarded this more than a bit.  I was in the &lt;em&gt;computer business&lt;/em&gt; after all it was a massive, globe spanning industry.  That old saw that my Dad emphasized so strongly couldn’t possibly be true, could it?  Interestingly enough it actually is true and here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-smallness-of-an-industry-the-first---discovering-blogging&quot;&gt;The Smallness of an Industry the First - Discovering Blogging&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Back in 2002 I discovered blogging and that was a wonderful, transformative experience for me that ripples through my life to this day.  The tool I initially used was UserLand Radio from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;.  There’s a whole tale and learning with respect to that experience, including how I came to be an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Essential-Blogging-Selecting-Using-Weblog/dp/0596003889/ref=sr_1_10?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1479377306&amp;amp;sr=8-10&amp;amp;keywords=o%27reilly+blogging+book&quot;&gt;O’Reilly author&lt;/a&gt;, that I’ll tell one of these days.  In the course of learning the product I got to know Dave Winer.  UserLand was Dave’s second venture.  His first was a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Living_Videotext&quot;&gt;Living VideoText&lt;/a&gt; which made outlining software.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51MGqGUE96L._SX374_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oreilly_blogging_book&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those software products was a tool called Ready! which was a Terminate and Stay Resident (TSR) program.  TSRs, now long forgotten, were an attempt to get around the single tasking nature of MS-DOS.  They were loaded into a chunk of memory and then assigned a hot key.  This let you trigger them quickly without unloading your current software.  The curious thing here is the software engineer who wrote the TSR kernel for Ready! was named &lt;em&gt;Bobby Bierman&lt;/em&gt;.  Bobby was brilliant and into computing way before anyone else I ever knew – I remember him back from the pre Apple days when I wasn’t even a teenager yet.  Now here’s the weird part.  Bobby belonged to my father’s scout troop when he was in high school and then later worked for one of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rgbrewer.com/&quot;&gt;family businesses&lt;/a&gt; before he went off to MIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bobby was more than a few years older than me and I had always known he went west to Silicon Valley but I never associated him with myself even after I got into computing until 15 years later when I realized that I was directly interacting with Bobby’s former boss.  This was my first &lt;strong&gt;smack in the face&lt;/strong&gt; clue that industries really are small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-smallness-of-an-industry-the-second---mark-fletcher--marc-hedlund&quot;&gt;The Smallness of an Industry the Second - Mark Fletcher / Marc Hedlund&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been lots and lots of “wow this industry really is small” experiences over the years but another that sticks out happened on September 7 of this year.  I noticed some chatter on Twitter about AWS deployment by Marc Hedlund and I shot him an email.  He very, very graciously granted me access to the Skyliner slack team and responded with this comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Thanks! I’m looking forward to chatting with you more. By the way, I enjoyed your post on my friend Mark Fletcher (https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/08/31/what-mark-fletcher-taught-me.html) — I’ve taken similar lessons from him and have long admired how he ran Bloglines. He also consistently has the best industry gossip. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go figure – a founder of a product that I’m interested in using happens to know someone that I haven’t spoken to since 2006.  I mean sheesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skyliner.io&quot;&gt;Skyliner.io&lt;/a&gt; just launched.  Congrats to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-smallness-of-an-industry-the-third---shimon-rura&quot;&gt;The Smallness of an Industry the Third - Shimon Rura&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve mulled over what my Dad taught me for years but I never felt compelled to write it down until today.  What led directly to this post was I noticed that Dropbox was syncing log files between boxes on my new UbuntuMate desktop and I thought to myself &lt;em&gt;well that sucks&lt;/em&gt;.  A quick google led me to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://superuser.com/questions/469776/how-to-exclude-files-not-folders-from-dropbox-sync&quot;&gt;SuperUser&lt;/a&gt; post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/shimon_superuser.png&quot; alt=&quot;shimon_superuser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was a lightning bolt of inspiration.  Damn.  I &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; him.  And I don’t mean that in the “oh I’ve read his blog”.  Once upon a time I used to know him in meat space aka the real world.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://rura.org/shimon/&quot;&gt;Shimon&lt;/a&gt; is an absolutely standup guy who used to be part of the Boston Blogging crowd out of the Berkman center at Harvard.  He and I used to share nerd issues in the blogging world and then eat indian food.  Curiously there’s another level of intersection with blogging in that Dave Winer actually organized those meetings when he lived in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t spoken to Shimon in more than a decade since I moved to Indiana but I still notice him from time to time on Facebook; he just had a child so Mazeltov!  And thanks for the excellent answer on SuperUser.  Appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;review-and-conclusion&quot;&gt;Review and Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Dad has operated his whole business career in a small geographic region really from New York to Connecticut and in an industry with tiny gross revenues with comparison to the industry in which I make my career but his point &lt;em&gt;All industries really are small; reputation matters&lt;/em&gt; is still absolutely true.  Thanks Dad!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/11/17/startup-learnings-something-my-dad-taught-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/startup/2016/11/17/startup-learnings-something-my-dad-taught-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>learnings</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
