<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff.  Ruby / Rails / Elixir.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 12:08:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 12:08:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails Post Mortem - An Analysis of Breaking the Build</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Making this blog post public as opposed to an internal document might ruffle some feathers.  I’d like to point out here that no has been called out by name and at least part of the responsibility trail here is &lt;strong&gt;mine&lt;/strong&gt; and I have no issues with accepting that.  The only way to learn from our mistakes is honesty  and this post was written in that spirit.  It is how all of us get better at our jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often tell my kids that when something goes wrong I care less about what went wrong and more about responsibility, specifically, whether or not you accept responsibility for it.  When something goes wrong accepting the responsibility for it, if it was actually your fault, to &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;, is a big deal.  If you don’t accept responsibility for your mistakes then you cannot learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the situation where a new hire broke the build.  And he broke it after 5 pm on a friday when mission critical work had to be done over the weekend. Sigh.  And, of course, he was offline when I found out so it fell on me to untangle it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistake-01-mine---accepting-the-change-on-a-friday&quot;&gt;Mistake 01: Mine - Accepting the Change on a Friday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the end of the week and I’d been busy and heads down all week on devops stuff.  I wanted to get his changes merged so I did take the change without my normal level of “it’s a friday; deny, deny, deny and then deny some more” commentary.  I should never, &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; have taken changes from anyone other than myself on a Friday afternoon.  Why?  Because, ultimately I’m in charge.  And when a crawl blows up partway through it is on me to fix it.  No one here carries pagers or is expected, other than myself, to be up in the middle of the night dealing with crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistake-02-his---over-scoping-the-work&quot;&gt;Mistake 02: His - Over Scoping the Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The individual in question had a ticket in his queue that read “Figure out what gems in gemfile we should throw out”.  This is a classic learning exercise that I often give to new hires.  Gemfile is often a bit like Mos Eisley in a Rails project - a wretched hive of scum and villany.  Gems accrete there – you need a tool for a one off hack and a gem gets added.  And then its not used and the one off hack goes away.  But the gem never goes away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did the analysis but then he decided to re-organize the Gemfile and alphabetize it.  And this was at the core of the problem.  I asked for analysis.  I didn’t ask for change specifically because I wanted to make that change gently, carefully and on my own.  Now I could absolutely have pushed back and said “Nope!  Don’t want it; didn’t ask for it; redo.”  But that would kind of be a jerk move. He clearly put thought and effort into this so as a person who manages people its better for their growth and development to follow the process end to end even when you think it might be a damn disaster waiting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as old engineers are wont do, we tell tales and we bitch about parts of software that we find odious.  Personally I’m not a fan of Gemfile and the whole gem stack in general in Rails.  Of all the things that give me issues in Rails, I find the overall fragility of the Gem stack and bundler to be the absolute worst part.  I know for a fact that he’s heard this rant.  However, whether or not he listened is unclear…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistake-03-his---moving-things-from-main-to-development-test-groups&quot;&gt;Mistake 03: His - Moving Things From Main to Development, Test Groups&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mistake that was made was his decision to move things from the main context in Gemfile to solely development and test.  The gem in question was pry and, for some reason, it not being present broke the running system.  His defense was “I’ve never seen an installation where pry needed to be in production”.  That’s fine but the reality with big complex software systems is that understanding side effects of changes is hard.  And when your boss has specifically called out the area in which you &lt;strong&gt;chose&lt;/strong&gt; to make complex changes, you need to approach it with caution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistake-04-his---introducing-things-not-present-prior-in-gemfile&quot;&gt;Mistake 04: His - Introducing Things Not Present Prior in Gemfile&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw pry in the Gemfile, I initially thought that he had introduced it and I pushed back on it.  Nope.  He was right – pry was part of the system.  It was an innocuous “gem ‘pry’” on or about line #65 and I was the one who had to add it once upon a time.  I’ve never been a pry fan despite its relative hotness within the community.  Now when he saw pry and moved it into the development and test groups, he also added pry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The person making the change introduced two additional, pry-rails and pry-byebug.  I don’t know what these do and the system is now breaking so I commented them out immediately.  And was that conservative of me?  Yes.  And was that reactionary of me?  Sure.  Maybe these are great gems that will rock my world but when a) the system is breaking and b) the goal was find out what’s not used, adding new gems shouldn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistake-05-his---mysqlplus&quot;&gt;Mistake 05: His - Mysqlplus&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best bits of work that this person has done for us so far is he got the mysqlplus gem working again.  Why we need this crufty old bit of code is irrelevant (or the subject of another blog post) but we absolutely do need it.  And where I couldn’t make it work in Ruby 2.3.1 and Dv couldn’t make it work, he pulled it off and that was absolutely, &lt;strong&gt;stellar&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;wonderful&lt;/strong&gt; work.  I simply cannot say enough good things about this.  Unfortunately when he refactored Gemfile it was &lt;em&gt;commented out&lt;/em&gt; and it not being there promptly broke all of our crawlers.  This was essentially a copy and paste refactor issue.  When he started the Gemfile project he hadn’t yet done the mysqlplus work so the gem, which at that point in time was broken, was commented out.  And, unfortunately, despite the good work he had done, stayed commented out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that it broke our crawlers is is that our crawlers are based on Rails but have their own dependency load structure so how they interact with Gemfile is complex.  And they also rely on this bit of trickery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class Mysql; alias :query :async_query; end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That takes the async_query method in mysqlplus and dynamically replaces query with it.  This eliminates blocking at the query level and improves our threaded performance by roughly 50%.  And because this is dynamically injected, when something isn’t present in Gemfile, there’s no way to know except for actually executing the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is the point about complex software systems – when you don’t fully understand them – you need to approach &lt;strong&gt;dangerous changes with care&lt;/strong&gt;.  He may not have perceived Gemfile as dangerous but I made damn sure that the rant was given because I do know the danger of messing with Gemfile.  The bottom line here is that you don’t change global things without a hell of a lot of care.  And you certainly don’t change it on a Friday afternoon.  And, remember, I accepted the changes and that was my error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistake-06-mine-no-monitoring-on-parts-of-our-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Mistake 06: Mine No Monitoring on Parts of our Infrastructure&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another mistake that I made was when our new AWS bits were setup, I didn’t immediately set up monitoring on a few production urls.  Since this is mainly an internal system which produces data that is ingested by Tableau, monitoring has never been a priority.  Again that’s on me.  If I had had monitoring setup I would have found at 3 on a Friday instead of at 5.  And since he would still have been online all of this would have been easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mistakes-other&quot;&gt;Mistakes Other&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was at least one other issue related to the Curses gem but I don’t think its particularly relevant here.  I had been in the middle of doing ansible work on devops and I saw our Ansible work failing and went sideways debugging it thinking the issue was me when it was really the lack of the curses gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;some-things-are-debatable-other-things-are-not&quot;&gt;Some Things are Debatable; Other Things Are Not&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this topic came up on a slack chat between this individual and myself, he gave me a lot of push back like the “I’ve never seen pry in production”.  And I’ll definitely admit that some technical topics are debatable.  Perhaps there is something critically wrong with our code that pry is needed in production.  Or maybe it was something else and adding pry causes another dependency to come in which fixed it.  I’m not 100% certain because I had production systems that needed to get running again and simply reversing a few of his changes was the most expedient way to do that.  So while we can debate aspects of his changes, what isn’t debatable, is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He chose to make changes above and beyond the requested scope of work – which was analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The production, running system entirely broke – website, backend, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me this is fairly incontrovertible – you broke the build.  Now this isn’t a huge deal to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New hires break things and no data was lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We lost about an hour and a half of crawling time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I resolved the issues in less than 30 minutes and had us up and running again before dinner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It took longer to write this post mortem than it did to fix the issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing I also should state that the alphabetized Gemfile is better organized and will be better for maintenance long term.  He also did a great job of preserving the cruft that was there previously which illustrated history and intent and I do appreciate that.  I simply should have been more diligent before I accepted these changes.  We lack a staging server for this project and I will ticket for myself the task of getting one built so we have a place to tackle sweeping changes like these.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/10/02/rails-an-analysis-of-breaking-the-build.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/10/02/rails-an-analysis-of-breaking-the-build.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Tutorial 12 - Using Ansible to Quickly Fix Your Server's TCP Connections</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The bulk of my coding is actually back end coding and I spent a lot of time dealing with network programming issues.  We’ve been running for years in a data center that I put together and every box was finely tuned.  Unfortunately due to the massive issues surrounding Chef, we were never able to maintain boxes automatically so every server became a unique snowflake – well set up and such but I have no idea now what changes we made to tune each server over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we still have that data center active, we’re now crawling on our AWS boxes and much happier but we’re still working the kinks out.  This morning I started seeing this appear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Cannot assign requested address.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was appearing in the context of our Redis connections.  And, sure enough, we had a routine which was creating a handle to redis every, single, time it was handling a url.  That’s bad.  So the easy fix was to pass the connection in from a higher level.  But even after that it was still an issue.  Some quick research brought me to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10980850/solveredis-localhost6379-cannot-assign-requested-address&quot;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10980850/solveredis-localhost6379-cannot-assign-requested-address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://redis4you.com/articles.php?id=012&amp;amp;name=redis&quot;&gt;http://redis4you.com/articles.php?id=012&amp;amp;name=redis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the recommended solution is to fix a running box with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo 1 &amp;gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/tcp_tw_reuse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and put the same fix into:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; /etc/rc.local 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-ansible-ize-this&quot;&gt;How to Ansible-ize This&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that we have a bunch of AWS nodes setup, I don’t really want to make this change manually so let’s script it with Ansible and run it as a role.  Here’s what to do for the directory where your Ansible stuff resides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mkdir -p roles/machine_setup_tcp_tw_reuse/tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;touch roles/machine_setup_tcp_tw_reuse/tasks/main.yml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your main.yml file you want this code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# this sets it for the machine permanently after the machine restarts
- name: update /etc/rc.local for tcp_tw_reuse (faster tcp recycling) on machines which are servers 
  lineinfile: dest=/etc/rc.local regexp=&quot;^echo 1 &amp;gt; &quot;  line=&quot;echo 1 &amp;gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/tcp_tw_reuse&quot;
  
# this fixes the current machine state
- name: execute the fix on the currently running machine instance
  shell: &quot;echo 1 &amp;gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/tcp_tw_reuse&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your main playbook.yml you want to call this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;- hosts: all
  become: yes
  remote_user: ubuntu
  roles:
- { role: machine_setup_tcp_tw_reuse, tags: machine_setup_tcp_tw_reuse}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-run-this&quot;&gt;How to Run this&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can run this using the following syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ansible-playbook -i inventories/production_actual playbook.yml --tags &quot;machine_setup_tcp_tw_reuse&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-verify-the-fix&quot;&gt;How to Verify the Fix&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To verify this, you can do what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ssh into a box&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cat /proc/sys/net/ipv4/tcp_tw_reuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a 1 there then the fix actually worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for the small level of granularity on this role is that I’m now using Ansible to fix issues on production running hosts.  And I wanted to be able to run &lt;strong&gt;just&lt;/strong&gt; this role.  Ansible has tagging which I do believe would let me have this embedded within my overall machine_setup task but this felt safer since I’m still a noob at Ansible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/10/02/aws-tutorial-12-using-ansible-to-quickly-fix-your-server-s-tcp-connections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/10/02/aws-tutorial-12-using-ansible-to-quickly-fix-your-server-s-tcp-connections.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>redis</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Tutorial 11 - An Ansible Role for Installing AWS Cloud Watch Monitoring On Ubuntu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve written here earlier, Ansible is a provisioning and management tool that you can use to enable better automated provisioning of your AWS machines.  While I am &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/09/06/aws-i-was-wrong-dead-wrong.html&quot;&gt;absolutely in love with AWS&lt;/a&gt;, one thing that I do think that CloudWatch got wrong is that there is no memory graphs when you use CloudWatch to monitor your machines.  Given that I write threaded applications all the time, knowing how my memory utilization looks is a vital diagnostic tool.  And while there is a way to do this, it requires a fair bit of systems administration to accomplish it since it requires code to be installed on every server to be monitored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we need to make a change to every box we have and to all new boxes we will create, who are we going to call?  Ansible!!!  That’s right – in this tutorial we’re going to use Ansible to write a playbook and role for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;downloading required modules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;downloading the code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;installing the code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;inserting our AWS keys&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;creating a cron job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-our-structure&quot;&gt;Creating our Structure&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ansible is flexible in how things can be structured, I use a standard approach.  All of the code here is available on my github (link at the end) but I find that writing it all out helps my understanding at least.  Here’s how to create the structure that I use for Ansible.  All of this assumes you are already in a project directory where you want to store this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir inventories
touch inventories/production
mkdir -p roles/aws_cloudwatch_memory/tasks
mkdir -p roles/aws_cloudwatch_memory/vars
touch roles/aws_cloudwatch_memory/tasks/main.yml
touch roles/roles/aws_cloudwatch_memory/vars/main.yml
# note - if you want to encrypt your aws keys that don't do the next step and do it below under Ansible Vault
touch ansible.cfg
touch playbook.yml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;core-ansible-concepts-inventory-playbook-role-var&quot;&gt;Core Ansible Concepts: Inventory, Playbook, Role, Var&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many automation products, Ansible is built around some core concepts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inventory - a list of the machine resources to create, update or destroy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playbook - a list of the roles to apply to each machine resource&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Role - what to do with a machine.  This can be very complex including tasks, variables, files to copy to and from, services to restart and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Var - a list of variables to use in your role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-inventory&quot;&gt;The Inventory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the inventory file you want a format very similar to an old fashioned .ini file.  Here’s what mine looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[web]
fiworker2    ansible_ssh_host=ec2-52-41-237-52.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com        ansible_ssh_private_key_file=/Users/sjohnson/.ssh/fi_nav_sitecrawl.pem
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The syntax I’m using is human_readable_name  ansible_ssh_host=  ansible_ssh_private_key_file=&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you can generate the inventory file automatically with code, I don’t have a ton of AWS instances yet so I’ve just listed them manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-playbook&quot;&gt;The Playbook&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the playbook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;- hosts: all
  become: yes
  remote_user: ubuntu
  roles:
    - { role: aws_cloudwatch_memory, tags: aws_cloudwatch_memory}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to read this is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run the playbook on all hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run the playbook as sudo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run the playbook with the remote user ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run the role aws_cloudwatch_memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-role&quot;&gt;The Role&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the role:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
  
- name: Install CloudWatch libraries
  apt: pkg=
       state=installed
  with_items:
    - unzip
    - libwww-perl
    - libdatetime-perl

- name: download scripts
  get_url: url=http://aws-cloudwatch.s3.amazonaws.com/downloads/CloudWatchMonitoringScripts-1.2.1.zip dest=/tmp/CloudWatchMonitoringScripts.zip

- name: chown the file and make it writeable
  file: path=/tmp/CloudWatchMonitoringScripts.zip mode=0755  #owner=ubuntu group=ubuntu 

- name: unzip the scripts
  # note - unarchive should work but it fails; maybe an ansible issue?  shell: to the rescue!
  #unarchive: src=/tmp/CloudWatchMonitoringScripts.zip dest=/tmp/
  shell: &quot;cd /tmp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; unzip /tmp/CloudWatchMonitoringScripts.zip&quot;

- name: delete archive
  file: path=/tmp/CloudWatchMonitoringScripts.zip state=absent

- name: set Access key in credentials file
  replace: dest=/tmp/aws-scripts-mon/awscreds.template regexp='AWSAccessKeyId=' replace='AWSAccessKeyId=' backup=yes

- name: set Secret key in credentials file
  replace: dest=/tmp/aws-scripts-mon/awscreds.template regexp='AWSSecretKey=' replace='AWSSecretKey=' backup=yes

- name: move directory out of /tmp
  command: mv /tmp/aws-scripts-mon/ /root/ creates=/root/aws-scripts-mon/

- name: add command to cron
  lineinfile: dest=/etc/crontab insertafter=EOF line=&quot;* * * * * root /root/aws-scripts-mon/mon-put-instance-data.pl --mem-util --mem-used --mem-avail --aws-credential-file=/root/aws-scripts-mon/awscreds.template&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-ansible-vault-for-the-vars-file&quot;&gt;Using Ansible Vault for the vars file&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the roles directory there is a vars directory and a file main.yml within it.  This file will contain our variables that define our AWS access key and AWS secret.  Given that this file will likely be checked into version control, there’s value in encrypting those variables.  The tool Ansible Vault is used for that.  Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the command:  ansible-vault create roles/aws_cloudwatch_memory/vars/main.yml&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This will ask your for a password.  Enter one and confirm it and then you’ll be launched into an editor where you can put in your keys.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exit the editor and it will save your now encrypted data.  You can then edit it later with: ansible-vault edit roles/aws_cloudwatch_memory/vars/main.yml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on the Ansible Vault is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/playbooks_vault.html&quot;&gt;docs.ansible.com site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vars file needs to look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ec2_access_key: &quot;foo&quot;
ec2_secret_key: &quot;bar&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously these would be replaced with real values.  By storing this file in rolename/vars/main.yml location and format, Ansible knows to load this file automatically when the role is executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ansiblecfg-file&quot;&gt;The ansible.cfg file&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may, or may not, need a ansible.cfg file.  This is an ASCII file that defines how to handle ssh connectivity.  Here’s mine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ssh_connection]
ssh_user = vagrant
scp_if_ssh = True
control_path = %(directory)s/%%h-%%r
ansible_ssh_private_key_file = /Users/sjohnson/.ssh/fi_nav_sitecrawl.pem
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not, at the time of this writing, a true Ansible expert so I suspect there’s redundancy in my cfg file but when I run without it, I’m unable to connect to AWS and I think it’s due to the control_path setting being required due to the length of the EC2 host names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;running-this&quot;&gt;Running This&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s all you need to do to run this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ansible-playbook -i inventories/production playbook.yml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you encrypted your keys then you’ll be prompted for the password.  If you want to store the password in a local file on your machine then you can always do it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ansible-playbook -i inventories/production playbook.yml --vault-password-file ~/.vault_pass.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;code-on-git&quot;&gt;Code on Git&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is published on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/ansible_cloud_watch_memory_monitoring&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some great references&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/weirdbricks/3e0d0e3428f3d683ccfa&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/weirdbricks/3e0d0e3428f3d683ccfa&lt;/a&gt;  This is the gist I started from; it was for Redhat / CentOS and used Yum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudWatch/latest/monitoring/mon-scripts.html&quot;&gt;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudWatch/latest/monitoring/mon-scripts.html&lt;/a&gt;  This is the canonical documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.krishnachaitanya.ch/2016/03/monitor-ec2-memory-usage-using-aws.html&quot;&gt;http://blog.krishnachaitanya.ch/2016/03/monitor-ec2-memory-usage-using-aws.html&lt;/a&gt; Good tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/10/01/aws-tutorial-11-an-ansible-role-for-installing-aws-cloud-watch-monitoring-on-ubuntu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/10/01/aws-tutorial-11-an-ansible-role-for-installing-aws-cloud-watch-monitoring-on-ubuntu.html</guid>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>cloudwatch</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Tutorial 10 - Diagnosing SSH Failures or When Ping Works But SSH Fails</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just had the issue where a Capistrano deploy onto our AWS cluster of boxes failed.  This let me into the following process of debugging:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can I ping each box?  Yes!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can I ssh into each box?  No!  The box we name ficrawler2 was unable to be ssh’d into and gave this error:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;ssh ficrawler2
ssh_exchange_identification: read: Operation timed out&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next action was to look at the instance in the web console and discover that it was actually reachable from the perspective of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System reachability check passed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instance reachability check passed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/aws/aws_tutorial_10_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;aws_tutorial_10_01.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me think that SSH itself went down but external network metrics like ping remained up.  Next step up is to reboot the box.  And I did that and the problem persisted.  This led me to thinking that there’s a lower level problem here, possibly network layer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now from my ssh config tutorial you might know that my ssh config file defined ficrawler2.  Here are the particulars:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host ficrawler2
    Hostname ec2-54-68-16-169.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com
    User ubuntu
    IdentityFile /Users/sjohnson/.ssh/fi_nav_sitecrawl.pem
    Port 22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this lets us construct a debuggable ssh connect line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh -i &quot;/Users/sjohnson/.ssh/fi_nav_sitecrawl.pem&quot; ubuntu@54.68.16.169 -vv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of the ssh -i line above will be a very long string of ssh commands showing what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately by the time I did the research to figure this out and setup this blog post, ssh returned and I’m left scratching my head more than a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we now know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A box can be ping’able but not ssh’able&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next time I may want to not reboot so quickly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A reboot doesn’t necessarily clear it up so the underlying box might actually have been fine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need to write the ssh test line faster next time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is very unclear how AWS cloud watch can be used to test for a box that is unable to be ssh’d into; that may not be viable (monitoring it could actually be construed as an attack)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/10/01/aws-tutorial-10-diagnosing-ssh-failures-or-when-ping-works-but-ssh-fails.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/aws/2016/10/01/aws-tutorial-10-diagnosing-ssh-failures-or-when-ping-works-but-ssh-fails.html</guid>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        <category>ssh</category>
        
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Ansible to Drive Down Hosting Costs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since the Fall of 2014 I have been trapped in an &lt;strong&gt;dysfunctional relationship&lt;/strong&gt; that I have been unable to leave.  No I’m not talking about a spouse, a boyfriend or a girlfriend.  I’m talking about my hosting company where all my Rails applications live.  And, while I’m talking about Rails, it doesn’t have to be Rails.  It could be PHP, Python, Go, Elixir or anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I refer to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;economic paradox of hosting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the day you arrange to use hardware from a hosting company you should be paying the MOST ever for your hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your bills almost always go UP not DOWN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue at hand here is that your hosting company knows that the longer you have a box with them, the more valuable that box becomes to you.  And the paradox is that the value of hardware falls over time.  That 24 gig of RAM box that you contracted for in 2014?  Well it should likely be a 36 gig of RAM box in 2015.  And it would be if you bought it again.  But you didn’t buy it again – you stayed with the machine you had – and your hosting company knows this.  So even tho the machine you’re renting today is worth less than it was when you started with it, your price per month hasn’t gone done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;servers-should-never-be-unique-snowflakes&quot;&gt;Servers Should Never Be Unique Snowflakes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the single best concepts that I’ve learned from cloud computing and all the time I’ve spent doing AWS is that servers should never be unique snowflakes. Servers should be identical resources that you just have.  They should be something that you &lt;strong&gt;generate&lt;/strong&gt; and build dynamically as needed.  Need a web server – just generate one.  Need a worker box?  Just generate another one.  And, you know what, even if you have your own infrastructure, its &lt;strong&gt;still true&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ansible-versus-chef&quot;&gt;Ansible Versus Chef&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the past week deeply immersed in devops using Ansible.  Ansible is a declarative approach to machine configuration and it is far, far beyond procedural approaches to machine configuration like puppet or chef – the tools I had used previously.  In 2014 I and one other engineer used Chef to provision a data center for 3 applications and over a 45 day period we never actually finished.  We took Chef as far as we were able to and then we had to finish the process manually and every time we needed to make a change to a box, after things were “setup”, we had to do it manually.  Here’s a comment from the other engineer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;with chef, I had no idea after all that time, where I should put what file
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here was my comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Chef was a f***ing disaster.  Make that my bad decision of 2014.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In about 4 days of on and off work I have not only duplicated every single bit of the chef provisioning work that I had done previously but:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Its testable using vagrant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Its repeatable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All the tools I rely on are there&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can add new boxes just by modifying a single inventory file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even things I used to have to do manually I can now automate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve improved security my adopting elements of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://12factor.net&quot;&gt;12 factor approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-this-bring-down-our-costs&quot;&gt;How Does this Bring Down Our Costs?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well if machines aren’t unique snowflakes, if they are things you can regenerate then you have the ability to better negotiate your rates.  When you’re prepared to go elsewhere, you’ll have the confidence to actually explore your alternatives.  I’ve never even considered moving from the hosting company I went to in 2014 purely because of the amount of effort it would entail.  Now that I can programmatically build the infrastructure I need?  You can bet that I’ll either be asking for lower rates or moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ansible/2016/09/30/using-ansible-to-drive-down-hosting-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ansible/2016/09/30/using-ansible-to-drive-down-hosting-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>hosting</category>
        
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ansible Tutorial 01 - Examples of Ansible Ad Hoc Commands</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My writing progress has slowed as of late while I have gone 100% heads down on learning Ansible.  Ansible is a provisioning tool which lets you describe a machine or machines as well as how you want them configured.  Ansible also offers an ad hoc mode where you can operate on a group of machines and execute a command or commands.  These examples are based on an Ansible inventory file located in the directory inventories/ as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;file: inventories/production_actual

[web]
# format - english machinename   ssh host   ssh private key
web1  ansible_ssh_host=ec2-52-41-237-52.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com  ansible_ssh_private_key_file=/Users/sjohnson/.ssh/fi_nav_sitecrawl.pe

[db]

[log]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note - in my actual inventory file there are machines in each group section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Execute uptime against all machines in the inventories file with the user ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;**ansible all -i inventories/production_actual -u ubuntu -a &quot;uptime&quot;**
ec2-52-39-100-178.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
 17:09:56 up 36 days,  4:05,  4 users,  load average: 0.99, 1.00, 0.97

ec2-52-89-105-4.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
 17:10:06 up 23 days,  4:17,  2 users,  load average: 0.69, 0.53, 0.54

ec2-54-68-16-169.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
 17:11:43 up 22 days,  9:11,  2 users,  load average: 0.93, 0.93, 0.89

ec2-52-42-166-105.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
 17:11:23 up 31 days,  7:26,  2 users,  load average: 0.00, 0.02, 0.05

52.40.224.171 | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
 17:10:54 up 20 days, 23:42,  1 user,  load average: 0.08, 0.04, 0.05
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Execute uptime against all machines in the db group in the inventories file with the user ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;**ansible db -i inventories/production_actual -u ubuntu -a &quot;uptime&quot;**
ec2-52-39-100-178.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
 17:11:13 up 36 days,  4:06,  4 users,  load average: 0.90, 0.97, 0.96
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use this to do things like check the amount of free disc space on every box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;**ansible all -i inventories/production_actual -u ubuntu -a &quot;df -h&quot;**
ec2-54-68-16-169.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
Filesystem      Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
udev            7.5G   12K  7.5G   1% /dev
tmpfs           1.5G  376K  1.5G   1% /run
/dev/xvda1      7.8G  3.9G  3.5G  53% /
none            4.0K     0  4.0K   0% /sys/fs/cgroup
none            5.0M     0  5.0M   0% /run/lock
none            7.5G     0  7.5G   0% /run/shm
none            100M     0  100M   0% /run/user

ec2-52-42-166-105.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
Filesystem      Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
udev            492M   12K  492M   1% /dev
tmpfs           100M  368K   99M   1% /run
/dev/xvda1      7.8G  3.7G  3.7G  51% /
none            4.0K     0  4.0K   0% /sys/fs/cgroup
none            5.0M     0  5.0M   0% /run/lock
none            497M     0  497M   0% /run/shm
none            100M     0  100M   0% /run/user

ec2-52-89-105-4.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
Filesystem      Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
udev            7.5G   12K  7.5G   1% /dev
tmpfs           1.5G  376K  1.5G   1% /run
/dev/xvda1       16G  3.9G   11G  27% /
none            4.0K     0  4.0K   0% /sys/fs/cgroup
none            5.0M     0  5.0M   0% /run/lock
none            7.5G     0  7.5G   0% /run/shm
none            100M     0  100M   0% /run/user

ec2-52-39-100-178.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
Filesystem      Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
udev             32G   12K   32G   1% /dev
tmpfs           6.3G  400K  6.3G   1% /run
/dev/xvda1      2.0T  1.4T  557G  71% /
none            4.0K     0  4.0K   0% /sys/fs/cgroup
none            5.0M     0  5.0M   0% /run/lock
none             32G     0   32G   0% /run/shm
none            100M     0  100M   0% /run/user

52.40.224.171 | success | rc=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
Filesystem      Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
udev            3.9G   12K  3.9G   1% /dev
tmpfs           799M  484K  798M   1% /run
/dev/xvda1      7.8G  5.6G  1.9G  76% /
none            4.0K     0  4.0K   0% /sys/fs/cgroup
none            5.0M     0  5.0M   0% /run/lock
none            3.9G     0  3.9G   0% /run/shm
none            100M     0  100M   0% /run/user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure that a package is installed; don’t update it if it isn’t&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;**ansible all -i inventories/production_actual -u ubuntu -m apt -a &quot;name=tree state=present&quot;**
ec2-52-39-100-178.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success &amp;gt;&amp;gt; {
    &quot;changed&quot;: false
}

ec2-52-89-105-4.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success &amp;gt;&amp;gt; {
    &quot;changed&quot;: false
}

ec2-54-68-16-169.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success &amp;gt;&amp;gt; {
    &quot;changed&quot;: false
}

ec2-52-42-166-105.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com | success &amp;gt;&amp;gt; {
    &quot;changed&quot;: false
}

52.40.224.171 | success &amp;gt;&amp;gt; {
    &quot;changed&quot;: false
}

**ansible all -i inventories/production_actual -u ubuntu --become -m apt -a &quot;name=htop state=present&quot;**
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edunham.net/2015/06/08/playing_with_ansible.html&quot;&gt;http://edunham.net/2015/06/08/playing_with_ansible.html&lt;/a&gt;   This is a very good read.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/intro_adhoc.html&quot;&gt;http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/intro_adhoc.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://dasari.me&quot;&gt;Dv&lt;/a&gt; who pushed me off the proverbial Ansible cliff and has supported me all the way down the learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ansible/2016/09/29/examples-of-ansible-ad-hoc-commands.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/ansible/2016/09/29/examples-of-ansible-ad-hoc-commands.html</guid>
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
        <category>ad_hoc</category>
        
        
        <category>ansible</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software Engineering - How Do You Fill The Time Between Times?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My wife and I refer to the time between sun set and true dark as the &lt;em&gt;time between times&lt;/em&gt;.  And in any software development project, you’ll always hit that point where either you’ve just wrapped a project or you are just plain churning your wheels on a task and you need something to do.  Happily, in any software development job, there are ALWAYS things to do.  Let’s say that you have finished all your tickets, all your code is committed and your boss just gave you a great review.  Its 1 in the afternoon on a monday and the product manager isn’t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you supposed to do?  Well obviously there’s always reddit and hacker news but that’s not what you’re supposed to do – that’s how you fill in a quick break.  There’s still a full half day of work left so what do you do?  Well, you &lt;strong&gt;test&lt;/strong&gt;.  There’s no software on the planet that can’t benefit from test coverage.  Even if you’re using the infinitely appealing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QuickCheck&quot;&gt;QuickCheck&lt;/a&gt;, there is still a role for well written test coverage.  So you find some corner of the software that isn’t well tested or that you don’t understand well and you poke it with a stick and write some tests.  And when they run, you write some more tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test coverage in 2016 is probably today’s equivalent of cleaning in the 1950s U.S. navy.  Just as &lt;strong&gt;nothing can ever be too clean&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;nothing can ever be too well tested&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  If you don’t know what to test then install RCov into your project and run a full rake spec.  This will show you what needs to be tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: A quick shout out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elixirfountain.com/&quot;&gt;Elixir Fountain&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/elixirfountain/elixir-fountain-john-hughes-2016-09-23&quot;&gt;absolutely excellent interview with John Hughes&lt;/a&gt; who invented QuickCheck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/27/software-engineering-how-do-you-fill-the-time-between-times.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/27/software-engineering-how-do-you-fill-the-time-between-times.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Become a Better Cook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to step out of my normal nerd comfort zone and move onto something more decidedly analog than digital – cooking.  Over on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/recipes&quot;&gt;recipe blog&lt;/a&gt;, I write down the recipe for everything I’ve ever cooked.  I’m a few hundred behind but all the current stuff I cook every single week is there.  What isn’t there however is the meta layer like how to do X or in this case how to &lt;strong&gt;become a better cook&lt;/strong&gt;.  And while I think I’m an ok cook, I do get rave reviews from the people who matter most to me – my wife, kids and friends.  So here’s how I got there:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-must-cook&quot;&gt;You Must Cook&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is adapted from Heinlein’s famous advice to writers: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfwriter.com/ow05.htm&quot;&gt;You Must Write&lt;/a&gt;.  Cooking is one of those things which you must do to improve.  This means that you get better in proportion to how much you do it.  What to be a better cook?  Well then my comment to you is &lt;strong&gt;cook more&lt;/strong&gt;.  Don’t have people around to eat what you make?  Take it to a neighbor or a sick friend.  Make cookies for the office.  Whatever.  You must cook.  Its about that simple.  When my wife was diagnosed with celiac disease about 6 years ago we effectively lost the ability to eat out.  That pushed the volume of my cooking up.  You can always stop dining out if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;read-voraciously&quot;&gt;Read Voraciously&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with everything else I do, I read voraciously.  And I highly recommend it as a learning tool to improve your cooking.  I have a simple rule for cookbooks and I call it the Rule of 1.  All a cookbook needs to be worthwhile for me is one good recipe.  And that’s my expectation.  Most cookbooks I find can supply one good recipe.  Sadly many can only only supply one.  And sadly sometimes what you get isn’t even a “recipe”.  I make a delicious asian rice bowl which I got from an author who just had a passing description of how rice is served on trains in china.  There weren’t ingredients, steps or anything other than three sentences but that justified that whole book.  Now you don’t have to read print – there’s an infinite supply of cooking information online.  There’s twitter, reddit, food network, etc.  If you do read print then I’d highly recommend you check out your local library.  Most libraries turn over inventory regularly and you can get cookbooks at the $1 to $2 per generally.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indyplfoundation.org/book-sale&quot;&gt;Here are the details for mine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understand-the-cookbook-authors-you-read&quot;&gt;Understand the Cookbook Authors You Read&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things to understand is that cook book authors are people and they have limitations.  Some of the most lauded authors, people fantastic at explaining things, don’t actually produce great recipes so there are people you learn from and people you imitate.  For example I made a clam chowder the other day from someone who intellectually I respect at a deep level but, honestly, it was no better than the clam chowder I’ve made a dozen times from various and sundry google results.  Now, that said, this person’s technique was spot on and I did learn a valuable trick from him or her.  What I have found generally is the better the explainer the worse the recipe.  One happy exception to this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ratio-Simple-Behind-Everyday-Cooking/dp/1416571728/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1474883244&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=ruhlman+ratio&quot;&gt;Ruhlman and his Ratio book&lt;/a&gt; is just outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;its-all-just-cooking&quot;&gt;Its All Just Cooking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear things from other people I speak with like “I can grill but I can’t bake” or “I can do vegetables but not meats”.  This is particularly common with restaurant cooks where people often specialize.  Honestly that’s just plain crap.  Its all just cooking and if you’re going to be any good then you need to cook across the spectrum whether its protein on a grill to cookies to pavlova to creme brûlée to eggs to salads to rolling your own sushi.  And, yes, I can say that with confidence because I can do all of that.  Yes we all have things we prefer to make and we can all have specialities but are you really going to tell your child you can’t make them cookies because you can’t bake?  Really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s only one thing that I’ve never mastered and it is making my own cheese (largely a product of UHT milk can’t make cheese and that’s all they sell in Indiana)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-must-experiment&quot;&gt;You Must Experiment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the worst things you can do if you cook seriously is to get stale.  You have to experiment.  Getting bored with making dinner for the family?  And the easiest way to do this is to dive into other cultures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to make &lt;a href=&quot;http://picapica.com/blog/2013/09/how-to-make-arepas-pica-pica-arepa-kitchen/&quot;&gt;Arepas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to make Sushi (too many results to pick one)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to make &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.food.com/recipe/norwegian-school-bread-428043&quot;&gt;Norwegian School Bread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to make &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodandwine.com/recipes/corn-tortillas&quot;&gt;Tortillas&lt;/a&gt; (They’re mostly right but add salt to the batter and use parchment paper not plastic between the tortilla press)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While cookbooks aren’t free, google is free and every culture in the world has recipes.  Interested in Peru?  Google “Peruvian Recipes” and you’ll end up perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quericavida.com/recipes/collections/by-country/10-traditional-peruvian-recipes&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Then make something, anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learn-what-makes-a-recipe-good-for-you-and-your-context&quot;&gt;Learn What Makes a Recipe Good for You and Your Context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most valuable skills I’ve picked up is the ability to read a recipe and, unerringly, know if its right for my context – generally me, my wife and my kids.  There are signs like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;effort; A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/croquembouche-recipe.html&quot;&gt;croquembouche&lt;/a&gt; almost never works when you have small children in the house because it takes too long&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flavors; my wife has certain flavors that she just hates so anything with an organ meat for example is out before it starts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tools; if you don’t have the tools then, well, it may be irrelevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to read a recipe and know whether or not its going to work for your context is a valuable skill and something to very much strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;question-your-assumptions&quot;&gt;Question Your Assumptions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As cooks we all develop habits and assumptions.  One of mine was, until recently, “there shall be no other oils than corn, vegetable and olive.”  For years now I followed that with near religious devotion.  However I just discovered grapeseed oil and it was like a revelation – a light oil.  What??? How can this be?  And now I use it with abandon.  Keep in mind that questioning your assumptions is really, really important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;salt-and-butter-amp-up-flavor&quot;&gt;Salt and Butter Amp Up Flavor&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep.  Add salt to everything.  And butter.  We’ve all heard about the dangers of salt and butter for so many years that I suspect most of us are way too conservative on this one.  I know I am.  Adding more salt really does help food.  And you can always add some butter when you’re cooking  almost anything to improve the flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-must-taste&quot;&gt;You Must Taste&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever watched a professional chef, one thing you’ll notice is that they taste things constantly.  Some home cooks do this and some don’t but I’d argue that the ones that do will produce better food so you may want to do this more if you don’t.  I know that until recently I didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The one exception to this is gluten free baking.  Gluten free flours, until cooked, taste horrible so do not taste gluten free batters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-must-cook-1&quot;&gt;You Must Cook&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to close as I opened because its really the single most important things so I’m going to re-phrase it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You get better in proportion to how much you cook.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to be a better cook then cook more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really that’s the best thing here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/cooking/2016/09/26/how-to-become-a-better-cook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/cooking/2016/09/26/how-to-become-a-better-cook.html</guid>
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elixir Example Using Ecto for An Existing MySQL Database</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My Elixir progress has slowed a bit as of late and the cause has mostly been Ecto.  I’ve been having a hard time wrapping my head around Ecto and I suspect the issue is over a decade of constant ActiveRecord usage.  So this morning I decided to read other blog posts and try and execute on them.  I settled on this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://geoffreylessel.com/2016/using-ecto-with-an-existing-mysql-database/&quot;&gt;http://geoffreylessel.com/2016/using-ecto-with-an-existing-mysql-database/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;since it seemed to be exactly what I needed - wrap an Ecto interface around an existing database.  Unfortunately the author hadn’t published everything and some of the details he glossed over were exactly what tripped me up.  Happily he was very responsive to email and while you should absolutely read his piece, here are the bare minimum steps to build this.  This application uses a Formula 1 racing database as a source of data to query.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously adjust all the path statements and passwords and username to match your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;download-the-data&quot;&gt;Download the Data&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source data can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;http://ergast.com/mrd/db/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-database&quot;&gt;Create a Database&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mysql -uroot -p -A
create database f1_history
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Load the data using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mysql -uroot -p f1_history &amp;lt; ~/Downloads/f1db.sql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-the-app&quot;&gt;Build the App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to build a basic app with a supervisor tree as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix new f1_history --sup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;edit-mixexs&quot;&gt;Edit mix.exs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the dependencies you need for deps.get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;defp deps do
  [
    {:ecto, &quot;~&amp;gt; 2.0&quot;},
    {:mariaex, &quot;~&amp;gt; 0.7&quot;}
  ]
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;edit-configexs&quot;&gt;Edit config.exs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The config.exs file defines how you connect to the repo and should look as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;config :f1_history, F1History.Repo,
  adapter: Ecto.Adapters.MySQL,
  database: &quot;f1&quot;,
  username: &quot;root&quot;,
  password: &quot;&quot;,
  hostname: &quot;localhost&quot;
  
config :f1_history, ecto_repos: [F1History.Repo]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;edit-f1historyexs&quot;&gt;Edit f1_history.exs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what f1_history.exs should look like.  This was the root of my issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;defmodule F1History do
  use Application
  
  def start(_type, _args) do
      import Supervisor.Spec, warn: false

      children = [
        supervisor(F1History.Repo, [])
      ]

      opts = [strategy: :one_for_one, name: F1History.Supervisor]
      Supervisor.start_link(children, opts)
  end
  
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that F1History.Repo needs to be one of the supervisor’s children. This is critically important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;edit-raceex&quot;&gt;Edit race.ex&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The file race.ex defines a race “object” that we will be querying. Here’s what that file looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;defmodule F1History.Race do
  use Ecto.Schema

  @primary_key {:raceId, :id, autogenerate: true}
  
  schema &quot;races&quot; do
    field :year, :integer
    field :round, :integer
    field :circuitId, :integer
    field :name, :string
    field :date, Ecto.Date
    field :time, Ecto.Time
    field :url, :string
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;edit-repoex&quot;&gt;Edit repo.ex&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The file repo.ex needs to live in lib and looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;defmodule F1History.Repo do
  use Ecto.Repo,
  otp_app: :f1_history
end    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ecto-actually-working&quot;&gt;Ecto Actually Working&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go into console with iex -S mix and enter a query like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex(1)&amp;gt; import Ecto.Query
Ecto.Query
iex(2)&amp;gt; F1History.Repo.one from race in F1History.Race, limit: 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;12:53:09.469 [debug] QUERY OK source=&quot;races&quot; db=39.4ms decode=0.1ms queue=0.1ms
SELECT r0.`raceId`, r0.`year`, r0.`round`, r0.`circuitId`, r0.`name`, r0.`date`, r0.`time`, r0.`url` FROM `races` AS r0 LIMIT 1 []
%F1History.Race{__meta__: #Ecto.Schema.Metadata&amp;lt;:loaded, &quot;races&quot;&amp;gt;, circuitId: 1,
 date: #Ecto.Date&amp;lt;2009-03-29&amp;gt;, name: &quot;Australian Grand Prix&quot;, raceId: 1,
 round: 1, time: #Ecto.Time&amp;lt;06:00:00&amp;gt;,
 url: &quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2009_Australian_Grand_Prix&quot;, year: 2009}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-the-whole-thing&quot;&gt;Get The Whole Thing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full git repo of everthing is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fuzzygroup/f1_history&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/26/elixir-example-using-ecto-for-an-existing-mysql-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/elixir/2016/09/26/elixir-example-using-ecto-for-an-existing-mysql-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
        <category>ecto</category>
        
        <category>mysql</category>
        
        
        <category>elixir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Old Engineers Are Cranky Engineers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had an interaction with a younger software engineer and I’m pretty sure that his impression of me after that boiled down to &lt;em&gt;cranky old bastard&lt;/em&gt; and that would be the nice version.  The less nice version could easily have incorporated the words difficult, jerk and a few other bits of invective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic at hand was getting a commercial, for pay CI server up and running on a single Rails code base of moderate size (about 40 K lines; about 110 tables).  This is a well known, leading product and I was very, very difficult about my expectations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I expected it to just plain work out of the box&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was stuck getting the configuration to work and I made it clear to him that I didn’t want him spending much more time on it.  He saw no problem with investing the time in it – and that was the conflict.  My logic goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We do not have a hard environment - Rails 4.2.x app, basic table structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RSpec works pretty much right out of the box when I set up a new developer work station&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They charge us money for this – doesn’t that mean that configuration is their damn job?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I had to say to him something akin to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cost us roughly $3,000 per week so 1 day of your effort is $3,000 / 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have until the end of the day at that point we’re done with this vendor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;crankiness-explained&quot;&gt;Crankiness Explained&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crankiness on my part comes from a combination of this particular vendor, partly from the unique snowflake attitude common to CI vendors, and partly from being older.  Here’s the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Vendor&lt;/em&gt;. The last time this vendor decided to change its architecture, it did so at the expense of its customers. They moved from static instances where your CI server was always the same box so configuration could be done at the box level to dynamically creating instances forcing configuration into your config file.  They kept their pricing the same but this move effectively made them more profitable since their AWS costs would now go down.  At one of my consulting gigs, I saw one of our engineers blow 2 man days on getting this back to a working state.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snowflake&lt;/em&gt;. For some reason CI software never seems to work out of the box.  I’ve seen this for years in the Rails world dating back to CI Joe.  All the vendors have this attitude that they are some unique snowflake and lots of setup work is needed.  That might have been true once upon a time when TDD was new but it is 2016 now and TDD is not new.  CI is not a new concept.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m older&lt;/em&gt;.  One of the things that happens as you become an older engineer is you realize just how many things that you – and your staff – miss out on thru obsessive attention to technology issues.  It isn’t that I’m incapable of configuring this piece of crap but that if I’m doing that I’m not doing the 10 other things that absolutely, positively have to get done today.  Ultimate the CI software needs to support my job and I don’t need to support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;happy-conclusion&quot;&gt;Happy Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My asshole style demand – get it done by the end of the day – actually worked.  I absolutely hate to manage that way but forced time bounding can be a great technique at times.  We now have a CI server that is setup and that is excellent.  He really did do a good job.  We’re not 100% there yet because it is only checking pull requests and not master but hopefully that is a matter of only minor additional configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;recommendation-to-vendors-and-an-example-of-doing-it-right&quot;&gt;Recommendation to Vendors And an Example of Doing it Right&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rightly or wrongly I don’t think I’m all that different from what a lot of people when it comes to evaluating software.  Getting a great out of the box experience is essential if you want someone to pay you.  If this was an open source CI server that I had to run myself I’d expect configuration but RSpec and Rails 4.x is a known thing.  This should have just worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of getting setup right, I’d like to point people to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codetree.com/&quot;&gt;CodeTree&lt;/a&gt;.  You can point CodeTree at your git account and boom!  It makes github issues better.  Can you configure it?  I think so but the point is that I haven’t needed to.  &lt;em&gt;Recommended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: CodeTree is run by a former boss of mine and I do view him as a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/24/why-old-engineers-are-cranky-engineers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/09/24/why-old-engineers-are-cranky-engineers.html</guid>
        
        <category>ci</category>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
