<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FuzzyBlog</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing about the usual array of nerd stuff: AWS / Ansible / Ruby / Rails / Elixir / Misc.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 07:31:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 07:31:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Build Rails views with Markdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I’m starting prototyping on an all new thing and I want to be commercially successful out of the gate.  That’s a bit different for me where I usually focus initially on the code.  This means thinking, from not just day 1 but hour 1, about how the customer sees things and for me that starts with two pages on the site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;faq&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would argue that for any web thing, an about page and a faq are at the core of your marketing.  And since both of these are content, I can’t see the point of using straight erb or haml views when MarkDown is so damn easy.  I wouldn’t use markdown for a page where there were forms or UI elements but for content?  Hell yes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-use-markdown-for-rails-views&quot;&gt;How to Use Markdown for Rails Views&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In your Gemfile you need to call the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chrisroberts/kramdown-rails&quot;&gt;kramdown-rails gem&lt;/a&gt;: gem ‘kramdown-rails’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do the bundle install happy dance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In your app/views/controller_name directory create your views with a .md extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kramdown-rails gem is a light wrapper around the core &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gettalong/kramdown&quot;&gt;kramdown gem&lt;/a&gt; which does the markdown to html translation and supports using it in an Rails view context.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/28/how-to-build-rails-views-with-markdown.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/28/how-to-build-rails-views-with-markdown.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>markdown</category>
        
        <category>kramdown</category>
        
        <category>hyde</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Product Review Amazon Echo is Excellent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So my wife got me an Amazon Echo for Christmas and I powered it up today.  Overall I was absolutely delighted with it – Amazon has a hell of a product here.  The ease of use that a conversational user interface brings is staggering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa play happy holiday music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa may the force be with you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa play pink&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa what is the weather&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa what is the temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa what is the news&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa 5 minute timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those were a few of the commands that we came up with right away.  My wife gets the serious nerd fu credit for the force one; bless her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;amazon-echo-out-of-the-box-experience&quot;&gt;Amazon Echo Out of the Box Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few thoughts on the out of the box experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The out of the box experience is far, far rougher than I had expected.  You certainly get thru it but I didn’t find it clear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You do need to install the Amazon Echo app on your phone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s a weird config step where the Echo presents a wifi network that you connect to so it can find the actual network that in your house; at the end of it your phone is left connected to the echo and its unclear if you change that or not (I would think so but who knows)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The trend towards “no one reads the manual so let’s not even have one” is a suck ass trend.  There are those of us who do read the manual and we get very annoyed by the fact that there isn’t even comprehensive online documentation.  I can rationalize the lack of a printed manual due to rapid updates but sheesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;when-it-doesnt-play-music&quot;&gt;When It Doesn’t Play Music&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest problem was that it wouldn’t play music initially.  Googling was relatively fruitless but it did reveal that lots of other people have this problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=amazon+echo+won%27t+play+music&amp;amp;oq=amazon+echo+won%27t+&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.3.0j69i57j0l4.5987j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Google Search - 3.42 million results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.echotalk.org/index.php?topic=322.0&quot;&gt;NTP Related&lt;/a&gt;; best theory I saw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer, at least for me, turned out to be turn it off and then on and then wait.  And that did it. Sigh.  Given how important digital technology is to all of our lives the answer of power on / power off or as I refer to it “get out of the car and get back into the car” is a crappy answer at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I’ve already tried to order the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01DFKC2SO/ref=ods_gw_b_h1_ha_justask_black?pf_rd_r=QMHK561Z7EWPEZQJ1BFX&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=68d26f18-1cf3-45a4-870c-87bf6bd9cee6&quot;&gt;hockey puck extension&lt;/a&gt; for the echo so I guess that says all you need to know about how much I like it. This is a fantastic product.  Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pocket-lint.com/news/136952-amazon-echo-vs-amazon-tap-vs-echo-dot-what-s-the-difference&quot;&gt;good article that clarifies the difference between the Echo and Echo Dot&lt;/a&gt;; much to my surprise the hockey puck isn’t an extension - its a standalone version of the echo with a smaller speaker so it can be cheaper but it doesn’t require the echo at all.  You can plug it into your own speakers for better output.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/amazon_echo/2016/12/26/product-review-amazon-echo-is-excellent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/amazon_echo/2016/12/26/product-review-amazon-echo-is-excellent.html</guid>
        
        <category>alexa</category>
        
        <category>echo</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>echo_dot</category>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        
        <category>amazon_echo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Worst Git Commit Message Ever</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was in the car with my wife talking to her as I worked and this was the bmessage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; git commit -m &quot;misc:
→ '''''''''''''''''''vvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvV 
VVVVVVVVVVVVVV                                                               
                          ///////// vvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvv
                          vvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvv
                          vvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvv
                          vvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvvv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel asleep while talking to her and coding.  I suspect drooling was also involved.  Too many late nights…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/git/2016/12/23/my-worst-git-commit-message-ever.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/git/2016/12/23/my-worst-git-commit-message-ever.html</guid>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
        
        <category>git</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Merging Files - Diff Alternatives on the Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are certain skills as a software developer that take, in my experience, a lifetime to master.  I have now been using version control since the mid 1990s and I still don’t consider myself, by any means, a master.  I’m good, don’t get me wrong, but I don’t feel that I have yet fully internalized all the benefits that version control offers.  So, when I have a chance to really take advantage of version control, I truly relish the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had a refactoring situtation where I was, shall we say, overly ambitious.  And, yes, that’s the positive version of what I’d refer to as “Humpty Dumpty” code syndrome where you have so thoroughly broken a critical bit of code that you just can’t put it back together.  Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I refactored a truly alway bit of two critical routines, one with 8 input variables that returned 6 variables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No test coverage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It would not, no matter what I did, do what it did before; specifically it would do the first pass of an N pass algorithm but I could never make it go beyond stage 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the process of doing this I added new and highly desirable functionality everywhere and fixed about 30 critical code mistakes along the way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, well, &lt;strong&gt;crap&lt;/strong&gt;.  The fix was, in the immortal words of Doctor Who, to get all timey-whimey!  Specifically I needed to time travel back to &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; I started and then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;confirm that this code actually worked in the first place – maybe this problem existed before I &lt;em&gt;fixed&lt;/em&gt; it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;figure out how to travel back from the past while bringing with me a working version&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NOT lose any of the cool new features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the development practices I am absolutely adamant about is only ever having 1 checkout of the code based at a time.  I’m hardcore on this because I’ve seen what happens when you have multiple versions floating about – its very, very convenient but you tend to get confused and then you lose track of what’s the master and things get screwball.  But, in desparate times, you do what you must and so I went over to github and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found a commit from roughly before I started; I wasn’t real specific about this, I just remember “this debacle started last Thursday so goto Wednesday”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I browsed the code base at that point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I created a new directory where I wanted this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I checked out the code; that put a fresh copy of master in place&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I did a git co HASH where HASH represented the commit hash for Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This put me what’s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3965676/why-did-my-git-repo-enter-a-detached-head-state&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;detached head&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; mode and I was able to modify /run / test, etc.  I then had to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;port over my rake task which was doing my tests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;port over the individual changes, one by one, &lt;em&gt;carefully&lt;/em&gt; to let the old code run correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found was that the old code did, in fact, run better than the new code.  Sigh.  And after 2 days of fixing things all over the place I had the system back to running order with the exception that I now had 2 code bases that needed to be merged.  &lt;em&gt;Bigger Sigh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;time-for-some-diff-magic&quot;&gt;Time for some Diff Magic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I now had two git checkouts with differences between them.  One of them was master, and did I mention that while this was all going on I got pulled off the project to fix something else and add yet more functionality to the code base for a day and half, and the other was my time travel branch.  When I did a git status in the time travel branch I got this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git status
HEAD detached at 93bf221
Changes not staged for commit:
  (use &quot;git add &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;...&quot; to update what will be committed)
  (use &quot;git checkout -- &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;...&quot; to discard changes in working directory)

	modified:   app/models/form.rb
	modified:   app/models/form2016_q4.rb
	modified:   app/models/iframe2016_q4.rb
	modified:   app/models/link.rb
	modified:   app/models/link2016_q4.rb
	modified:   app/models/page.rb
	modified:   app/models/page2016_q4.rb
	modified:   app/models/page_body.rb
	modified:   app/models/page_body2016_q4.rb
	modified:   app/models/site.rb
	modified:   app/models/unique_url.rb
	modified:   app/models/unique_url2016_q4.rb
	modified:   app/models/url_resolver.rb
	modified:   app/models/url_tool.rb
	modified:   config/initializers/constants.rb
	modified:   lib/common_link.rb
	modified:   lib/common_page.rb

Untracked files:
  (use &quot;git add &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;...&quot; to include in what will be committed)

	docs/snippets/create_mechanize_page_without_fetch.rb
	lib/tasks/crawl2016_q4.rake

no changes added to commit (use &quot;git add&quot; and/or &quot;git commit -a&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a whole lot of changes.  The easiest approach was to start with the entirely new files and just copy them over to the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is where I’m going to make a highly personal engineering choice here – I’m going to avoid an automated merge process of any type.  When it comes to complex code changes in an automated fashion I honestly don’t have a lot of faith.  I’ve seen automated merges go wrong time after time so I was looking for a tool to make this easier.  A quick bit of googling turned up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OpenDiff / FileMerge (part of X-Code)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://meldmerge.org/&quot;&gt;meld&lt;/a&gt; - a python tool with an unofficial brew install via &lt;em&gt;brew install homebrew/gui/meld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Beyond Compare]http://www.scootersoftware.com/download.php from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scootersoftware.com/&quot;&gt;Scooter Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sourcegear.com/diffmerge/&quot;&gt;Diff Merge&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sourcegear.com/&quot;&gt;SourceGear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kaleidoscopeapp.com/&quot;&gt;Kaleidoscope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up using Open Diff for my merge issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/open_diff.png&quot; alt=&quot;opendiff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;diff_merge.png
beyond_compare.png
kaleidoscope.png&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good articles on merge tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.git-tower.com/blog/diff-tools-mac&quot;&gt;GitTower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outcoldman.com/en/archive/2014/05/12/git-dirdiff/&quot;&gt;outcoldman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 11:26:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/12/22/on-merging-files-diff-alternatives-on-the-mac.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_engineering/2016/12/22/on-merging-files-diff-alternatives-on-the-mac.html</guid>
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
        <category>version_control</category>
        
        <category>merge</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>diff</category>
        
        
        <category>software_engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PostMac Roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are a few more things in the ongoing PostMac roundup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/19/apples-tim-cook-assures-employees-that-it-is-committed-to-the-mac-and-that-great-desktops-are-coming/&quot;&gt;Apple’s Tim Cook assures employees that it is committed to the Mac and that ‘great desktops’ are coming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13217008&quot;&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/a&gt;  Given that Tim Cook is the one who said publicly that people should use iPads and not laptops I’d have to wonder about this.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/linked/2016/10/31/cook-why-would-you-buy-a-pc-anymore&quot;&gt;Gruber on This Comment&lt;/a&gt;.  Lots of good comments on people using Linux in place of OSX here.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13217412&quot;&gt;A brilliant comment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-12-20/how-apple-alienated-mac-loyalists&quot;&gt;How Apple Alienated Mac Loyalists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13220623&quot;&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/12/21/postmac-roundup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/postmac/2016/12/21/postmac-roundup.html</guid>
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        
        <category>postmac</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Gems to Slay the Monolith Part 1 - Validations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all talk quite a bit about the monolithic Ruby application but the simple truth of it is that your rails application really, really wants to be monolithic.  Let’s explore the concept of an email sending application that wants to offer an API for contact import.  If you think about this you’re basically saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s externalize the process of importing user data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally we’d like to build this with the new Rails 5 api mode that speaks JSON as its lingua franca.  Rails 5 api mode is small, fast and like Rails was before the asset pipeline – easy.  And, personally, I love API mode.  But since API mode does not ANY view handling this means that you are inherently building two rails applications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the user facing portion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since user data inevitably needs to be displayed and generally created in the user facing application as well as in the api, you’re talking about a user model that exists in two places.  And that means that all the support cruft like validations needs to exist in both places.  That’s not DRY at all – it is verbose beyond belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cross-project-code-sharing-1---git&quot;&gt;Cross Project Code Sharing 1 - Git&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an idealized world you would think that git would race to our rescue and be the hero here but I’ve looked into git for cross project model re-use and my response was “icky poo”.  Another developer I know, Winston, looked into it and wrote up the options but had a similar feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cross-project-code-sharing-2---a-gem-based-approach&quot;&gt;Cross Project Code Sharing 2 - A Gem Based Approach&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you come right down to it we actually have a model for code sharing in the Rails world and it is the Ruby Gem.  I was in Rails prior to gems and still remember, fondly, the days of plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if there was a website to support it??? validationhub.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 12:11:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/20/using-gems-to-slay-the-monolith-part-1-validations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rails/2016/12/20/using-gems-to-slay-the-monolith-part-1-validations.html</guid>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>monolith</category>
        
        <category>validations</category>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple - A Tale of Too Litle Storage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;http://daringfireball.net/linked/2016/12/15/speirs-icloud-storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.speirs.org/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 07:55:03 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/20/apple-a-tale-of-too-litle-storage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/20/apple-a-tale-of-too-litle-storage.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Kindest Thing I Ever Saw Disney Do</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 07:02:48 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/20/the-kindest-thing-i-ever-saw-disney-do.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/20/the-kindest-thing-i-ever-saw-disney-do.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>David Rovics Community Supported Art or a Tale of PayWoe and UI / UX Failures for Startups to Learn From</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tales on the Internet of problems with PayPal are damn near epic in their size.  Everyone, always, seems to have issues with PayPal and I am no exception.  Part of this is the nature of PayPal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a long running Internet service - I remember the first time I used PayPal and that was three houses ago (not three rented houses; three owned houses); if I measure PayPal in terms of places I have lived then the number is 8.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;focus on a single persistent personal address; I have been using the same email address since the early days of gMail. It is how PayPal knows me but that means there is “contact cruft” attached to it in the form of dead address; dead cell phone numbers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it is constantly under attack.  I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/PayPal-Wars-Battles-Media-Planet/dp/1936488590&quot;&gt;The PayPal Wars&lt;/a&gt; back when I worked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kareem.m?source=false---------0&quot;&gt;Kareem&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve fought spam wars in both email and blog so I understand how being under constant attack changes how you build and design products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the people I grew up with is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidrovics.com&quot;&gt;David Rovics&lt;/a&gt; and consider a friend albeit one I haven’t seen since 1985.  I remember trading comic books with him at his parent’s house back in the late 1970s.  Our political leanings couldn’t be more different - he’s a card carrying anarchist / socialist / musican who writes beautiful songs that honestly bring tears to my eyes.  Songs of social significance is how he describes them and he isn’t wrong.  Me?  I may live in Indiana but I’m deeply tied to tech entrepreneurialism and the open source world.  We could not be more different along ideological lines but I have damn near infinite respect for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David is also a writer / blogger and his piece about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://songwritersnotebook.blogspot.com/2016/03/rejected-by-america.html&quot;&gt;differences between America and Europe&lt;/a&gt; is illuminating.  I don’t agree entirely with his conclusions but I also don’t argue with the facts.  If you like folk music / songs with meaning then his stuff, all freely available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidrovics.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt; is fascinating.  Personally I’d highly recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z_rCdNdkb_g&quot;&gt;Battle of Blair Mountain&lt;/a&gt; which tells a dark tale of American labor relations that you don’t learn in school – certainly not Wilton High School where David and I attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does that very long introduction have to do with PayPal?  Well David is an artist which means that he sells CDs, tours, etc and he recently introduced his CSA or Community Supported Art program where you can sign up as a member for $50 / year (other options available as well).  And I tried, back in September, to signup only to be thwarted by PayPal issues.  And then, sadly, I got busy and lost it amongst the weeks of AWS, Ansible, server migrations, code migrations, learning elixir, etc.  But you should never forget your friends.  Yesterday I noticed that David’s main site was down so I dropped him an email and that inspired me to finally fix my PayPal account.  In the process I noticed a few UI issues that I found surprising in a site of PayPal’s scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would think that a company like PayPal would have a finely tuned UI / UX team around the issues of common problems. Somehow, given what I just experienced, I don’t think so.  And therein lies the tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem-the-first---login-and-verification&quot;&gt;Problem the First - Login and Verification&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened yesterday morning and I did not capture any screenshots because, well, my bad.  Given that PayPal had old contact info for all my cell phones user verification was tricky but I got past it.  To be entirely honest tho I was actually kind of happy that verification was tricky - that means accounts cannot be compromised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem-2---expired-card&quot;&gt;Problem 2 - Expired Card&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went to purchase from a link from David’s site, I got this screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/paypal_link_to_add_new_card_is_where.png&quot; alt=&quot;paypal_link_to_add_new_card_is_where.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you notice there is no way to add a new card here and the card that they had on file for me was easily 5 years old.  Now I do get that the designers might have been worried about breaking the payment flow by allowing a link to add a new card.  But given that I’m not a UI guy and I can easily think of at least one way around that, should’t they been able to?  I have to think that adding a new credit card is a fairly common thing if you are PayPal.  And if the card is as old as I had then shouldn’t a link be presented at least in that case if not every case?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem-3---the-no-no-no-screen&quot;&gt;Problem 3 - The No No No Screen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I navigated thru the PayPal ui and finally found where to add a new card – the correctly named “Wallet”.  So I copied and pasted my details from &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_worth_purchasing/2016/09/15/software-worth-purchasing-02-enpass.html&quot;&gt;Enpass&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommended btw) and I got what I think of as the No No No screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/paypal_no_no_no.png&quot; alt=&quot;paypal_no_no_no.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah I get it.  My wife has our main credit card attached to her PayPal account but she’s sleeping.  Time to dig out the wallet and find some other card.  But, again, shouldn’t there have been a link here to use a different card instead?  The web is, inherently, a hyper linked medium – didn’t the PayPal designers ever get the memo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I navigated backwards thru the UI and found the place to add a different credit card and then went back to my friends site and completed my purchase.  Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;good-things&quot;&gt;Good Things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few good things that PayPal has done that in all fairness I should point out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The list of security questions has been substantially revised.  My older security questions where last 4 of social and mother’s maiden name.  Now it is things like “name of first pet” / “name of favorite childhood stuffed toy”.  That isn’t as good as write your own question but it is much, much harder to find that type of personal trivia online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was able to add a credit card, pay for something and then delete the credit card even tho the transaction might not have been processed yet.  That is a wonderful design decision and very much pro user.  Kudos!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-fix-core-usability-if-you-are-a-startup&quot;&gt;How to Fix Core Usability if You Are a Startup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The take away here and the reason that I tagged this as startup is that even well established, mature companies get common UI / UX issues wrong all the time.  I don’t think I’m wrong to think that adding a credit card is a common use case for PayPal and that it should have been a 1 step action from payment.  Instead I spent about 15 minutes to do nothing more than complete one purchase.  If it wasn’t for my friend then there’s a very good chance that I would have dropped out – as I did once before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single best way to avoid this type of UI disaster is to simply watch your users use your product, take notes and then iterate on your product until that issue is addressed.  Then you go back to a different user and watch them try and do the same thing and see if you made it better or worse.  And repeat until this whatever that issue is is fixed.  I learned this lesson a number of times over the years but most recently from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kouriskalligas&quot;&gt;Kouris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dave_Sifry&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People, particularly “UX specialists”, want to make a big deal out of usability but it really isn’t all that hard or even all that expensive.  All you need to do, if you want to solve these type of core usability issues, is have &lt;strong&gt;the will to do it&lt;/strong&gt;.  You have to take responsibility for the problem, focus on it and then set an agenda like “this week we’re going to improve login”.  It can be absolutely exhausting since you’re iterating on the same, often tiny details, over and over but that’s part of the game.  A software engineer, particularly someone like myself, generally won’t take ownership of that kind of problem since our focus is internals but someone on the management or product side absolutely can do this.  Sometimes the improvements are absolutely tiny – perhaps better messaging is needed or even just a link.  As an example, messaging in one case and a link in both cases would have addressed all of my issues above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, given the size of PayPal I can actually sort of understand why getting this fixed is hard – I suspect that there are a lot of organizational boundaries to cross and people to deal with.  A startup shouldn’t have that problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Kudos to &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/software_worth_purchasing/2016/09/11/software-worth-purchasing-01-acorn.html&quot;&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; for being easy enough to use that even I, a thumb fingered, graphically challenged engineer, could get it right.  Recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rant/2016/12/20/david-rovics-community-supported-art-or-a-tale-of-paywoe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/rant/2016/12/20/david-rovics-community-supported-art-or-a-tale-of-paywoe.html</guid>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>paypal</category>
        
        <category>paywoe</category>
        
        <category>rant</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
        <category>rovics</category>
        
        <category>ui</category>
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
        <category>usability</category>
        
        
        <category>rant</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make Testing Easy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;bundle exec rake crawl2016_q4:test_crawl –trace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crawling site: 457, domain: lowrystate.com there were:
      pages_count: 43 | 46 (prior)
      links_count: 1337 | 1333 (prior)
page_bodies_count: 43 | 46 (prior)
      forms_count: 0 | 3 (prior)
    iframes_count: 1 | 0 (prior)
unique_urls_count: 152 | 73 (prior)
Total crawl time: 79.70658148999792 | seconds_per_page: 1.8536414299999515&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tests for writing to the WRONG table – In the q3 data set there are:
        q3_pages: 0
        q3_links: 0
        q3_forms: 0
      q3_iframes: 0
  q3_unique_urls: 74
  q3_page_bodies: 0
MAJOR ERROR - The q3 calls above should be 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crawling site: 457, domain: lowrystate.com there were:
      pages_count: 43 | 46 (prior)
      links_count: 1337 | 1333 (prior)
page_bodies_count: 43 | 46 (prior)
      forms_count: 0 | 3 (prior)
    iframes_count: 1 | 0 (prior)
unique_urls_count: 74 | 73 (prior)
Total crawl time: 119.04229378001764 | seconds_per_page: 2.768425436744596&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tests for writing to the WRONG table – In the q3 data set there are:
        q3_pages: 0
        q3_links: 0
        q3_forms: 0
      q3_iframes: 0
  q3_unique_urls: 0
  q3_page_bodies: 0
No crawling into the q3 data so good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 06:57:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/19/make-testing-easy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzygroup.github.io/blog/2016/12/19/make-testing-easy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
